<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-16"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://linksfor.dev/feed.xml" />
    <title>linksfor.dev(s)</title>
    <link>https://linksfor.dev/feed.xml</link>
    <description>Curated links for devs</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>The chip made for the AI inference era – the Google TPU</title>
      <link>https://www.uncoveralpha.com/p/the-chip-made-for-the-ai-inference</link>
      <description>I am publishing a comprehensive deep dive, not just a technical overview, but also strategic and financial coverage of the Google TPU.</description>
      <category>cloud</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>vscode</category>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <guid>https://www.uncoveralpha.com/p/the-chip-made-for-the-ai-inference</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 02:02:06 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Daniel's Blog · People as Foundation (以民为本): The Productive Capacity Theory of Money (Part 1)</title>
      <link>https://danieltan.weblog.lol/2025/11/people-as-foundation-the-productive-capacity-theory-of-money-part-1</link>
      <description>Conventional macroeconomic frameworks—whether neoclassical, Keynesian, or monetarist—cannot explain persistent policy failures across developed economies. This paper presents the Productive Capacity Theory of Money: money is created through debt backed by human productive capacity—working-age population, skills, health, and infrastructure. Companies aggregate and certify this capacity, enabling banks to lend against workers' future productivity. Employment isn't just wages—it's capacity activation for money creation.</description>
      <category>encryption</category>
      <guid>https://danieltan.weblog.lol/2025/11/people-as-foundation-the-productive-capacity-theory-of-money-part-1</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 23:03:57 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SSE sucks for transporting LLM tokens</title>
      <link>https://zknill.io/posts/sse-sucks-for-transporting-llm-tokens/</link>
      <description>SSE sucks I’m just going to cut to the chase here. SSE as a transport mechanism for LLM tokens is naff. It’s not that it can’t work, obviously it can, because people are using it and SDKs are built around it. But it’s not a great fit for the problem space.
The basic SSE flow goes something like this:
Client makes an HTTP POST request to the server with a prompt Server responds with a 200 OK and keeps the connection open Server streams tokens back to the client as they are generated, using the SSE format Client processes the tokens as they arrive on the long-lived HTTP connection Sure the approach has some benefits, like simplicity and compatibility with existing HTTP infrastructure. But it still sucks.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>sql</category>
      <guid>https://zknill.io/posts/sse-sucks-for-transporting-llm-tokens/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 23:03:51 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Principles: Why You Must Learn Before You Prompt</title>
      <link>https://imapenguin.com/2025/11/first-principles-why-you-must-learn-before-you-prompt/</link>
      <description>Why mastering fundamentals before using AI coding tools is the difference between wielding power and being wielded by it</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>sql</category>
      <category>vscode</category>
      <guid>https://imapenguin.com/2025/11/first-principles-why-you-must-learn-before-you-prompt/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 23:03:46 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Impossible Prompt</title>
      <link>https://teodordyakov.github.io/the-impossible-promt/</link>
      <description>Historically there have been very simple prompts that LLMs struggled with disproportionately
            compared to the areas in which they excel. The early versions of ChatGPT struggled with very simple
            one-step logical deduction. But that is no longer the case; in the last 2.5 years, LLMs have progressed
            tremendously.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://teodordyakov.github.io/the-impossible-promt/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 23:03:42 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing LeanSpec: A Lightweight SDD Framework Built from First Principles | Marvin Zhang</title>
      <link>https://www.marvinzhang.dev/blog/introducing-leanspec</link>
      <description>Earlier this year, I was amazed by agentic AI coding with Claude Sonnet 3.7. The term "vibe coding" hadn't been coined yet, but that's exactly what I was doing—letting AI generate code while I steered the conversation. It felt magical. Until it didn't.</description>
      <author> (https://github.com/tikazyq)</author>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>nodejs</category>
      <category>vscode</category>
      <guid>https://www.marvinzhang.dev/blog/introducing-leanspec</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 23:03:39 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Made Playing Cards to Teach English – LandenLove.xyz</title>
      <link>https://landenlove.xyz/i-made-playing-cards-to-teach-english/</link>
      <description>I own nothing related to the ‘Uno’ trademark. Please do not destroy me, Mattel</description>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <guid>https://landenlove.xyz/i-made-playing-cards-to-teach-english/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 23:03:35 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3.3x Faster HuggingFace Tokenizers for Single Sequence</title>
      <link>https://charlesxu.io/parallel-tokenizer/</link>
      <description>I made HuggingFace tokenizers 3.3x faster by parallelizing single-input tokenization with overlapping chunks, zero-copy offset operations, SIMD-accelerated boundary detection, and cache-hierarchy-aware chunking. The result is bit-identical to serial encoding. Fast tokenization is critical to achieve low TTFT given long context.</description>
      <category>git</category>
      <category>python</category>
      <category>vscode</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <guid>https://charlesxu.io/parallel-tokenizer/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 23:03:32 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On 10 Years of Writing a Blog Nobody Reads</title>
      <link>https://flowtwo.io/post/on-10-years-of-writing-a-blog-nobody-reads</link>
      <description>flow2 | Blog post: 'On 10 Years of Writing a Blog Nobody Reads' in Personal</description>
      <category>encryption</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://flowtwo.io/post/on-10-years-of-writing-a-blog-nobody-reads</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 23:03:27 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Don’t be a scary old guy: My 40s survival strategy with charm</title>
      <link>https://www.devas.life/dont-be-a-scary-old-guy-my-40s-survival-strategy-with-charm/</link>
      <description>Hi, it’s Takuya.
Last week I had my birthday and turned 41 (November 19th).

When I was younger, I could never really picture what life in my 40s would look like. It’s this vague age where you don’t have a clear image of how you’re supposed</description>
      <guid>https://www.devas.life/dont-be-a-scary-old-guy-my-40s-survival-strategy-with-charm/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 23:03:20 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Notes on: When Ants Are Smarter Than People</title>
      <link>https://aethermug.com/posts/my-notes-on-when-ants-are-smarter-than-people</link>
      <description>Group intelligence is worth talking about</description>
      <author> (Marco Giancotti)</author>
      <guid>https://aethermug.com/posts/my-notes-on-when-ants-are-smarter-than-people</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 23:03:16 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What a prototype can be</title>
      <link>https://sophia.ooo/writing/what-a-prototype-can-be/</link>
      <description>A prototype is a sketch of a possible thing.


  A prototype can be an exploration: it materializes and hones intuition.
  It generates hypotheses. Its unboundedness is strength and danger.



  A prototype can be an argument: it articulates a gap between the
  world as it is and as it could be.



  An argument reframes the gap in ways that can’t be unseen. It makes its claims
  visceral and renders the contrast to the status quo unmistakable. It functions
  as an irritant; its existence provokes a response and makes change feel
  necessary.
</description>
      <author> (sophia ooo)</author>
      <guid>https://sophia.ooo/writing/what-a-prototype-can-be/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 23:03:12 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Expect Subvertations</title>
      <link>https://knhash.in/expect-subvertations/</link>
      <description>A World Model is an AI's internal representation of cause and effect. Not memorized facts, but learned dynamics. A robot with a World Model can predict "if I...</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://knhash.in/expect-subvertations/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 23:03:08 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Antimatter Development Program</title>
      <link>https://caseyhandmer.wordpress.com/2025/11/26/antimatter-development-program/</link>
      <description>Printable PDF of this post.  “Space is big. You just won’t believe how vastly, hugely, mind-bogglingly big it is. I mean, you may think it’s a long way down the road to the chemist…</description>
      <guid>https://caseyhandmer.wordpress.com/2025/11/26/antimatter-development-program/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 23:03:05 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bringing Emacs Support to OCaml's LSP Server with `ocaml-eglot`</title>
      <link>https://tarides.com/blog/2025-11-27-bringing-emacs-support-to-ocaml-s-lsp-server-with-ocaml-eglot/</link>
      <description>Discover the `ocaml-eglot` project, a plugin that integrates OCaml's Emacs editor support with the LSP.</description>
      <category>visualstudio</category>
      <category>vscode</category>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <guid>https://tarides.com/blog/2025-11-27-bringing-emacs-support-to-ocaml-s-lsp-server-with-ocaml-eglot/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 23:03:01 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Age of “Don’t do it yourself”</title>
      <link>https://blog.rybarix.com/2025/11/26/age-of-dont-diy.html</link>
      <description>Lately, I started seeing more and more replies to the juniors where they shouldn’t try to build something themselves but instead use off the shelf solution.</description>
      <category>web</category>
      <guid>https://blog.rybarix.com/2025/11/26/age-of-dont-diy.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 23:02:56 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This time it’s not fatigue, but disconnection</title>
      <link>https://morrick.me/archives/10176</link>
      <description>Trying to elaborate on why I feel increasingly disconnected from tech and by tech, and why this isn't just some passing sense of fatigue.</description>
      <category>visualstudio</category>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>apple</category>
      <guid>https://morrick.me/archives/10176</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 23:02:52 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Delivering Value Without the Weight of Over-Engineering</title>
      <link>https://uberpub.com/posts/delivering-value-without-the-weight-of-over-engineering</link>
      <description>Every software team has faced this familiar dilemma: should we build it fast, or build it right? Agile promises a way to do both, but let's be honest, in practice it's like walking a tightrope. On one side is the rush to deliver something now; on the other, the pull to make it perfect for every possible future.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <guid>https://uberpub.com/posts/delivering-value-without-the-weight-of-over-engineering</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 23:02:48 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The State of College Hackathons | Deveesh Shetty</title>
      <link>https://dev.shetty.me/blog/the-state-of-college-hackathons?v=2</link>
      <description>My perspective on how college hackathons are drifting from their original purpose, and how AI is changing what participants build and how they learn.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <category>python</category>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <guid>https://dev.shetty.me/blog/the-state-of-college-hackathons?v=2</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 23:02:44 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>belongings</title>
      <link>https://amulya.no/belongings.html</link>
      <description>The amortized daily cost represents how much I've spent per day to own each item. It is calculated by dividing the purchase price by the number of days owned. 
                If I were to, say, lose an item, this metric is roughly the amount that I paid to own that item for a day. 
                This metric naturally decreases over time as items are kept longer and so it rewards long-term ownership of the things I buy..it's a subtle encouragement to avoid impulsive buying and to think carefully about purchases.  
                When items are sold or given away, they stop contributing to the total amortized cost so it is a dynamic measure of my current material commitment. My goal is to keep this value as low as possible, or atleast strive to make it to 1kr/day per item for *most* items.
                It is ofcourse unrealistic to expect this for all items, especially electronics and gadgets which tend to have a higher upfront cost and depreciate quickly but I try to be mindful of their ADC when making purchases.</description>
      <category>web</category>
      <guid>https://amulya.no/belongings.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 23:02:41 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is RCE Really Just Low Severity?</title>
      <link>https://www.0xkato.xyz/Is-RCE-Really-Just-Low-Severity/</link>
      <description>A friendly case study of a command injection in fmt::say, how it was fixed, and how impact and exposure shape severity</description>
      <guid>https://www.0xkato.xyz/Is-RCE-Really-Just-Low-Severity/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 23:02:38 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Running a Business Means Contact With Reality - Fried Kielbasa</title>
      <link>https://fredkozlowski.com/2025/11/02/running-a-business-means-contact-with-reality/</link>
      <description>A year ago I decided to help build a service business for my mom because I wanted to learn about marketing and business. One of the largest blindspots engineers have is around sales and marketing. I was determined to not fall into this trap, but marketing seemed like a skill I couldn’t just learn by […]</description>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <guid>https://fredkozlowski.com/2025/11/02/running-a-business-means-contact-with-reality/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 23:02:34 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to get hired in 2025</title>
      <link>https://tonsky.me/blog/hiring-ai/</link>
      <description>A collection of red flags in software engineers' test assignments</description>
      <author> (https://www.facebook.com/nikitonsky)</author>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://tonsky.me/blog/hiring-ai/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 23:02:30 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>All that is solid melts into code</title>
      <link>https://www.robinsloan.com/lab/all-that-is-solid/</link>
      <description>More computer, rather than more human.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://www.robinsloan.com/lab/all-that-is-solid/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 23:02:25 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Same-day upstream Linux support for Snapdragon 8 Elite Gen 5 mobile platform </title>
      <link>https://www.qualcomm.com/developer/blog/2025/10/same-day-snapdragon-8-elite-gen-5-upstream-linux-support</link>
      <description>Initial kernel and subsystem support for new Snapdragon 8 Elite Gen 5 posted for review. Learn what’s in the patches and how you can start working with them.</description>
      <category>linux</category>
      <guid>https://www.qualcomm.com/developer/blog/2025/10/same-day-snapdragon-8-elite-gen-5-upstream-linux-support</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 22:02:02 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI CEO – Replace Your Boss Before They Replace You</title>
      <link>https://replaceyourboss.ai/</link>
      <description>Stop working for humans. AI CEO delivers algorithmic thought leadership, with instant decisions, and zero ego. Replace your boss before they replace you.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://replaceyourboss.ai/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 21:02:04 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We're Losing Our Voice to LLMs | Tony Alicea</title>
      <link>https://tonyalicea.dev/blog/were-losing-our-voice-to-llms/</link>
      <description>We are losing something precious in the age of LLMs: our unique voices.</description>
      <guid>https://tonyalicea.dev/blog/were-losing-our-voice-to-llms/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 19:02:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google's Antigravity IDE Sparks Forking Debate -- Visual Studio Magazine</title>
      <link>https://visualstudiomagazine.com/articles/2025/11/21/googles-antigravity-ide-sparks-forking-debate.aspx</link>
      <description>Google's new Antigravity IDE spurred much developer debate focusing heavily on its apparent status as a Visual Studio Code fork, with developers debating why another fork is needed, what it means for the VS Code ecosystem, and how open source reuse, lock-in, and fragmentation should be handled in AI-focused development tools.</description>
      <category>vscode</category>
      <category>visualstudio</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <guid>https://visualstudiomagazine.com/articles/2025/11/21/googles-antigravity-ide-sparks-forking-debate.aspx</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 19:02:07 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linux Kernel Explorer | reverser.dev</title>
      <link>https://reverser.dev/linux-kernel-explorer</link>
      <description>Interactive Linux kernel source code browser with guided learning paths.</description>
      <category>linux</category>
      <guid>https://reverser.dev/linux-kernel-explorer</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 14:02:01 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DIY NAS: 2026 Edition</title>
      <link>https://blog.briancmoses.com/2025/11/diy-nas-2026-edition.html</link>
      <description>An 8-bay DIY NAS with 10GbE networking, TrueNAS 25.10.1, an Intel N355 CPU, 32GB of DDR5 RAM, and a smallish form factor that occupies less than 20 liters of your office space.</description>
      <category>rust</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <guid>https://blog.briancmoses.com/2025/11/diy-nas-2026-edition.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 14:01:58 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ray Marching Soft Shadows in 2D</title>
      <link>https://www.rykap.com/2020/09/23/distance-fields/</link>
      <description>Software Engineer at Figma. Previously at Dropbox. Studied Math/CS at Brown University.
</description>
      <guid>https://www.rykap.com/2020/09/23/distance-fields/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 13:02:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitHub - penpot/penpot: Penpot: The open-source design tool for design and code collaboration</title>
      <link>https://github.com/penpot/penpot</link>
      <description>Penpot: The open-source design tool for design and code collaboration - penpot/penpot</description>
      <category>containers</category>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <category>youtube</category>
      <category>web</category>
      <guid>https://github.com/penpot/penpot</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 10:01:58 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitHub - addyosmani/gemini-cli-tips: Gemini CLI Tips and Tricks</title>
      <link>https://github.com/addyosmani/gemini-cli-tips</link>
      <description>Gemini CLI Tips and Tricks. Contribute to addyosmani/gemini-cli-tips development by creating an account on GitHub.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>nodejs</category>
      <category>vscode</category>
      <category>containers</category>
      <category>python</category>
      <guid>https://github.com/addyosmani/gemini-cli-tips</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 08:01:58 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Update 25.11.26</title>
      <link>https://sbox.game/news/update-25-11-26</link>
      <description>s&amp;box is now an open source game engine, terrain looks 20% cooler with anti tiling and seam fixes, and a ton of bug fixes this week</description>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <guid>https://sbox.game/news/update-25-11-26</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 05:02:28 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Migrating from GitHub to Codeberg ⚡ Zig Programming Language</title>
      <link>https://ziglang.org/news/migrating-from-github-to-codeberg/</link>
      <description>← Back to
        News
        page</description>
      <category>git</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <guid>https://ziglang.org/news/migrating-from-github-to-codeberg/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 05:02:24 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Don't Download Apps</title>
      <link>https://blog.calebjay.com/posts/dont-download-apps/</link>
      <description>The personal blog of Caleb Jay Rogers, Software Engineer</description>
      <guid>https://blog.calebjay.com/posts/dont-download-apps/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 03:02:13 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>