<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-16"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://linksfor.dev/feed.xml" />
    <title>linksfor.dev(s)</title>
    <link>https://linksfor.dev/feed.xml</link>
    <description>Curated links for devs</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>Rubenerd: Xfce is great</title>
      <link>https://rubenerd.com/xfce-is-great/</link>
      <description>A post from David Gerard reminded me why I still use Xfce almost everywhere.</description>
      <author> (Ruben Schade)</author>
      <category>linux</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://rubenerd.com/xfce-is-great/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 14:02:27 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Order of the Sinking Star | Official Announcement Trailer</title>
      <link>https://youtube.com/watch?v=OIxuGF6CwnU</link>
      <description>Wishlist Now on Steam: https://bit.ly/3Mu2Zle

We’re excited to announce Order of the Sinking Star, a massive narrative puzzle adventure featuring more than one thousand hand-crafted puzzles, an unlikely cast of heroes, and hundreds of hours of gameplay designed to put your intellect to the test. In development from Thekla, Inc., and led by legendary, award-winning game designer Jonathan Blow behind critically acclaimed puzzle games, The Witness and Braid, Order of the Sinking Star is a huge and innovative puzzle game that’s been in the making for 10 years since the release of The Witness. Order of the Sinking Star will launch on PC in 2026. Additional platforms and the release timing for the game will be revealed at a later date. 

ABOUT ORDER OF THE SINKING STAR 

From Thekla, Inc. comes Order of the Sinking Star, a massive narrative adventure featuring more than one thousand hand-crafted puzzles designed to put your intellect to the test. You are transported to a realm of curious magic, dangerous contraptions, and vicious monsters. You'll explore four distinct worlds, each with its own mechanics, characters, and stories, and then watch as they all collide. As the worlds merge, and characters meet one another, puzzle systems intertwine, creating surprising new possibilities. Explore at your own pace, revisit worlds and return to challenges as you see fit. Discover unique playable characters, master evolving gameplay mechanics, and decipher the deep mysteries of a sprawling, interconnected game world. Blending exploration, storytelling, and ever-progressing mechanics, Order of the Sinking Star invites you into a mysterious, living puzzle unlike anything you've played. 

STAY CONNECTED

https://bit.ly/m/SinkingStarGame</description>
      <author> (Jonathan Blow)</author>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <category>youtube</category>
      <guid>https://youtube.com/watch?v=OIxuGF6CwnU</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 13:02:02 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boredom is the Gatekeeper</title>
      <link>https://idiallo.com/blog/boredom-is-the-gatekeeper?src=feed</link>
      <description>That first Monday of my holiday break, I made a promise to myself. No work emails, no side projects, not even glancing at my blog. This time was for family, for Netflix queues, for rereading dog-eared</description>
      <category>python</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>youtube</category>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <guid>https://idiallo.com/blog/boredom-is-the-gatekeeper?src=feed</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 12:02:13 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI insiders seek to poison the data that feeds them</title>
      <link>https://www.theregister.com/2026/01/11/industry_insiders_seek_to_poison/</link>
      <description>: Poison Fountain project seeks allies to fight the power</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://www.theregister.com/2026/01/11/industry_insiders_seek_to_poison/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 06:02:17 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Statement from Federal Reserve Chair Jerome H. Powell</title>
      <link>https://www.federalreserve.gov/newsevents/speech/powell20260111a.htm</link>
      <description> Good evening.  On Friday, the Department of Justice served the Federal Reserve with grand jury subpoenas, threatening a criminal indictment related to my testi</description>
      <guid>https://www.federalreserve.gov/newsevents/speech/powell20260111a.htm</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 03:02:18 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Statement by Federal Reserve Chair Jerome H. Powell</title>
      <link>https://youtube.com/watch?v=KckGHaBLSn4</link>
      <description>https://www.federalreserve.gov/newsevents/speech/powell20260111a.htm

The Federal Reserve System is the central bank of the United States. It performs five general functions to promote the effective operation of the U.S. economy and, more generally, the public interest. 

The Federal Reserve conducts the nation’s monetary policy to promote maximum employment, stable prices, and moderate long-term interest rates in the U.S. economy; promotes the stability of the financial system and seeks to minimize and contain systemic risks through active monitoring and engagement in the U.S. and abroad; promotes the safety and soundness of individual financial institutions and monitors their impact on the financial system as a whole; fosters payment and settlement system safety and efficiency through services to the banking industry and the U.S. government that facilitate U.S.-dollar transactions and payments; and promotes consumer protection and community development through consumer-focused supervision and examination, research and analysis of emerging consumer issues and trends, community economic development activities, and the administration of consumer laws and regulations.

Visit the Federal Reserve’s website at www.federalreserve.gov for more information.</description>
      <author> (Federal Reserve)</author>
      <category>youtube</category>
      <guid>https://youtube.com/watch?v=KckGHaBLSn4</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 02:02:06 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Agent Fallacy</title>
      <link>https://noemititarenco.com/blog/the-agent-fallacy-prompt-orchestration/</link>
      <description>The Agent Fallacy</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>cloud</category>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <category>nodejs</category>
      <guid>https://noemititarenco.com/blog/the-agent-fallacy-prompt-orchestration/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 01:02:50 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Attempt at Independence from Big-Tech</title>
      <link>https://blog.antonlydike.de/My%20Attempt%20at%20Independence%20from%20Big-Tech.html</link>
      <description>I've been trying to stay ahead of the great enshittifcation. During which I thought a lot about the incentives involved, created some rules of thumb and discovered some cool services, which I wanted to talk about in this post.</description>
      <category>git</category>
      <category>web</category>
      <guid>https://blog.antonlydike.de/My%20Attempt%20at%20Independence%20from%20Big-Tech.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 01:02:47 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Axioms of Polity</title>
      <link>https://colinsteele.org/blog/axioms_of_polity/</link>
      <description>A manifesto for human/machine polity charting civispace. Neither as apex mind. A forest.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <guid>https://colinsteele.org/blog/axioms_of_polity/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 01:02:42 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Culture Isn't Stagnating, You Guys Are Just Old</title>
      <link>https://www.jenn.site/culture-isnt-stagnating-you-guys-are-just-old/</link>
      <description>People who talk about how culture is stagnating[^1] all point to around the same arguments: movies are all sequels, books and music are getting simpler, Netf...</description>
      <category>youtube</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <guid>https://www.jenn.site/culture-isnt-stagnating-you-guys-are-just-old/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 01:02:39 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Always Already Betas</title>
      <link>https://disjunctionsmag.com/articles/always-already-betas/</link>
      <description>The user subject and the GPT grindset</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://disjunctionsmag.com/articles/always-already-betas/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 01:02:36 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sophisticated Simplicity of Modern SQLite</title>
      <link>https://shivekkhurana.com/blog/sqlite-in-production/</link>
      <description>A benchmark-driven guide to tuning SQLite for production workloads</description>
      <author> (Shivek Khurana)</author>
      <category>sql</category>
      <category>vscode</category>
      <category>cloud</category>
      <category>nodejs</category>
      <guid>https://shivekkhurana.com/blog/sqlite-in-production/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 01:02:32 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Writing a work log</title>
      <link>https://fredrikmeyer.net/2026/01/11/work-log.html</link>
      <description>About a year ago I started writing a “work diary”. The process is simple: at the end of the day, I write a few sentences of what I did that day at work.</description>
      <category>sql</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <category>web</category>
      <guid>https://fredrikmeyer.net/2026/01/11/work-log.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 01:02:28 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weird DNS behavior on Alpine Linux - .local and mDNS</title>
      <link>https://ozelot.fyi/blog/weird-dns-behavior-on-alpine-linux/</link>
      <description>Learn why .local name resolution behaves differently on Alpine Linux and minimal environments.</description>
      <category>linux</category>
      <category>containers</category>
      <guid>https://ozelot.fyi/blog/weird-dns-behavior-on-alpine-linux/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 01:02:25 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diagnosing performance issues in .NET applications with dotnet-trace and Perfetto</title>
      <link>https://dfamonteiro.com/posts/using-dotnet-trace-with-perfetto/</link>
      <description>As the software industry transitioned towards more cloud-centric environments, programming languages have had to focus on treating virtualized Linux environments as first-class citizens or risk getting left behind. C# was no exception and for this language to maintain its popularity, Microsoft had to perform a complete overhaul of the .NET runtime to make it cloud-ready.
As part of this initiative to make .NET platform-agnostic, a supporting cast of CLI diagnostic tools was developed from scratch with the goal of uniformizing the developer experience of diagnosing C# applications across operating systems. One of these tools is dotnet-trace: a tool that can be hooked into a running .NET application to collect tracing data which can then be analysed with trace viewers.</description>
      <category>sql</category>
      <category>containers</category>
      <category>aspnet</category>
      <category>dotnet</category>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <guid>https://dfamonteiro.com/posts/using-dotnet-trace-with-perfetto/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 01:02:22 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FUSE is All You Need - Giving agents access to anything via filesystems</title>
      <link>https://jakobemmerling.de/posts/fuse-is-all-you-need/</link>
      <description>Giving agents access to a sandboxed environment with a shell and a filesystem has been the latest hype when it comes to agentic harnesses. Recent examples of this include:
Turso’s AgentFS Anthropic’s Agent SDK, which brings Claude Code’s harness to non-coding domains Vercel rebuilding their text-to-SQL agent on top of a sandbox Anthropic’s Agent Skills for filesystem-based progressive disclosure The argument for why this is good goes something like this:
The big labs are doing heavy RL for coding tasks in these kinds of environments. Aligning more closely with such a harness brings free gains from the coding domain to other problem spaces.</description>
      <category>containers</category>
      <category>sql</category>
      <category>typescript</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>apple</category>
      <guid>https://jakobemmerling.de/posts/fuse-is-all-you-need/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 01:02:18 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mitigating the Billion Dollar Mistake</title>
      <link>https://www.gingerbill.org/article/2026/01/11/mitigating-the-billion-dollar-mistake/</link>
      <description>This article is continuation to: Was it really a Billion Dollar Mistake?.
After reading a lot of the comments on numerous social media sites on the original article, I think I need to clarify a lot more.
The main points I wanted to clarify:
Null pointer dereferences are empirically the easiest class of invalid memory addresses to catch at runtime, and are the least common kind of invalid memory addresses that happen in memory unsafe languages. I do think it was a costly mistake but the “obvious solutions” to the problem are probably just as costly, if not more so, but in very subtle ways which most people neglected to understand in the article1. I think that even if Tony Hoare didn’t “invent” NULL pointers, within a couple years someone else would have. I don’t think it’s a “mistake” the programming world was ever going to avoid. I am talking about languages that run on modern systems with virtual memory, not embedded systems where you interact with physical memory directly. Those platforms in my opinion need much different kinds of languages which unfortunately do not exist yet. I was also talking about languages akin to C and Odin, not languages that run on a VM or have “everything be a reference”. Languages where Everything is a Pointer A lot of commentors based their complaints in their experience with languages like Java/C#/Python/etc, and the issues with null-pointer-exceptions (NPEs) in them. What I think a lot of people seemed to forget is that in those languages, virtually everything is a pointer, unlike in a language like C/Go/Odin which has explicit pointers. When everything is a pointer, it is exponentially more likely that you will hit a pointer that is invalid. And in the case of a managed (garbage collected) language, that invalid pointer will most definitely be a null pointer. This is why I can understand the problem of having null pointers in such languages.</description>
      <category>rust</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <guid>https://www.gingerbill.org/article/2026/01/11/mitigating-the-billion-dollar-mistake/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 01:02:15 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impressed by Synology Support</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmyhostna.me/posts/impressed-by-synology-support</link>
      <description>I've recently written about an issue that I have been experiencing with Synology Drive on macOS for many months. These days when you are running into …</description>
      <category>apple</category>
      <guid>https://blog.notmyhostna.me/posts/impressed-by-synology-support</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 01:02:12 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitHub - icloud-photos-downloader/icloud_photos_downloader: A command-line tool to download photos from iCloud</title>
      <link>https://github.com/icloud-photos-downloader/icloud_photos_downloader</link>
      <description>A command-line tool to download photos from iCloud - icloud-photos-downloader/icloud_photos_downloader</description>
      <category>apple</category>
      <category>nodejs</category>
      <category>containers</category>
      <category>linux</category>
      <guid>https://github.com/icloud-photos-downloader/icloud_photos_downloader</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 00:02:11 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The struggle of resizing windows on macOS Tahoe – no.heger</title>
      <link>https://noheger.at/blog/2026/01/11/the-struggle-of-resizing-windows-on-macos-tahoe/</link>
      <description>A lot has already been said about the absurdly large corner radius of windows on macOS Tahoe. People are calling the way it looks comical, like a child’s toy, or downright insane.</description>
      <guid>https://noheger.at/blog/2026/01/11/the-struggle-of-resizing-windows-on-macos-tahoe/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 23:02:16 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025 in retrospect &amp; happy new year 2026! – Gentoo Linux</title>
      <link>https://www.gentoo.org/news/2026/01/05/new-year.html</link>
      <description>News and information from Gentoo Linux</description>
      <category>rust</category>
      <category>python</category>
      <category>linux</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <guid>https://www.gentoo.org/news/2026/01/05/new-year.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 21:02:11 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thanks AI!</title>
      <link>https://gist.github.com/richhickey/ea94e3741ff0a4e3af55b9fe6287887f</link>
      <description>Thanks AI! GitHub Gist: instantly share code, notes, and snippets.</description>
      <author> (262588213843476)</author>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://gist.github.com/richhickey/ea94e3741ff0a4e3af55b9fe6287887f</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 18:02:18 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I dumped Windows 11 for Linux, and you should too</title>
      <link>https://www.notebookcheck.net/I-dumped-Windows-11-for-Linux-and-you-should-too.1190961.0.html</link>
      <description>With the growing number of users jumping from Windows to Linux, I decided to fully take the plunge and dive deep into the Open Source ocean. A few months and several headaches later, it has proved to be the best computer-related decision I've made in over a decade (and perhaps in my entire life).</description>
      <author> (Sam Medley)</author>
      <category>linux</category>
      <category>android</category>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <category>typescript</category>
      <guid>https://www.notebookcheck.net/I-dumped-Windows-11-for-Linux-and-you-should-too.1190961.0.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 17:02:11 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Don't fall into the anti-AI hype</title>
      <link>https://antirez.com/news/158</link>
      <description />
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>python</category>
      <guid>https://antirez.com/news/158</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 16:02:08 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>