<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-16"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://linksfor.dev/feed.xml" />
    <title>linksfor.dev(s)</title>
    <link>https://linksfor.dev/feed.xml</link>
    <description>Curated links for devs</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>» A Looking Glass Half Empty, Part 2: A Series of Unfortunate Events The Digital Antiquarian</title>
      <link>https://www.filfre.net/2025/10/a-looking-glass-half-empty-part-2-a-series-of-unfortunate-events/</link>
      <description>Coming out of 1998, the folks at Looking Glass Studios believed they had pretty good reason to feel optimistic about their future. With Thief, they had delivered not just their first profitable original game since 1995’s Flight Unlimited but their biggest single commercial success ever. They had no fewer than four more games slated for release within the next fifteen months, a positively blistering pace for them. Yes, all of said games were sequels and iterations on existing brands, but that was just the nature of the industry by now, wasn’t it? As long-running franchises like Ultima had first begun to demonstrate fifteen years ago, there was no reason you couldn’t continue to innovate under a well-known and -loved banner headline. Looking Glass closed their Austin office that had done so much to pay the bills in the past by taking on porting contracts. In the wake of Thief, they felt ready to concentrate entirely on their own games.</description>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <category>visualstudio</category>
      <category>encryption</category>
      <guid>https://www.filfre.net/2025/10/a-looking-glass-half-empty-part-2-a-series-of-unfortunate-events/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 00:01:56 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Treat your morning ritual like an opening chess move - Herbert Lui</title>
      <link>https://herbertlui.net/treat-your-morning-ritual-like-an-opening-chess-move/</link>
      <description>Life throws curveballs at you. A problem might come up in the evening that needs to wait until the next morning. An evening of sleep might be interrupted, or you might wake up earlier than you’d expected and not be able to fall asleep. Perhaps you want to get some fresh air in the morning. […]</description>
      <guid>https://herbertlui.net/treat-your-morning-ritual-like-an-opening-chess-move/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 23:02:31 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A non-technical CFO is shipping better code than the agencies he hired</title>
      <link>https://martinalderson.com/posts/non-technical-cfo-shipping-better-code-than-agencies/</link>
      <description>A non-technical CFO built a production operations dashboard with Claude Code that had failed with low-code tools and agencies. This shift in who can build software is going to change everything.</description>
      <author> (Martin Alderson)</author>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>encryption</category>
      <category>sql</category>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <guid>https://martinalderson.com/posts/non-technical-cfo-shipping-better-code-than-agencies/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 23:02:27 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yohei Yamasaki (yayoi)</title>
      <link>https://yayo1.com/en/blog/tiny-truetype-renderer/</link>
      <description>I am a software engineer and a computer science student based in Germany with a keen interest in the intersection of web technology and 2D graphics.</description>
      <category>git</category>
      <guid>https://yayo1.com/en/blog/tiny-truetype-renderer/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 23:02:24 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My most popular application</title>
      <link>https://blog.6nok.org/my-most-popular-application/</link>
      <description>A post about the tracker app I built for my girlfriend</description>
      <category>apple</category>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <category>web</category>
      <guid>https://blog.6nok.org/my-most-popular-application/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 23:02:20 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Hidden Cost of URL Design</title>
      <link>https://alfy.blog/2025/10/16/hidden-cost-of-url-design.html</link>
      <description>URL design impacts application architecture, performance, and costs. Case study: how flat URLs caused 2x backend load and how we optimized it.</description>
      <author> (Ahmad Elalfy)</author>
      <category>cloud</category>
      <category>sql</category>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <guid>https://alfy.blog/2025/10/16/hidden-cost-of-url-design.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 23:02:17 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On dealing with GPT results, or, Pots, Kettles And Hallucinations</title>
      <link>https://ebellani.github.io/blog/2025/on-dealing-with-gpt-results-or-pots-kettles-and-hallucinations/</link>
      <description>.org-center { margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center; } Hallucinations in GPTs can lead to the dissemination of false information, creating harmful outcomes in applications of critical decision making or leading to mistrust in AI. In a viral instance, The New York Times published an article about a lawyer who used ChatGPT to produce case citations without realizing they were fictional, or hallucinated. This incident highlights the danger of hallucinations in LLM-based queries; often the hallucinations are subtle and go easily unnoticed.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://ebellani.github.io/blog/2025/on-dealing-with-gpt-results-or-pots-kettles-and-hallucinations/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 23:02:12 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Engineers Can Learn from Sales</title>
      <link>https://togetherlondon.com/insights/what-engineers-can-learn-from-sales</link>
      <description>If you can’t sell your ideas, they won’t get adopted.</description>
      <guid>https://togetherlondon.com/insights/what-engineers-can-learn-from-sales</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 23:02:09 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Polars vs Pandas – Quantile Method</title>
      <link>https://wedgworth.dev/polars-vs-pandas-quantile-method/</link>
      <description>You can save some memory by moving to Polars from Pandas but watch out for a subtle difference in the quantile's different default interpolation methods.</description>
      <category>python</category>
      <category>vscode</category>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <guid>https://wedgworth.dev/polars-vs-pandas-quantile-method/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 23:02:06 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Text Offset Calculations</title>
      <link>https://beeb.li/blog/optimizing-text-offset-calculation</link>
      <description>A tale of optimization for an algorithm that turns byte offsets into line and column numbers, and UTF-16 offsets. The final implementation leverages SIMD and fixes several inefficiencies in the original solution.
</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>vscode</category>
      <category>rust</category>
      <guid>https://beeb.li/blog/optimizing-text-offset-calculation</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 23:02:02 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Copilot Inline Suggestions Are Like TikTok</title>
      <link>https://remy.duthu.org/2025/10/18/copilot-inline-suggestions-are-like-tik-tok.html</link>
      <description>I’ve spent the last few months using GitHub Copilot without inline suggestions.
Since the feature came out, I’ve been uneasy about it.
It feels to me like the TikTok vs. YouTube debate: do I want to choose the content I consume or let an algorithm feed me what it thinks I want?</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>vscode</category>
      <category>youtube</category>
      <category>web</category>
      <guid>https://remy.duthu.org/2025/10/18/copilot-inline-suggestions-are-like-tik-tok.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 23:01:58 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fast calculation of the distance to cubic Bezier curves on the GPU</title>
      <link>https://blog.pkh.me/p/46-fast-calculation-of-the-distance-to-cubic-bezier-curves-on-the-gpu.html</link>
      <description>Bézier curves are a core building block of text and 2D shapes rendering.
There are several approaches to rendering them, but one especially challenging
problem, both mathematically and technically, is computing the distance to
a Bézier curve. For quadratic curves (one control point), this is fairly
accessible, but for cubic (two control points) we're going to see why it is
so hard.</description>
      <category>git</category>
      <guid>https://blog.pkh.me/p/46-fast-calculation-of-the-distance-to-cubic-bezier-curves-on-the-gpu.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 22:01:56 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Release 15.0.0 · BurntSushi/ripgrep</title>
      <link>https://github.com/BurntSushi/ripgrep/releases/tag/15.0.0</link>
      <description>Sponsorship is appreciated!
ripgrep 15 is a new major version release of ripgrep that mostly has bug fixes,
some minor performance improvements and minor new features.

In case you haven't heard of...</description>
      <category>git</category>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <guid>https://github.com/BurntSushi/ripgrep/releases/tag/15.0.0</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 21:02:01 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>./watch</title>
      <link>https://dotslashwatch.com/</link>
      <description>Many quartz watches do their best to hide away any electronic components from view.  The design concept for this watch was to embrace those digital components instead, taking inspiration from command-line interfaces and computer hardware.</description>
      <guid>https://dotslashwatch.com/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 20:01:56 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The pivot - Charlie's Diary</title>
      <link>https://www.antipope.org/charlie/blog-static/2025/10/the-pivot-1.html</link>
      <description>It's pretty clear now that a lot of the unrest we're seeing—and the insecurity-induced radicalization—is due to an unprecedented civilizational energy transition that looks to be more or less irreversible at this point.</description>
      <guid>https://www.antipope.org/charlie/blog-static/2025/10/the-pivot-1.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 06:02:03 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>