<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-16"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://linksfor.dev/feed.xml" />
    <title>linksfor.dev(s)</title>
    <link>https://linksfor.dev/feed.xml</link>
    <description>Curated links for devs</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>Statement by Denmark, Finland, France, Germany, the Netherlands, Norway, Sweden and the United Kingdom (englanniksi) - Presidentti</title>
      <link>https://www.presidentti.fi/statement-by-denmark-finland-france-germany-the-netherlands-norway-sweden-and-the-united-kingdom-englanniksi/</link>
      <description>As members of NATO, we are committed to strengthening Arctic security as a shared transatlantic interest. The pre-coordinated Danish exercise ”Arctic Endurance” conducted with Allies, responds to this necessity. It poses no threat to anyone. We stand in full solidarity with the Kingdom of Denmark and the people of Greenland. Building on the process begun […]</description>
      <guid>https://www.presidentti.fi/statement-by-denmark-finland-france-germany-the-netherlands-norway-sweden-and-the-united-kingdom-englanniksi/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 18:02:40 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The A in AGI stands for Ads</title>
      <link>https://ossa-ma.github.io/blog/openads</link>
      <description>Had to crunch the ad revenue projection numbers for OpenAI real quick, had enough of the fearmongering and nonsense takes. AGI... now funded by 5x60 second unskippable ads!</description>
      <category>cloud</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://ossa-ma.github.io/blog/openads</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 17:02:17 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stop using MySQL in 2026, it is not true open source</title>
      <link>https://optimizedbyotto.com/post/reasons-to-stop-using-mysql/</link>
      <description>If you care about supporting open source software, and still use MySQL in 2026, you should switch to MariaDB like so many others have already done.
</description>
      <category>cloud</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <category>linux</category>
      <category>sql</category>
      <category>vscode</category>
      <guid>https://optimizedbyotto.com/post/reasons-to-stop-using-mysql/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 14:02:12 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iconify - home of open source icons</title>
      <link>https://icon-sets.iconify.design/</link>
      <description>Open source vector icons from all popular icon sets</description>
      <guid>https://icon-sets.iconify.design/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 12:02:07 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>jQuery 4.0.0 | Official jQuery Blog</title>
      <link>https://blog.jquery.com/2026/01/17/jquery-4-0-0/</link>
      <description>jQuery: The Write Less, Do More, JavaScript Library</description>
      <category>nodejs</category>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <category>apple</category>
      <category>android</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <guid>https://blog.jquery.com/2026/01/17/jquery-4-0-0/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 10:02:02 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Héliographe (@heliographe_studio@mastodon.social)</title>
      <link>https://mastodon.social/@heliographe_studio/115890819509545391</link>
      <description>Attached: 1 image

If you put the Apple icons in reverse it looks like the portfolio of someone getting really really good at icon design</description>
      <guid>https://mastodon.social/@heliographe_studio/115890819509545391</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 04:02:33 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TTY and Buffering</title>
      <link>https://mattrighetti.com/2026/01/12/tty-and-buffering</link>
      <description>Every developer has at least once in their career stumbled upon the scenariowhere a program would not print something as they initially thought. A fewyears a...</description>
      <category>rust</category>
      <guid>https://mattrighetti.com/2026/01/12/tty-and-buffering</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 01:03:39 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The thing that brought me joy</title>
      <link>https://www.stephenlewis.me/blog/the-thing-that-brought-me-joy/</link>
      <description>The code is not the point, but what if it’s the reason?</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>python</category>
      <guid>https://www.stephenlewis.me/blog/the-thing-that-brought-me-joy/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 01:03:35 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Don’t be a human alarm clock</title>
      <link>https://mannhowie.com/human-alarm-clock</link>
      <description>How to avoid being left behind by technology.</description>
      <guid>https://mannhowie.com/human-alarm-clock</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 01:03:32 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Don't waste your back pressure ·</title>
      <link>https://banay.me/dont-waste-your-backpressure/</link>
      <description>Back pressure for agents
You might notice a pattern in the most successful applications of agents over the last year. Projects that are able to
setup structure around the agent itself, to provide it with automated feedback on quality and correctness, have been able
to push them to work on longer horizon tasks.
This back pressure helps the agent identify mistakes as it progresses and models are now good enough that this feedback
can keep them aligned to a task for much longer. As an engineer, this means you can increase your leverage by delegating
progressively more complex tasks to agents, while increasing trust that when completed they are at a satisfactory standard.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>rust</category>
      <category>python</category>
      <guid>https://banay.me/dont-waste-your-backpressure/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 01:03:28 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My first year in sales as a technical founder</title>
      <link>https://www.fabiandietrich.com/blog/first-year-in-sales.html</link>
      <description>[11-2025 / English / 1917 words]</description>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://www.fabiandietrich.com/blog/first-year-in-sales.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 01:03:25 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hardware for local coding models is still affordable. For how long?</title>
      <link>https://mitjamartini.com/posts/2026/01/hardware-for-local-coding-models-still-affordable/</link>
      <description>The recent RAM price hikes have pushed GPU prices up as well. The only systems that have not yet been affected to the same extent are Macs and high-end GPUs (RTX 6000 Pro and above). However, I would already classify GPUs as out of reach: running coding models with sufficiently large context windows would require one or two RTX 6000 Pro cards, or three to six RTX 5090s.
Let’s take a look at Macs instead.
Price Mem Bandwidth CPU RAM NVMe CPU GPU Model Price/Bandwidth Price/Memory 2.500 EUR 273 GB/s M4 Pro 64 GB 1 TB 12C 16C Mac Mini 9,15 EUR/GB/s 39,06 EUR/GB 4.027 EUR 546 GB/s M4 Max 128 GB 1 TB 16C 40C Mac Studio 7,14 EUR/GB/s 31,43 EUR/GB 4.200 EUR 800 GB/s M3 Ultra 96 GB 1 TB 28C 60C Mac Studio 5,52 EUR/GB/s 43,75 EUR/GB 6.720 EUR 800 GB/s M3 Ultra 256 GB 2 TB 28C 60C Mac Studio 8,40 EUR/GB/s 26,25 EUR/GB 11.900 EUR 800 GB/s M3 Ultra 512 GB 4 TB 32C 80C Mac Studio 14,87 EUR/GB/s 23,24 EUR/GB Mac Studios with the M3 Ultra currently offer the best overall value. The 96 GB version is fast, and its RAM capacity is sufficient to run many general-purpose models using quantization. The 256 GB version can handle coding models at reasonable quantization levels with 64k context, which is just about sufficient for running coding agents 1. The 512 GB model, however, exceeds the €10k, which I consider a hard upper limit for what can reasonably be called an “affordable” system.
The price difference between the 96 GB and 256 GB Mac Studio models is surprisingly close to current RAM market prices. For comparison, 256 GB of DDR5-6000 RAM currently costs around €3,430, or €13.39 per GB. The price delta between the 96 GB and 256 GB Mac Studio, and between the 256 GB and 512 GB versions, is approximately €12.88 per GB and €18.50 per GB, respectively. If Apple were to return to its usual memory pricing premiums, the 256 GB configuration would likely end up much closer to €10,000.
Hosted inference is both cheaper and more capable, but it cannot be used in all scenarios. In particular, freelancers and small companies are often required to rely on local systems when working for larger clients. The M3 Ultra, launched in March 2025, together with improved models, quantization techniques, and REAP, has effectively kicked off an era of affordable local coding models. That era may now enter a pause: RAM prices are expected to rise through 2026 and are likely to remain elevated until 2027 or 2028 2.
Based on benchmark results shared on r/localllama ↩︎
Based on an analysis from December 2025 on wccftech ↩︎</description>
      <category>apple</category>
      <guid>https://mitjamartini.com/posts/2026/01/hardware-for-local-coding-models-still-affordable/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 01:03:21 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Artisanal Code - Sunny Amrat-Nath</title>
      <link>https://sunnyamrat.com/posts/2026-01-17-artisanal-code/</link>
      <description>&gt; Our single-origin, small-batch code is traceable through its commit history to artisanal programmers and traditional foundries. Incorporating a confluence of different cultures and languages, our code is hand-crafted, wrought through pull requests, processed on baremetal and roasted to perfection in a cast-iron CI/CD pipeline - giving you a bold, full-bodied, rich shot of open-source goodness. The perfect start to your day.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>rust</category>
      <category>python</category>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <guid>https://sunnyamrat.com/posts/2026-01-17-artisanal-code/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 01:03:17 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The year everything changed</title>
      <link>https://networkgames.fyi/the-year-everything-changed</link>
      <description>Far from my best years being behind me, it feels as though everything in my life has been leading to this moment: building a completely new category of product where the most useful lessons come not from GitHub repos, but from the science fiction novels I’ve been obsessed with since I was a kid.</description>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <guid>https://networkgames.fyi/the-year-everything-changed</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 01:03:14 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Musings on "The Internet After YouTube" | Scott Larson</title>
      <link>https://www.scottrlarson.com/updates/update-response-internet-after-youtube/</link>
      <description></description>
      <category>youtube</category>
      <guid>https://www.scottrlarson.com/updates/update-response-internet-after-youtube/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 01:03:07 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using the M1 MacBook Air in 2026</title>
      <link>https://mahadk.com/posts/m1-mba</link>
      <description>It's surprisingly capable more than five years later — as long as you temper your expectations.</description>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <category>apple</category>
      <category>vscode</category>
      <category>linux</category>
      <guid>https://mahadk.com/posts/m1-mba</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 01:03:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Computers Work</title>
      <link>https://www.aweineverything.com/how-computers-work/</link>
      <description>A deep dive into how computers work.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>apple</category>
      <guid>https://www.aweineverything.com/how-computers-work/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 01:02:56 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Counterfactual Evaluation for Recommendation Systems</title>
      <link>https://eugeneyan.com/writing/counterfactual-evaluation/</link>
      <description>Thinking about recsys as interventional vs. observational, and inverse propensity scoring.</description>
      <author> (https://eugeneyan.com/about/)</author>
      <category>android</category>
      <category>apple</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://eugeneyan.com/writing/counterfactual-evaluation/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 01:02:52 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Backpressure in Client-Server Applications | Travis Haagen's Blog</title>
      <link>https://travishaagen.github.io/posts/backpressure-in-client-server-applications/</link>
      <description>Backpressure, in client-server applications, is accomplished when a client adjusts its transmission of messages in response to a server that has slowed its processing of messages.</description>
      <guid>https://travishaagen.github.io/posts/backpressure-in-client-server-applications/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 01:02:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We Don't Build the Machines Anymore</title>
      <link>https://blog.mariusvach.com/posts/designing-not-building</link>
      <description>We design the machines. We don't build them anymore. I'm still not sure how I feel about that.</description>
      <category>encryption</category>
      <category>cloud</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>python</category>
      <guid>https://blog.mariusvach.com/posts/designing-not-building</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 01:02:45 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Death of Software Development</title>
      <link>https://mike.tech/blog/death-of-software-development</link>
      <description>The job of software developer is dead. You might still be coding, but the profession as you knew it is gone.</description>
      <category>typescript</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <guid>https://mike.tech/blog/death-of-software-development</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 01:02:42 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Desired State to Negotiated State</title>
      <link>https://jlmr.dev/posts/from-desired-state-to-negotiated-state/</link>
      <description>Software Engineer writing about infrastructure, Kubernetes, and Go</description>
      <category>containers</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <category>encryption</category>
      <category>vscode</category>
      <category>cloud</category>
      <guid>https://jlmr.dev/posts/from-desired-state-to-negotiated-state/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 01:02:38 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Architecture for Disposable Systems</title>
      <link>https://tuananh.net/2026/01/15/architecture-for-disposable-systems/</link>
      <description>As coding agents make software cheaper and lower quality, we're moving toward disposable software, and that changes everything about how we architect systems.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://tuananh.net/2026/01/15/architecture-for-disposable-systems/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 01:02:35 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I Stopped Reading Fiction and How I Found It Again</title>
      <link>https://leroy.works/articles/why-i-stopped-reading-fiction-and-how-i-found-it-again/</link>
      <description>For some reason that I don't understand I've always been searching for something. This need to search has always been present within me but I can't quite put into words what it is that I'm searching for, whether I will ever find it, or if the search will ever finish. Well, I can always find words to describe it but they do a poor job and never capture the depth of what I want to find, if it's even possible to find: I'm always searching for the connection of how my humanity relates to the mystery of all the different lives that have ever lived.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://leroy.works/articles/why-i-stopped-reading-fiction-and-how-i-found-it-again/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 01:02:32 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why We've Tried to Replace Developers Every Decade Since 1969</title>
      <link>https://www.caimito.net/en/blog/2025/12/07/the-recurring-dream-of-replacing-developers.html</link>
      <description>Every decade brings new promises: this time, we'll finally make software development simple enough that we won't need so many developers. From COBOL to AI, the pattern repeats. Business leaders gro...</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>ruby</category>
      <category>python</category>
      <guid>https://www.caimito.net/en/blog/2025/12/07/the-recurring-dream-of-replacing-developers.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 01:02:28 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Is Password Hygiene Important? – hnst1</title>
      <link>https://hnst1.com/why-is-password-hygiene-important/</link>
      <description>Introduction: In an era where our bank accounts, family photos, and work identities live behind a login screen, the phrase “it won’t happen to me” is no longer a security strategy. With billions of data points leaked every year, your digital safety isn’t determined by if your information will be exposed, but by how well you’ve prepared for when it happens. This article explores the common pitfalls of password management and introduces the one tool that makes “impossible” security easy for everyone: the Password Manager.</description>
      <category>encryption</category>
      <category>apple</category>
      <category>android</category>
      <guid>https://hnst1.com/why-is-password-hygiene-important/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 01:02:25 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I'll build this later</title>
      <link>https://cnicodeme.com/ill-build-this-later</link>
      <description>Your roadmap is a cat-and-mouse game between new ideas/features/bugs that are added to it versus what you and your team can tackle. Ideally, it should go down, but it’s often the contrary that happens.
And then, you get a customer asking you for some...</description>
      <author> (https://cnicodeme.com/@cnicodeme)</author>
      <category>sql</category>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <guid>https://cnicodeme.com/ill-build-this-later</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 01:02:21 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Too Far for WiFi? The Ultimate 600ft PoE Camera Setup!</title>
      <link>https://youtube.com/watch?v=EpEX9IWol18</link>
      <description>Curious how to run ethernet more than 100 yards? Find out!</description>
      <author> (Dave's Garage)</author>
      <category>youtube</category>
      <guid>https://youtube.com/watch?v=EpEX9IWol18</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 22:02:11 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tech Promised Everything. Did it deliver? | Scott Hanselman | TEDxPortland</title>
      <link>https://youtube.com/watch?v=dVG8W-0p6vg</link>
      <description>The technology industry promised us connection, convenience, and creativity. Has it delivered, or offered false promises that may never be fully realized? Scott Hanselman offers a candid look at what’s really happening beneath the surface of AI and innovation and how we must make conscious, informed decisions about the tools shaping our future.

We could not do this without community support. With special thanks to the University of Oregon for their presenting partnership. The world-class stage production by For Good &amp; Co. The incredible legacy bound Event Book provided by Premier Press. Lastly, the brand identity and creative digital craft provided by our Agency of Record - Thesis. All of our Partners and event history can be found at TEDxPortland.com. Scott Hanselman is the VP of Developer Community at Microsoft and has spent over 30 years as a teacher, programmer, and prolific blogger. In addition to writing numerous technical books, Scott has produced nearly 2,000 episodes of his popular Hanselman Minutes and Azure Friday podcasts. A passionate technologist, he focuses on empowering developers and fostering inclusivity in tech. Scott frequently speaks at conferences worldwide, sharing insights on software development, productivity, and diversity in technology. This talk was given at a TEDx event using the TED conference format but independently organized by a local community. Learn more at https://www.ted.com/tedx</description>
      <author> (TEDx Talks)</author>
      <category>cloud</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>youtube</category>
      <guid>https://youtube.com/watch?v=dVG8W-0p6vg</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 19:02:08 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>