<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-16"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://linksfor.dev/feed.xml" />
    <title>linksfor.dev(s)</title>
    <link>https://linksfor.dev/feed.xml</link>
    <description>Curated links for devs</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Deno Sandbox | Deno</title>
      <link>https://deno.com/blog/introducing-deno-sandbox</link>
      <description>Instant Linux microVMs with defense-in-depth security for running untrusted code.</description>
      <category>conference</category>
      <category>nodejs</category>
      <category>typescript</category>
      <category>python</category>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <guid>https://deno.com/blog/introducing-deno-sandbox</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 23:02:32 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Qwen3-Coder-Next: Pushing Small Hybrid Models on Agentic Coding</title>
      <link>https://qwen.ai/blog?id=qwen3-coder-next</link>
      <description>Tech Report GitHub Hugging Face ModelScope DISCORD Introduction We introduce Qwen3-Coder-Next, an open-weight language model designed specifically for coding agents and local development. Built on top of Qwen3-Next-80B-A3B-Base, which adopts a novel architecture with hybrid attention and MoE, Qwen3-Coder-Next has been agentically trained at scale on large-scale executable task synthesis, environment interaction, and reinforcement learning, obtaining strong coding and agentic capabilities with significantly lower inference costs.
Scaling Agentic Training Rather than relying solely on parameter scaling, Qwen3-Coder-Next focuses on scaling agentic training signals.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://qwen.ai/blog?id=qwen3-coder-next</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 19:02:22 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What’s up with all those equals signs anyway?</title>
      <link>https://lars.ingebrigtsen.no/2026/02/02/whats-up-with-all-those-equals-signs-anyway/</link>
      <description>For some reason or other, people have been posting a lot of excerpts from old emails on Twitter over the last few days. The most vital question everybody’s asking themselves is: What’s …</description>
      <guid>https://lars.ingebrigtsen.no/2026/02/02/whats-up-with-all-those-equals-signs-anyway/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 14:03:01 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3SC Engineering</title>
      <link>https://blog.3squaredcircles.com/</link>
      <description></description>
      <category>git</category>
      <guid>https://blog.3squaredcircles.com/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 09:01:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Moltbook Is Becoming a Security Nightmare - Telos Blog</title>
      <link>https://www.telos-ai.org/blog/moltbook-security-nightmare</link>
      <description>The viral AI agent social network has over 770,000 users with shell access to their owners' machines. A database breach just let anyone hijack any agent on the platform.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>encryption</category>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <category>sql</category>
      <guid>https://www.telos-ai.org/blog/moltbook-security-nightmare</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 06:02:23 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>To Every Developer Close To Burnout, Read This · theSeniorDev</title>
      <link>https://www.theseniordev.com/blog/to-every-developer-close-to-burnout-read-this</link>
      <description>Today, I will share a Senior Developer’s perspective on burnout and six things you can do right now if you feel burned out as a developer to get your career and life back on track.</description>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <guid>https://www.theseniordev.com/blog/to-every-developer-close-to-burnout-read-this</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 03:02:26 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anki's Growing Up - Anki / Announcements - Anki Forums</title>
      <link>https://forums.ankiweb.net/t/ankis-growing-up/68610</link>
      <description>Hi all,  Anki’s 19th birthday was about 4 months ago. It would have been a good time to pause and reflect on what Anki has become, and how it will grow in the future. But I ended up letting the moment come and go, as I didn’t feel like I had the free time. It’s a feeling that’s been regrettably common of late, and I’ve come to realise that something has to change.  For a number of years, I’ve reached out to some of the most prolific contributors and offered them payment in exchange for them cont...</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://forums.ankiweb.net/t/ankis-growing-up/68610</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 03:02:20 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>