<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-16"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://linksfor.dev/feed.xml" />
    <title>linksfor.dev(s)</title>
    <link>https://linksfor.dev/feed.xml</link>
    <description>Curated links for devs</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>Michael Reeves (@integralpilot.bsky.social)</title>
      <link>https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:okydh7e54e2nok65kjxdklvd/post/3mdd55paffk2o</link>
      <description>On Apple M3, a Linux KDE plasma desktop under Fedora Asahi Remix is now WORKING! Super excited to share this update and happy to answer any questions! Co-credits to noopwafel and Shiz. :)</description>
      <category>linux</category>
      <guid>https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:okydh7e54e2nok65kjxdklvd/post/3mdd55paffk2o</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 21:02:46 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Nomad Soul The Digital Antiquarian</title>
      <link>https://www.filfre.net/2026/01/omikron-the-nomad-soul/</link>
      <description></description>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <category>visualstudio</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://www.filfre.net/2026/01/omikron-the-nomad-soul/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 21:02:40 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pushing Qwen3-Max-Thinking Beyond its Limits</title>
      <link>https://qwen.ai/blog?id=qwen3-max-thinking</link>
      <description>QWEN CHAT API DISCORD
Introduction We present Qwen3-Max-Thinking, our latest flagship reasoning model. By scaling up model parameters and leveraging substantial computational resources for reinforcement learning, Qwen3-Max-Thinking achieves significant performance improvements across multiple dimensions, including factual knowledge, complex reasoning, instruction following, alignment with human preferences, and agent capabilities. On 19 established benchmarks, it demonstrates performance comparable to leading models such as GPT-5.2-Thinking, Claude-Opus-4.5, and Gemini 3 Pro.
We further enhance Qwen3-Max-Thinking with two key innovations: (1) adaptive tool-use capabilities that enable on-demand retrieval and code interpreter invocation, now available at chat.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>nodejs</category>
      <category>python</category>
      <guid>https://qwen.ai/blog?id=qwen3-max-thinking</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 19:02:36 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vibe Coding Kills Open Source</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.15494</link>
      <description>Generative AI is changing how software is produced and used. In vibe coding, an AI agent builds software by selecting and assembling open-source software (OSS), often without users directly reading documentation, reporting bugs, or otherwise engaging with maintainers. We study the equilibrium effects of vibe coding on the OSS ecosystem. We develop a model with endogenous entry and heterogeneous project quality in which OSS is a scalable input into producing more software. Users choose whether to use OSS directly or through vibe coding. Vibe coding raises productivity by lowering the cost of using and building on existing code, but it also weakens the user engagement through which many maintainers earn returns. When OSS is monetized only through direct user engagement, greater adoption of vibe coding lowers entry and sharing, reduces the availability and quality of OSS, and reduces welfare despite higher productivity. Sustaining OSS at its current scale under widespread vibe coding requires major changes in how maintainers are paid.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>web</category>
      <guid>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.15494</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 18:02:53 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Video Games as Art · Gwern.net</title>
      <link>https://gwern.net/video-game-art</link>
      <description>Video games are art, but a strange art: their essence is transformation of the player, not description to the player. This makes meaningful criticism nearly impossible—you can point at the moon, but it’s not the moon, and once someone sees it, they no longer need the pointing.</description>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <guid>https://gwern.net/video-game-art</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 18:02:48 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Announcing MapLibre Tile: a modern and efficient vector tile format</title>
      <link>https://maplibre.org/news/2026-01-23-mlt-release/</link>
      <description>The MapLibre Organization is an umbrella for open-source mapping libraries.</description>
      <category>cloud</category>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <guid>https://maplibre.org/news/2026-01-23-mlt-release/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 17:02:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>programming</title>
      <link>https://www.reddit.com/r/programming/</link>
      <description>Whenever we spoke to people thinking about cyber security roles, we kept hearing “SOC work is just staring at alerts all day.” So, to demonstrate that it’s way more than that, we built a learning pathway filled with practical labs to recreate the experience of being a Security Operations Center Analyst.</description>
      <guid>https://www.reddit.com/r/programming/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 17:02:45 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A new digital divide? Coder worldviews, the ‘Slop economy,’ and democracy in the age of AI</title>
      <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/1369118X.2025.2566814</link>
      <description>Digital technologies are transforming democratic life in conflicting ways. This article bridges two perspectives to unpack these tensions. First, we present an original survey of software developer...</description>
      <category>encryption</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/1369118X.2025.2566814</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 16:02:48 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>the browser is the sandbox</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2026/Jan/25/the-browser-is-the-sandbox/</link>
      <description>Paul Kinlan is a web platform developer advocate at Google and recently turned his attention to coding agents. He quickly identified the importance of a robust sandbox for agents to …</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>web</category>
      <guid>https://simonwillison.net/2026/Jan/25/the-browser-is-the-sandbox/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 16:02:44 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>After two years of vibecoding, I'm back to writing by hand</title>
      <link>https://atmoio.substack.com/p/after-two-years-of-vibecoding-im</link>
      <description>Agents write units of changes that look good in isolation. They are consistent with themselves and your prompt. But respect for the whole, there is not.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>youtube</category>
      <guid>https://atmoio.substack.com/p/after-two-years-of-vibecoding-im</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 16:02:40 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Another 100 Tips to Write Better C# Code</title>
      <link>https://youtube.com/watch?v=V2uRyxffnHA</link>
      <description>Learn PostgreSQL for Free at Dometrain: https://dometrain.com/course/hands-on-learn-postgresql/?ref=nick-chapsas&amp;promo=youtube

Hello, everybody. I'm Nick, and in this video, I will give you 100 of my top .NET and C# Tips and Tricks to help you write better C# code.

Don't forget to comment, like and subscribe :)

Social Media:
Follow me on GitHub: https://github.com/Elfocrash
Follow me on Twitter: https://twitter.com/nickchapsas
Connect on LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/nick-chapsas

#csharp #dotnet</description>
      <author> (Nick Chapsas)</author>
      <category>sql</category>
      <category>dotnet</category>
      <category>youtube</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <guid>https://youtube.com/watch?v=V2uRyxffnHA</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 12:02:18 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitHub - clawdbot/clawdbot: Your own personal AI assistant. Any OS. Any Platform. The lobster way. 🦞</title>
      <link>https://github.com/clawdbot/clawdbot</link>
      <description>Your own personal AI assistant. Any OS. Any Platform. The lobster way. 🦞  - GitHub - clawdbot/clawdbot: Your own personal AI assistant. Any OS. Any Platform. The lobster way. 🦞</description>
      <category>nodejs</category>
      <category>apple</category>
      <category>conference</category>
      <category>android</category>
      <category>containers</category>
      <guid>https://github.com/clawdbot/clawdbot</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 12:02:17 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You have to know how to drive the car</title>
      <link>https://www.seangoedecke.com/knowing-how-to-drive-the-car/</link>
      <description>There are lots of different ways to be a software engineer. You can grind out code for twelve hours a day to make the world a better place. You can focus on glue work: process-based work that makes everyone around you more successful. You can join the conversation with your product manager and designer colleagues to influence what gets built, not just how it gets built. You can climb the ladder to staff engineer and above, or you can take it easy and focus on your hobbies. But whichever of these you choose, you have to know how tech companies work.</description>
      <guid>https://www.seangoedecke.com/knowing-how-to-drive-the-car/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 09:02:30 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FAA creates drone no-fly zone for ICE operations</title>
      <link>https://www.aerotime.aero/articles/faa-drone-no-fly-zone-ice-dhs</link>
      <description>The FAA has created nationwide moving drone no-fly zones around ICE vehicles and convoys, with criminal penalties for violating the restricted airspace.</description>
      <guid>https://www.aerotime.aero/articles/faa-drone-no-fly-zone-ice-dhs</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 04:02:16 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pruning Claude Code conversation history</title>
      <link>https://brtkwr.com/posts/2026-01-22-pruning-claude-code-conversation-history/</link>
      <description>A few days ago I cleaned up 200GB from my Mac and deliberately kept my Claude Code history at 2.3GB. Four days later it had grown to 9.5GB. Here’s how I pruned it back to 1.1GB without breaking conversation continuity.
This also broke ccs - my fuzzy finder for Claude conversations. Parsing 3GB JSONL files was taking forever. I’ve since added --max-size filtering to ccs (defaults to 1GB), but that just hides the problem. Better to prune the files themselves.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>apple</category>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <guid>https://brtkwr.com/posts/2026-01-22-pruning-claude-code-conversation-history/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 01:11:26 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Don't Write Evals for Fast-Moving Systems</title>
      <link>https://simon.podhajsky.net/blog/2026/evaluating-clobsidian/</link>
      <description>You're developing an LLM-powered system. It's moving fast. Should you write evals? Not yet.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://simon.podhajsky.net/blog/2026/evaluating-clobsidian/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 01:11:12 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>De-Vibing A Codebase</title>
      <link>https://dumbideas.xyz/posts/de-vibing-a-codebase/</link>
      <description>Like a digital hangover.</description>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <category>vscode</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://dumbideas.xyz/posts/de-vibing-a-codebase/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 01:11:08 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is ChatGPT Your Friend or Enemy: You Decide</title>
      <link>https://shielddigitaldesign.com/posts/2026/ai/</link>
      <description>Shield Digital Design Engineering analysis and signal integrity insights. Hardware and electrical engineering. PCB Design and simulations.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://shielddigitaldesign.com/posts/2026/ai/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 01:11:05 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First, Make Me Care, by Gwern · Gwern.net</title>
      <link>https://gwern.net/blog/2026/make-me-care</link>
      <description>Writing advice: some nonfiction fails because it opens with background instead of a hook—readers leave before reaching the good material. Find the single anomaly or question that makes your topic interesting, lead with that, and let the background follow once you’ve earned attention.</description>
      <guid>https://gwern.net/blog/2026/make-me-care</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 01:11:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bing is not as bad as you think (a search engine quality study) — nilch</title>
      <link>https://blog.nilch.org/blog/bing-is-not-as-bad-as-you-think-a-search-engine-quality-study/</link>
      <description>You've probably heard, or even said, how bad Bing's search results are in quality. It's true, they were pretty bad. Keyword "were". Back closer to the launch of Bing (then MSN search), the index size was significantly smaller than that of Google. However, here's the thing... it's been 21 years since it launched, and it has improved slowly over time a lot since then, and I have the data to prove it!</description>
      <category>cloud</category>
      <guid>https://blog.nilch.org/blog/bing-is-not-as-bad-as-you-think-a-search-engine-quality-study/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 01:10:56 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Turns out I was wrong about TDD</title>
      <link>https://martinalderson.com/posts/turns-out-i-was-wrong-about-tdd/</link>
      <description>I used to be a TDD sceptic - too much time writing tests for features that might get deleted. Then coding agents completely changed the economics of software testing.</description>
      <author> (Martin Alderson)</author>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>containers</category>
      <category>vscode</category>
      <guid>https://martinalderson.com/posts/turns-out-i-was-wrong-about-tdd/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 01:10:52 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Follow the trend lines, not the headlines</title>
      <link>https://www.adriankrebs.ch/blog/trend-lines-not-headlines/</link>
      <description>By almost every measure, life is better than ever. So why does it feel like things are falling apart?</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <guid>https://www.adriankrebs.ch/blog/trend-lines-not-headlines/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 01:10:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The future of software engineering is SRE | Swizec Teller</title>
      <link>https://swizec.com/blog/the-future-of-software-engineering-is-sre/</link>
      <description>When code gets cheap operational excellence wins. Anyone can build a greenfield demo, but it takes engineering to run a service.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <guid>https://swizec.com/blog/the-future-of-software-engineering-is-sre/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 01:10:45 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The one and only codebase I'm ever going to keep working on</title>
      <link>https://arjonagelhout.nl/writings/2026-01-25_the_one_and_only_codebase/</link>
      <description>A little while back, my contract ended with Treble Technologies, for whom I had been writing (parts of) a geometry processing pipeline for automated mesh simplification and mesh cleanup in C++.</description>
      <category>git</category>
      <guid>https://arjonagelhout.nl/writings/2026-01-25_the_one_and_only_codebase/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 01:10:42 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Another rabbit hole: Paperless-ngx</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmyhostna.me/posts/another-rabbit-hole-paperless-ngx</link>
      <description>As part of my quest to make things in my daily life more complicated I stumbled upon Paperless-ngx a few times already. This weekend I finally went …</description>
      <category>sql</category>
      <category>containers</category>
      <category>apple</category>
      <guid>https://blog.notmyhostna.me/posts/another-rabbit-hole-paperless-ngx</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 01:10:38 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>suspiciously precise floats, or, how I got Claude's real limits</title>
      <link>https://she-llac.com/claude-limits</link>
      <description>I reverse-engineered Claude's hidden subscription usage caps from two unrounded utilization floats, recovered exact denominators via Stern-Brocot, and compared what Pro/Max actually buy you versus API pricing (including caching).</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://she-llac.com/claude-limits</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 01:10:32 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stop Separating People Problems from Engineering Problems</title>
      <link>https://andrew.grahamyooll.com/blog/The-False-Dichotomy/</link>
      <description>Published on 2026-01-17 by Andrew Graham-Yooll</description>
      <category>sql</category>
      <guid>https://andrew.grahamyooll.com/blog/The-False-Dichotomy/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 01:10:28 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In defense of the .zip TLD</title>
      <link>https://luke.zip/posts/zip-defense/</link>
      <description>I am unbiased in this.</description>
      <author> (Luke Schaefer)</author>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://luke.zip/posts/zip-defense/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 01:10:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oneplus phone update introduces hardware anti-rollback</title>
      <link>https://consumerrights.wiki/w/Oneplus_phone_update_introduces_hardware_anti-rollback</link>
      <description>From Consumer Rights Wiki</description>
      <category>android</category>
      <guid>https://consumerrights.wiki/w/Oneplus_phone_update_introduces_hardware_anti-rollback</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 23:02:40 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>