<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-16"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://linksfor.dev/feed.xml" />
    <title>linksfor.dev(s)</title>
    <link>https://linksfor.dev/feed.xml</link>
    <description>Curated links for devs</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>OpenSCAD Is Kinda Neat – nuxx.net</title>
      <link>https://nuxx.net/blog/2025/12/20/openscad-is-kinda-neat/</link>
      <description>Earlier this year I designed a very basic box/organizer for AA and AAA batteries in Autodesk Fusion, making it parameterized so that by changing a few variables one could adjust the battery type/size, rows/columns, etc. This worked well, and after uploading it to Printables earlier today I realized that reimplementing it would probably be a good way to learn the basics of OpenSCAD.</description>
      <guid>https://nuxx.net/blog/2025/12/20/openscad-is-kinda-neat/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 12:02:02 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Flock and Cyble Inc. Weaponize "Cybercrime" Takedowns to Silence Critics</title>
      <link>https://haveibeenflocked.com/news/cyble-downtime</link>
      <description>When a government contractor pays a company for "Takedown Services" to prevent transparency in government</description>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <guid>https://haveibeenflocked.com/news/cyble-downtime</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 06:02:18 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jmail, logged in as jeevacation@gmail.com</title>
      <link>https://www.jmail.world/</link>
      <description>You are logged into jeevacation@gmail.com, Jeffrey Epstein's email. Sourced from the November 2025 House Oversight Committee data release.</description>
      <guid>https://www.jmail.world/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 02:02:04 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2025-66019: LZW Decompression DoS Vulnerability in pypdf Library | Yunus Aydın Blog</title>
      <link>https://aydinnyunus.github.io/2025/12/20/cve-2025-66019-pypdf-lzw-dos/</link>
      <description>DoS vulnerability I found in pypdf library's LZW decompression. How the LZW algorithm works, why it leads to this vulnerability, and how it differs from ZLIB.</description>
      <category>vscode</category>
      <category>cloud</category>
      <guid>https://aydinnyunus.github.io/2025/12/20/cve-2025-66019-pypdf-lzw-dos/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 01:01:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>pg-trgm and Text Similarity Search — Common Sense Development</title>
      <link>https://blog.kehvyn.dev/blog/pg-trgm-and-text-similarity-search/</link>
      <description>When browsing the default Postgres extensions (a perfectly normal activity), I discovered pg_trgm. After a bit more reading, I'm convinced this simple database extension should be an essential part of any database engineer's toolkit.</description>
      <category>sql</category>
      <guid>https://blog.kehvyn.dev/blog/pg-trgm-and-text-similarity-search/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 01:01:46 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When You Increase Kafka Partitions</title>
      <link>https://arpitbhayani.me/blogs/kafka-partitions/</link>
      <description>Partitions sit right in the middle of how Kafka works. They define ordering, parallelism, and how far it can scale. But what actually happens when you need more of them? How does Kafka grow that number, what happens to the data you already have, and which guarantees stay intact after the change?</description>
      <category>nodejs</category>
      <guid>https://arpitbhayani.me/blogs/kafka-partitions/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 01:01:42 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I’m not letting the juniors use GenAI for coding</title>
      <link>https://lukeplant.me.uk/blog/posts/why-im-not-letting-the-juniors-use-genai-for-coding/</link>
      <description>TLDR: because I want them to become seniors one day, and I want them to enjoy being developers</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>sql</category>
      <guid>https://lukeplant.me.uk/blog/posts/why-im-not-letting-the-juniors-use-genai-for-coding/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 01:01:37 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pure Silicon Demo Coding: No CPU, No Memory, Just 4k Gates</title>
      <link>https://www.a1k0n.net/2025/12/19/tiny-tapeout-demo.html</link>
      <description>Dec 19, 2025</description>
      <category>python</category>
      <guid>https://www.a1k0n.net/2025/12/19/tiny-tapeout-demo.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 00:02:05 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Backing up Spotify</title>
      <link>https://annas-archive.li/blog/backing-up-spotify.html</link>
      <description>We backed up Spotify (metadata and music files). It’s distributed in bulk torrents (~300TB). It’s the world’s first “preservation archive” for music which is fully open (meaning it can easily be mirrored by anyone with enough disk space), with 86 million music files, representing around 99.6% of listens.</description>
      <category>sql</category>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <category>encryption</category>
      <guid>https://annas-archive.li/blog/backing-up-spotify.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 23:02:08 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Go ahead, self-host Postgres | Pierce Freeman</title>
      <link>https://pierce.dev/notes/go-ahead-self-host-postgres#user-content-fn-1</link>
      <description>Self-hosting Postgres is simpler and cheaper than managed services suggest, with comparable reliability and better performance tunability.</description>
      <category>conference</category>
      <category>cloud</category>
      <category>containers</category>
      <category>sql</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <guid>https://pierce.dev/notes/go-ahead-self-host-postgres#user-content-fn-1</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 20:02:08 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Charles Web Debugging Proxy • HTTP Monitor / HTTP Proxy / HTTPS &amp; SSL Proxy</title>
      <link>https://www.charlesproxy.com/</link>
      <description>Charles Web Debugging Proxy - Official Site</description>
      <guid>https://www.charlesproxy.com/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 19:02:06 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Privacy is Marketing. Anonymity is Architecture.</title>
      <link>https://servury.com/blog/privacy-is-marketing-anonymity-is-architecture/</link>
      <description>Privacy is when they promise to protect your data. Anonymity is when they never had your data to begin with.</description>
      <author> (Matteo M.)</author>
      <guid>https://servury.com/blog/privacy-is-marketing-anonymity-is-architecture/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 18:02:13 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NTP at NIST Boulder has lost power - NANOG</title>
      <link>https://lists.nanog.org/archives/list/nanog@lists.nanog.org/message/ACADD3NKOG2QRWZ56OSNNG7UIEKKTZXL/</link>
      <description>reposting from the Internet time service list


jeff.s...@nist.gov &lt;jeff.sherman@nist.gov&gt;: Dec 19 05:18PM -0800

Dear colleagues,

In short, the atomic ensemble time scale at our Boulder campus has failed
due to a prolonged utility power outage. One impact is that the Boulder
Internet Time Services no longer have an accurate time reference. At time
of writing the Boulder servers are still available due a standby power
generator, but I will attempt to disable them to avoid disseminating
incorrect time.

The affected servers are:
time-a-b.nist.gov
time-b-b.nist.gov
time-c-b.nist.gov
time-d-b.nist.gov
time-e-b.nist.gov
ntp-b.nist.gov (authenticated NTP)

No time to repair estimate is available until we regain staff access and
power. Efforts are currently focused on obtaining an alternate source of
power so the hydrogen maser clocks survive beyond their battery backups.

More details follow.

Due to prolonged high wind gusts there have been a combination of utility
power line damage and preemptive utility shutdowns (in the interest of
wildfire prevention) in the Boulder, CO area. NIST's campus lost utility
power Wednesday (Dec. 17 2025) around 22:23 UTC. At time of writing utility
power is still off to the campus. Facility operators anticipated needing to
shutdown the heat-exchange infrastructure providing air cooling to many
parts of the building, including some internal networking closets. As a
result, many of these too were preemptively shutdown with the result that
our group lacks much of the monitoring and control capabilities we
ordinarily have. Also, the site has been closed to all but emergency
personnel Thursday and Friday, and at time of writing remains closed.

At initial power loss, there was no immediate impact to the NIST atomic
time scale or distribution services because the projects are afforded
standby power generators. However, we now have strong evidence one of the
crucial generators has failed. In the downstream path is the primary signal
distribution chain, including to the Boulder Internet Time Service. Another
campus building houses additional clocks backed up by a different power
generator; if these survive it will allow us to re-align the primary time
scale when site stability returns without making use of external clocks or
reference signals.

Best wishes,
-Jeff Sherman
project email: internet-time-service@nist.gov

AnneJ (watching from Edinburgh, UK)</description>
      <guid>https://lists.nanog.org/archives/list/nanog@lists.nanog.org/message/ACADD3NKOG2QRWZ56OSNNG7UIEKKTZXL/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 16:02:05 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Airbus to migrate critical apps to a sovereign Euro cloud</title>
      <link>https://www.theregister.com/2025/12/19/airbus_sovereign_cloud/</link>
      <description>Exclusive: Tech exec admits not dead cert it'll find the right solution</description>
      <category>cloud</category>
      <guid>https://www.theregister.com/2025/12/19/airbus_sovereign_cloud/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 14:02:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>