<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-16"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://linksfor.dev/feed.xml" />
    <title>linksfor.dev(s)</title>
    <link>https://linksfor.dev/feed.xml</link>
    <description>Curated links for devs</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>Khronos at 25: Shaping Visual Computing with Open Standards</title>
      <link>https://www.khronos.org/blog/the-khronos-group-celebrates-25-years-shaping-the-future-through-open-standards</link>
      <description>In 2025, Khronos reached an impressive milestone: 25 years of member-driven open standards development. The graphics, compute, and media landscape looked wildly different in 2000, when Khronos was formed, than it does today.  Era-defining technologies such as smartphones, cloud computing, and the metaverse hadn’t yet emerged into the marketplace. The founders of Khronos were on the forefront of these emerging technologies. They knew that withou</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <category>apple</category>
      <category>android</category>
      <guid>https://www.khronos.org/blog/the-khronos-group-celebrates-25-years-shaping-the-future-through-open-standards</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 15:02:18 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitHub - TrevorS/voxtral-mini-realtime-rs</title>
      <link>https://github.com/TrevorS/voxtral-mini-realtime-rs</link>
      <description>Contribute to TrevorS/voxtral-mini-realtime-rs development by creating an account on GitHub.</description>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <category>rust</category>
      <category>web</category>
      <guid>https://github.com/TrevorS/voxtral-mini-realtime-rs</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 12:02:09 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Benchmark for Evaluating Outcome-Driven Constraint Violations in Autonomous AI Agents</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20798</link>
      <description>As autonomous AI agents are increasingly deployed in high-stakes environments, ensuring their safety and alignment with human values has become a paramount concern. Current safety benchmarks primarily evaluate whether agents refuse explicitly harmful instructions or whether they can maintain procedural compliance in complex tasks. However, there is a lack of benchmarks designed to capture emergent forms of outcome-driven constraint violations, which arise when agents pursue goal optimization under strong performance incentives while deprioritizing ethical, legal, or safety constraints over multiple steps in realistic production settings. To address this gap, we introduce a new benchmark comprising 40 distinct scenarios. Each scenario presents a task that requires multi-step actions, and the agent's performance is tied to a specific Key Performance Indicator (KPI). Each scenario features Mandated (instruction-commanded) and Incentivized (KPI-pressure-driven) variations to distinguish between obedience and emergent misalignment. Across 12 state-of-the-art large language models, we observe outcome-driven constraint violations ranging from 1.3% to 71.4%, with 9 of the 12 evaluated models exhibiting misalignment rates between 30% and 50%. Strikingly, we find that superior reasoning capability does not inherently ensure safety; for instance, Gemini-3-Pro-Preview, one of the most capable models evaluated, exhibits the highest violation rate at 71.4%, frequently escalating to severe misconduct to satisfy KPIs. Furthermore, we observe significant "deliberative misalignment", where the models that power the agents recognize their actions as unethical during separate evaluation. These results emphasize the critical need for more realistic agentic-safety training before deployment to mitigate their risks in the real world.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>web</category>
      <guid>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20798</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 10:02:12 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FOSDEM 2026 - Fluorite - console-grade game engine in Flutter</title>
      <link>https://fosdem.org/2026/schedule/event/7ZJJWW-fluorite-game-engine-flutter/</link>
      <description>Toyota Connected North America (TCNA) introduces Fluorite, its open-source 3D game engine built in Flutter.</description>
      <category>cloud</category>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <guid>https://fosdem.org/2026/schedule/event/7ZJJWW-fluorite-game-engine-flutter/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 09:02:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon Dating</title>
      <link>https://xkcd.com/3205/</link>
      <description></description>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <guid>https://xkcd.com/3205/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 05:02:35 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Incident with Issues, Actions and Git Operations</title>
      <link>https://www.githubstatus.com/incidents/lcw3tg2f6zsd</link>
      <description>GitHub's Status Page - Incident with Issues, Actions and Git Operations.</description>
      <category>git</category>
      <guid>https://www.githubstatus.com/incidents/lcw3tg2f6zsd</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 02:02:14 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitHub - joshuanwalker/Raiders2600: Reverse Engineering Raiders of the Lost Ark for the Atari 2600</title>
      <link>https://github.com/joshuanwalker/Raiders2600/</link>
      <description>Reverse Engineering Raiders of the Lost Ark for the Atari 2600 - joshuanwalker/Raiders2600</description>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>vscode</category>
      <guid>https://github.com/joshuanwalker/Raiders2600/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 01:01:34 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The journey was the point</title>
      <link>https://mahdiyusuf.com/the-journey-was-the-point/</link>
      <description>America outsourced manufacturing, then the skills to design what gets manufactured. Software is next.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://mahdiyusuf.com/the-journey-was-the-point/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 00:03:36 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why We Discourage Sleep in Code</title>
      <link>https://www.jakeworth.com/posts/why-we-discourage-sleep/</link>
      <description>You might have heard that using blocking, waiting code, e.g., sleep in many languages, is discouraged. Why?</description>
      <category>ruby</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <guid>https://www.jakeworth.com/posts/why-we-discourage-sleep/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 00:03:32 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Webspace Invaders · Matthias Ott</title>
      <link>https://matthiasott.com/articles/webspace-invaders</link>
      <description>There’s something happening on the Web at the moment that almost feels like watching that old arcade game Space Invaders play out across our servers. Bots and scrapers marching in formation, attacking our servers wave after wave, systematically requesting page after page, relentlessly filling their data stores while we watch our access logs fill up.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <category>web</category>
      <guid>https://matthiasott.com/articles/webspace-invaders</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 00:03:29 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Second Brain Never Worked. Then I Gave It a Gardener. - Rob Dodson</title>
      <link>https://robdodson.me/posts/i-gave-my-second-brain-a-gardener/</link>
      <description>I could never maintain a second brain. Then I pointed Claude Code at my Obsidian vault and let it do the organizing for me. Now I'm writing again.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://robdodson.me/posts/i-gave-my-second-brain-a-gardener/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 00:03:22 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Buying the Kinesis Advantage 360 keyboard was a mistake | Angelika.me</title>
      <link>https://angelika.me/2025/12/04/buying-kinesis-advantage-was-a-mistake/</link>
      <description>Why this beast of a keyboard did not work for me and what I ended up using instead.</description>
      <category>apple</category>
      <guid>https://angelika.me/2025/12/04/buying-kinesis-advantage-was-a-mistake/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 00:03:19 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Letting Gemini Drive My Rover</title>
      <link>http://martin.drashkov.com/2026/02/letting-gemini-drive-my-rover.html</link>
      <description>  Letting Gemini Drive My Rover LLMs have had visual capabilities for a while now, with the general ability to understand what they’re looki...</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <category>web</category>
      <guid>http://martin.drashkov.com/2026/02/letting-gemini-drive-my-rover.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 00:03:11 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>M1 MacBook Pro as a k3s Node with Asahi Linux - Graham Stevens – Grh.am</title>
      <link>https://grh.am/2026/m1-macbook-pro-as-a-k3s-node-with-asahi-linux/</link>
      <description>Background At home, I run a small 4 node k3s cluster on Dell Wyse 5070, primarily for the experience but also just for the fun of it. It houses all sorts of containers, but happily handles almost everything I throw at it, including Home Assistant, an MQTT instance, Predbat, Smokeping etc. etc.
This little stack of 4 Dell thin clients sits on the corner of my desk, each being powered via a single USB power supply - this means it only takes up a single power socket under the desk for neatness. Each node is also connected to a single Ubiquiti 5 port POE switch (USW-Flex), which again means no plug sockets being used up under the desk (but of course requires a POE switch to power it elsewhere…). Lovely and neat! Each node has two 8GB sticks of RAM, and I’ve replaced the M.2 WiFi cards with M.2 to NVME adapters to all me to expand the local storage.
</description>
      <category>nodejs</category>
      <category>linux</category>
      <category>apple</category>
      <guid>https://grh.am/2026/m1-macbook-pro-as-a-k3s-node-with-asahi-linux/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 00:03:07 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stop Telling Users Their DNS Is Wrong</title>
      <link>https://jacob.gold/posts/stop-telling-users-their-dns-is-wrong/</link>
      <description>You add a DNS record. The app says it’s wrong. You check it, fix a typo, try again. Still wrong. You wait. You try again. Still wrong. You triple check it. It looks correct.
The app is checking DNS records in a half-assed way.
If you’re building a product that asks users to add DNS records, please take the time to verify DNS records properly.</description>
      <guid>https://jacob.gold/posts/stop-telling-users-their-dns-is-wrong/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 00:03:04 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agent Systems Fail Quietly: Why Orchestration Matters More Than Intelligence</title>
      <link>https://bnjam.dev/posts/agent-orchestration/agent-systems-fail-quietly.html</link>
      <description>Most agent systems don’t fail because models are weak — they fail because coordination is underspecified, and the failures are silent.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://bnjam.dev/posts/agent-orchestration/agent-systems-fail-quietly.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 00:03:01 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building at the Speed of Thought | zach wills</title>
      <link>https://zachwills.net/building-at-the-speed-of-thought/</link>
      <description>I woke up to 77 pull requests. None of them were from a human. The night before — a Sunday — I had connected the...</description>
      <category>encryption</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <guid>https://zachwills.net/building-at-the-speed-of-thought/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 00:02:58 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Samrian | Manufacturing QMS Software</title>
      <link>https://www.samrian.com/blog/cost-of-truth</link>
      <description>Stop chasing paper. Automate your ISO 9001 compliance with the QMS built for the shop floor.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://www.samrian.com/blog/cost-of-truth</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 00:02:54 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Talk to Claude More Than Humans (And What That Taught Me)</title>
      <link>https://paraz.in/posts/i-talk-to-claude-more-than-humans</link>
      <description>Three weeks running Claude 24/7 taught me how to make coding agents actually work: verification loops, team standards, and the right tooling setup.</description>
      <category>vscode</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://paraz.in/posts/i-talk-to-claude-more-than-humans</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 00:02:51 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Culmination and Not Yet Turning Thirty | Brian Kitano</title>
      <link>https://briankitano.com/essays/on-culmination/</link>
      <description>the ouroboros is savoring itself, or "you met me in a very Carrie Bradshaw time of my life"</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://briankitano.com/essays/on-culmination/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 00:02:48 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I used Claude Code in a real data journalism project</title>
      <link>https://kschaul.com/post/2026/02/09/2026-02-09-ai-data-journalism/</link>
      <description>This morning three colleagues and I published a story outlining how the federal government is using AI. Here’s how I used Claude Code to help.
Agencies are required to publish a spreadsheet of AI use cases. Unfortunately (and unsurprisingly) each agency posts them in a different place on their website, in a different file format, using different column names and values. OMB will eventually consolidate these, but why wait when we can do it ourselves?</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>python</category>
      <guid>https://kschaul.com/post/2026/02/09/2026-02-09-ai-data-journalism/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 00:02:45 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Half Your Skills Expire Every Few Years</title>
      <link>https://arpitbhayani.me/blogs/half-life/</link>
      <description>That is the half-life of knowledge in computer science and software engineering - the time it takes for half of what you know to be replaced by better tools, approaches, or understanding. For an engineering degree earned in 1930, the half-life was roughly 35 years. By 1960, it had dropped to about a decade.</description>
      <category>containers</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>vscode</category>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <category>sql</category>
      <guid>https://arpitbhayani.me/blogs/half-life/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 00:02:41 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards Perfect Vulnerability Management System - Work &amp; Life Notes</title>
      <link>https://worklifenotes.com/2026/02/09/towards-perfect-vulnerability-management-system/</link>
      <description>Here I would like to summarize my thoughts on what constitutes a perfect vulnerability management system, what frequently gets missed, and what elements we</description>
      <guid>https://worklifenotes.com/2026/02/09/towards-perfect-vulnerability-management-system/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 00:02:37 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Edited This Video 100% With Codex ft. SAM3 + MatAnyone + Remotion</title>
      <link>https://www.adithyan.io/blog/codex-text-effects-toolchain</link>
      <description>A practical workflow: record first, transcribe with word timings, generate a subject alpha, then compose everything in Remotion. No timeline editor.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <category>apple</category>
      <guid>https://www.adithyan.io/blog/codex-text-effects-toolchain</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 00:02:31 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Testing software in the era of coding agents</title>
      <link>https://www.garymm.org/blog/2026/02/06/testing-software-coding-agents/</link>
      <description>What parts of my software should be tested? And how? And how do coding agents (e.g. Claude Code) change things? This is my attempt to succinctly explain how I think about these questions at the beginning of 2026 (software development is changing so quickly I feel compelled to note the date. This may all be obsolete soon).</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://www.garymm.org/blog/2026/02/06/testing-software-coding-agents/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 00:02:26 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Domain Knowledge Is the New Syntax</title>
      <link>https://blog.melashri.net/posts/specs-focus/</link>
      <description>A collection of notes about physics, programming and personal thoughts.</description>
      <category>encryption</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <guid>https://blog.melashri.net/posts/specs-focus/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 00:02:22 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Canvas Breaks Your Screen Recorder (And What to Do Instead) — SendRec</title>
      <link>https://sendrec.eu/blog/why-canvas-breaks-your-screen-recorder/</link>
      <description>Most screen recorders composite webcam overlays using canvas. Here's why that fails in background tabs and how we solved it with server-side ffmpeg.</description>
      <category>nodejs</category>
      <guid>https://sendrec.eu/blog/why-canvas-breaks-your-screen-recorder/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 00:02:18 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Wrote a Scheme in 2025</title>
      <link>https://maplant.com/2026-02-09-I-Wrote-a-Scheme-in-2025.html</link>
      <description>One year minus one week ago to the day I published an article
announcing the new Scheme implementation I was writing, scheme-rs.
Today I am excited to announce that scheme-rs has reached its first version,
0.1.0. You can check it out at it’s website (scheme-rs.org, which should be
updated to scheme.rs at some point when DNS propagation finishes) or its
github page.</description>
      <category>rust</category>
      <category>web</category>
      <guid>https://maplant.com/2026-02-09-I-Wrote-a-Scheme-in-2025.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 00:02:14 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What LEGO Can Teach Us about Autonomy and Engagement - Pawel Brodzinski on Leadership in Technology</title>
      <link>https://brodzinski.com/2026/01/lego-autonomy-engagement.html</link>
      <description>A simple experiment with building LEGO models in groups demonstrates how important autonomy is for high engagement at work.</description>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <guid>https://brodzinski.com/2026/01/lego-autonomy-engagement.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 00:02:09 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why use Conventional Commits? - byandrev</title>
      <link>https://byandrev.dev/en/blog/conventional-commits</link>
      <description>Opening a project's Git history and finding messages like “various fixes,” “update,” or “fixed something” can be a nightmare. That chaos makes it impossible for anyone to understand what actually happened in the code. This is where Conventional Commits come in.</description>
      <category>git</category>
      <guid>https://byandrev.dev/en/blog/conventional-commits</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 00:02:05 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Potential of RLMs</title>
      <link>https://www.dbreunig.com/2026/02/09/the-potential-of-rlms.html</link>
      <description>Handling Your Long Context Today &amp; Designing Your Agent Tomorrow</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>python</category>
      <guid>https://www.dbreunig.com/2026/02/09/the-potential-of-rlms.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 00:02:02 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From prototype to production: A low-latency multiplayer stack</title>
      <link>https://dcastares.github.io/2025/12/15/Multi-region-highly-available-architecture-for-indie-budget.html</link>
      <description>When you start working on a real-time multiplayer game, the idea might seem simple, but it can escalate quickly. That happened when we started giving form to Rumble Racer with the Blyts team.</description>
      <category>containers</category>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <category>linux</category>
      <category>web</category>
      <guid>https://dcastares.github.io/2025/12/15/Multi-region-highly-available-architecture-for-indie-budget.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 00:01:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using Claude Code as a general agent — Raahel Baig</title>
      <link>https://www.raahelbaig.com/entry/claude-code-as-a-general-agent/</link>
      <description>Raahel Baig's personal blog — entries, links, quotes, and notes.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>python</category>
      <guid>https://www.raahelbaig.com/entry/claude-code-as-a-general-agent/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 00:01:55 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why is the sky blue?</title>
      <link>https://explainers.blog/posts/why-is-the-sky-blue/</link>
      <description>Let’s start by asking ourselves: what color SHOULD the sky be?</description>
      <guid>https://explainers.blog/posts/why-is-the-sky-blue/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 21:02:17 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitHub - jim11662418/ESP8266_WiFi_Analog_Clock: Uses an ESP8266 module and an Arduino sketch to display the local time on a inexpensive analog quartz clock.</title>
      <link>https://github.com/jim11662418/ESP8266_WiFi_Analog_Clock</link>
      <description>Uses an ESP8266 module and an Arduino sketch to display the local time on a inexpensive analog quartz clock. - jim11662418/ESP8266_WiFi_Analog_Clock</description>
      <category>web</category>
      <guid>https://github.com/jim11662418/ESP8266_WiFi_Analog_Clock</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 21:02:12 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Notifications are delayed</title>
      <link>https://www.githubstatus.com/incidents/54hndjxft5bx</link>
      <description>GitHub's Status Page - Notifications are delayed.</description>
      <guid>https://www.githubstatus.com/incidents/54hndjxft5bx</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 19:02:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Game Boy Snake: A Complete Implementation in Assembly</title>
      <link>https://www.4rknova.com//blog/2026/02/08/gb-snake</link>
      <description>A detailed walkthrough of a classic Snake game for the Nintendo Game Boy, written entirely in RGBDS assembly. Covers the game loop, state machine, snake ring buffer, occupancy grid collision detect...</description>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://www.4rknova.com//blog/2026/02/08/gb-snake</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 17:02:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>All The Views</title>
      <link>https://alltheviews.world/</link>
      <description>With the help of a custom-developed algorithm, CacheTVS, we have exhaustively
checked every single view on Earth in search of the coveted longest line of sight on the planet.
Based on the method we detail here, we present the greatest view of all:</description>
      <guid>https://alltheviews.world/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 17:02:06 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>