<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-16"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://linksfor.dev/feed.xml" />
    <title>linksfor.dev(s)</title>
    <link>https://linksfor.dev/feed.xml</link>
    <description>Curated links for devs</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>GitHub - rolflobker/recall-for-linux: Bring Microsoft Recall to Linux!</title>
      <link>https://github.com/rolflobker/recall-for-linux</link>
      <description>Bring Microsoft Recall to Linux! Contribute to rolflobker/recall-for-linux development by creating an account on GitHub.</description>
      <category>encryption</category>
      <category>linux</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>sql</category>
      <guid>https://github.com/rolflobker/recall-for-linux</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 14:02:21 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#29: Poison, Poison Everywhere</title>
      <link>https://loeber.substack.com/p/29-poison-poison-everywhere</link>
      <description>When I was in high school, my teacher once told us a crazy story.</description>
      <guid>https://loeber.substack.com/p/29-poison-poison-everywhere</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 12:02:03 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI Doom Predictions Are Overhyped | Why Programmers Aren’t Going Anywhere - Uncle Bob's take</title>
      <link>https://youtu.be/pAj3zRfAvfc</link>
      <description>#AI #Programming #TechCareers #ArtificialIntelligence #ChatGPT #AIHype #SoftwareDevelopment #GraceHopper #AITools #TechMyths #unclebob 

Are AI doomsayers right that programmers will soon be obsolete? Or is this just clickbait fear-mongering? In this video, we break down:
Why early programmers panicked when Grace Hopper introduced compilers
How AI tools like ChatGPT compare to human intelligence
The repeating cycles of hype and disappointment in AI history
Why software development is far from fully automatable
The risks of pivoting careers based on AI “doom predictions”
AI is a tool, not a replacement—for now. Understand the trends, separate hype from reality, and make informed career decisions.


Sources:
https://youtu.be/HD0L3lQ9cms?si=4skwzUgqKYMHC9Op</description>
      <author> (Dev Tools Made Simple)</author>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://youtu.be/pAj3zRfAvfc</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 06:01:51 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LLMs Are Bottlenecked by Linear Interfaces</title>
      <link>https://handmadeoasis.com/llms-are-bottlenecked-by-linear-interfaces/</link>
      <description>Current limitation as I see it So I have been experimenting quite a bit with LLMs recently (see my other posts, especially /state-of-ai-assisted-workflows-october-2025/) and dedicated some serious amount of effort to play around with the tech to both learn more but also to build an intuition for what it is and what it can do well etc. This has led me to having a realisation or an idea, that I’m sure is not unique but I have not seen much about it being mentioned yet.</description>
      <category>nodejs</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://handmadeoasis.com/llms-are-bottlenecked-by-linear-interfaces/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 00:03:41 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Knowledge is Worth Your Time</title>
      <link>https://chanda.bearblog.dev/knowledge-is-worth-your-time/</link>
      <description>Folks who hang out on Bluesky/Twitter may have caught bits and pieces of the discussions amongst academics about what to do about today's university students...</description>
      <guid>https://chanda.bearblog.dev/knowledge-is-worth-your-time/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 00:03:37 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How bugs made me believe in TDD</title>
      <link>https://patrickm.de/why-tdd/</link>
      <description>I always knew that testing was important, but I neglected it for a long time. During my studies, the subject was unfortunately given far too little attention and there was also a lack of practical relevance. However, as I gained more professional experience, I learned that I always have to</description>
      <guid>https://patrickm.de/why-tdd/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 00:03:34 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>questionable | Isaac Bowen</title>
      <link>https://www.isaacbowen.com/2025/10/25/questionable</link>
      <description>2 + 2 = 4</description>
      <guid>https://www.isaacbowen.com/2025/10/25/questionable</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 00:03:29 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Better Boards</title>
      <link>https://www.dylancollins.com/p/building-better-boards</link>
      <description>How is your BBB rating?</description>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <guid>https://www.dylancollins.com/p/building-better-boards</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 00:03:24 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unit Tests for Intelligence</title>
      <link>https://blog.anirudha.dev/ai-evals</link>
      <description>Structured tests for model reasoning</description>
      <author> (https://hashnode.com/@anirudha)</author>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>rust</category>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <category>python</category>
      <guid>https://blog.anirudha.dev/ai-evals</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 00:03:20 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Praise of Amateurism</title>
      <link>https://blog.jakobschwichtenberg.com/p/in-praise-of-amateurism</link>
      <description>I. One of my icks is reading anything that was clearly only written because the author felt like they had to write, not because they actually felt the urgent need to share something.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <guid>https://blog.jakobschwichtenberg.com/p/in-praise-of-amateurism</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 00:03:16 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>After a Year Rebuilding Search, I Had to Rethink Everything | Sebastian Sigl</title>
      <link>https://www.sebastiansigl.com/blog/rebuilding-search-lessons-learned/</link>
      <description>A seasoned engineer's lessons from a year rebuilding a search system from the ground up, shifting from engineering-first to product-first thinking.</description>
      <guid>https://www.sebastiansigl.com/blog/rebuilding-search-lessons-learned/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 00:03:12 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I turned Zig into my favorite language to write network programs in</title>
      <link>https://lalinsky.com/2025/10/26/zio-async-io-for-zig.html</link>
      <description>I’ve been watching the Zig language for a while now, given that it was created for writing audio software (low-level, no allocations, real time). I never paid too much attention though, it seemed a little weird to me and I didn’t see the real need. Then I saw a post from Andrew Kelley (creator of the language) on Hacker News, about how he reimplemented my Chromaprint algorithm in Zig, and that got me really interested.</description>
      <category>rust</category>
      <guid>https://lalinsky.com/2025/10/26/zio-async-io-for-zig.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 00:03:08 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The difficulties of choosing a startup idea</title>
      <link>https://dennisy.me/notes/the-difficulties-of-choosing-a-startup-idea</link>
      <description>Note: this piece has no solution (yet).</description>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://dennisy.me/notes/the-difficulties-of-choosing-a-startup-idea</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 00:03:05 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kris De Asis | Design for Learning</title>
      <link>https://kris.pengy.ca/designforlearning</link>
      <description>A position arguing that robots can and should be designed for learning.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://kris.pengy.ca/designforlearning</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 00:03:02 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ossa: Towards the Next Generation Web</title>
      <link>https://jamesparker.me/blog/post/2025/08/04/ossa-towards-the-next-generation-web</link>
      <description>The internet is one of the most impactful technologies of today, enabling billions of people to communicate with family members around the globe, to share photos with one another, and to collaboratively edit documents in real time.
Most of these systems are built on cloud architectures where centralized servers store user information and synchronize that data across user devices.
The image below illustrates how this architecture typically works.
When a user makes an edit on their laptop, the update is sent to a trusted third party server which synchronizes the data and forwards it to another user's cell phone.</description>
      <category>encryption</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <guid>https://jamesparker.me/blog/post/2025/08/04/ossa-towards-the-next-generation-web</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 00:02:58 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are transformers all we need?</title>
      <link>https://merqur.io/2025/10/26/Are-transformers-all-we-need/</link>
      <description>I vividly remember November 10th, 2017, the day I first read the “Attention is
All You Need” paper. I was in the Paris CDG airport. It struck me how similar
the architecture was to the autoencoders I had learned about just a few months
earlier at the DeepLearn 2017 in Bilbao. The attention mechanism (which I later
learned originated from Dzmitry Bahdanau’s 2014 work) seemed like a remarkably
elegant solution. It captivated me, sparking my deep dive into AI and shaping my
career in applying these models to real-world problems, but I never imagined it
would become the phenomenon it is today.</description>
      <category>cloud</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://merqur.io/2025/10/26/Are-transformers-all-we-need/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 00:02:22 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Language Modeling with Hierarchical Reasoning Models: Lessons from 1M Parameters</title>
      <link>https://williamthurston.com/ml/language-models/transformers/2025/10/25/language-modeling-with-hierarchical-reasoning-models.html</link>
      <description>The Hierarchical Reasoning Models (HRM) paper made waves by demonstrating strong performance on ARC-AGI reasoning tasks with very few parameters, and the Tiny Recursive Models (TRM) paper pushed it further, setting higher benchmarks with just 7M parameters. The architecture uses hierarchical reasoning through recursion of transformer layers—effectively running the same parameters through multiple forward passes to reach impressive small model performance.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://williamthurston.com/ml/language-models/transformers/2025/10/25/language-modeling-with-hierarchical-reasoning-models.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 00:02:18 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We are all becoming managers – Juan Michelini</title>
      <link>https://juan.com.uy/we-are-all-becoming-managers/</link>
      <description>AI agents are so good that some days I don’t code anymore: instead, I manage agents. Given a feature, I discuss the requirements with the agent, discuss possible solutions, decide on a design and ask the agent for an implementation.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <guid>https://juan.com.uy/we-are-all-becoming-managers/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 00:02:15 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How the Earth Invented Sleep</title>
      <link>https://www.derekthompson.org/p/how-the-earth-invented-sleep</link>
      <description>The Sunday Morning Post: The scientific connection between billion-year-old volcanos, oxygen, and your dreams</description>
      <guid>https://www.derekthompson.org/p/how-the-earth-invented-sleep</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 00:02:11 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About - Advent of Code 2025</title>
      <link>https://adventofcode.com/2025/about#faq_num_days</link>
      <description>Hi!  I'm Eric Wastl. I make Advent of Code.  I hope you like it!  I also make lots of other things.  I'm on Bluesky, Mastodon, and GitHub.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <guid>https://adventofcode.com/2025/about#faq_num_days</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 19:01:58 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Let's Help NetBSD Cross the Finish Line Before 2025 Ends</title>
      <link>https://mail-index.netbsd.org/netbsd-users/2025/10/26/msg033327.html</link>
      <description>As 2025 draws to a close, I are reaching out to community with a request for helping The NetBSD Foundation.</description>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <category>web</category>
      <guid>https://mail-index.netbsd.org/netbsd-users/2025/10/26/msg033327.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 18:02:03 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You already have a git server: (Maurycy's blog)</title>
      <link>https://maurycyz.com/misc/easy_git/</link>
      <description>If you have a git repository on a server with ssh access, you can just clone it:</description>
      <category>git</category>
      <guid>https://maurycyz.com/misc/easy_git/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 18:01:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>That Time Ken Thompson Wrote a Backdoor into the C Compiler</title>
      <link>https://micahkepe.com/blog/thompson-trojan-horse/</link>
      <description>When Ken Thompson won the Turing Award jointly with Dennis Ritchie for their
work in UNIX, he was expected like other Turing winners to write a paper that
would be published in the ACM Computer Journal. What he ended up submitting was
a paper about "the cutest program [he] ever wrote"-- a sneaky undetectable
self-reproducing "Trojan horse" backdoor in the C compiler that would allow him
to log into affected machines as any user.</description>
      <category>python</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://micahkepe.com/blog/thompson-trojan-horse/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 17:01:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Journey Before main() | Amit's Blog</title>
      <link>https://amit.prasad.me/blog/before-main</link>
      <description>A while back, I worked on a RISC-V-based userspace simulator for fun. In doing so, taught myself a lot more than I wanted to know about what happens in-between when the Kernel is asked to run a program, and when the first line of our program’s main function is actually executed. Here’s a summary of that rabbit hole.</description>
      <category>rust</category>
      <category>python</category>
      <category>linux</category>
      <category>vscode</category>
      <guid>https://amit.prasad.me/blog/before-main</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 15:02:11 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>