<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-16"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://linksfor.dev/feed.xml" />
    <title>linksfor.dev(s)</title>
    <link>https://linksfor.dev/feed.xml</link>
    <description>Curated links for devs</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>Prompt Injection Inside GitHub Actions: The New Frontier of Supply Chain Attacks</title>
      <link>https://www.aikido.dev/blog/promptpwnd-github-actions-ai-agents</link>
      <description>AI-driven GitHub Actions expose new prompt-injection supply chain vulnerabilities.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <guid>https://www.aikido.dev/blog/promptpwnd-github-actions-ai-agents</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 20:02:20 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transparent Leadership Beats Servant Leadership</title>
      <link>https://entropicthoughts.com/transparent-leadership-beats-servant-leadership</link>
      <description>tl:dr: Parenting and leadership is similar. Teach a man to fish, etc.</description>
      <guid>https://entropicthoughts.com/transparent-leadership-beats-servant-leadership</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 20:02:14 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wolfenstein 3D's map renderer</title>
      <link>https://youtube.com/watch?v=eOCQfxRQ2pY</link>
      <description>Wolfenstein 3D was a triumph of early 90s engineering. It was an action packed 3d first person shooter - arguably the first - and it ran well on a 12 MHz 286 PC.

How on earth was such a feat pulled off? Find out by watching this in-depth analysis of how the map renderer worked.

Apologies for the small size of the graphics: this was an early video of mine and my later presentations look better!

The Wolfenstein 3D source is available at: https://github.com/id-Software/wolf3d

Source for this presentation: : https://github.com/mattgodbolt/wolf-doom-quake</description>
      <author> (Matt Godbolt)</author>
      <category>youtube</category>
      <guid>https://youtube.com/watch?v=eOCQfxRQ2pY</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 20:02:08 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stacktower: An Accidental Deep Dive</title>
      <link>https://stacktower.io/</link>
      <description>How an XKCD comic led to teaching myself graph theory — a journey through NP-hard problems, PQ-trees, and layered graph algorithms.</description>
      <category>nodejs</category>
      <category>python</category>
      <category>rust</category>
      <guid>https://stacktower.io/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 19:11:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RAM is so expensive, Samsung won't even sell it to Samsung</title>
      <link>https://www.pcworld.com/article/2998935/ram-is-so-expensive-samsung-wont-even-sell-it-to-samsung.html</link>
      <description>Due to rising prices from the "AI" bubble, Samsung Semiconductor reportedly refused a RAM order for new Galaxy phones from Samsung Electronics.</description>
      <category>android</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>web</category>
      <guid>https://www.pcworld.com/article/2998935/ram-is-so-expensive-samsung-wont-even-sell-it-to-samsung.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 19:11:06 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I Ignore The Spotlight as a Staff Engineer</title>
      <link>https://lalitm.com/software-engineering-outside-the-spotlight/</link>
      <description>Lately I’ve been reading Sean Goedecke’s essays on being a Staff+ engineer. His work (particularly Software engineering under the spotlight and It’s Not Your Codebase) is razor-sharp and feels painfully familiar to anyone in Big Tech.
On paper, I fit the mold he describes: I’m a Senior Staff engineer at Google. Yet, reading his work left me with a lingering sense of unease. At first, I dismissed this as cynicism. After reflecting, however, I realized the problem wasn’t Sean’s writing but my reading.
Sean isn’t being bleak; he is accurately describing how to deal with a world where engineers are fungible assets and priorities shift quarterly. But my job looks nothing like that and I know deep down that if I tried to operate in that environment or in the way he described I’d burn out within months.
Instead I’ve followed an alternate path, one that optimizes for systems over spotlights, and stewardship over fungibility.</description>
      <category>android</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>aspnet</category>
      <guid>https://lalitm.com/software-engineering-outside-the-spotlight/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 18:02:05 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Basket Case Barn Find: Resurrection of Pontiac's Holy Grail</title>
      <link>https://youtube.com/watch?v=voKa9L7b3c0</link>
      <description>This is the hunt for the only known 1969 Pontiac 2+2 convertible to leave the factory with a Corvette-spec 427 and a four-speed—born in Canada, hiding Chevy bones under Pontiac skin, and scattered across an Alberta farm in coffee cans. We follow the trail from my dad’s bubble-top Parisienne to a barn-find basket case, through mirrored Protect-O-Plate forensics, lost-and-found VIN tags, and an eight-year, concours-level resurrection that dyno-verifies 390 honest horsepower.

If you love deep cuts—Canadian tariffs, Wide-Track myths, Chevy chassis in Pontiac clothing, NOS treasure hunting, and the moment a ghost car rolls back into the light—this one pays off. Stick around to the end to see the “Holy Grail Pontiac” reborn and the paper trail that proves it existed at all.

Free Sample of my Book on the Spectrum: https://amzn.to/3zBinWM

Code: https://github.com/PlummersSoftwareLLC/retropad

Black Friday Affiliate Links!! Save on the Slate 7:
https://amzn.to/4pJfZ4Q
For the Slate AX 1800: https://amzn.to/49hKPt2

Check out ShopTalk, our weekly podcast, every Friday!
https://www.youtube.com/@davepl

Great episode from Ed's Auto Reviews on the weird Canadian auto industry:
https://youtu.be/EzgEOh4s9Lw</description>
      <author> (Dave's Garage)</author>
      <category>youtube</category>
      <guid>https://youtube.com/watch?v=voKa9L7b3c0</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 17:02:01 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BREAKING: Unreal Tournament 2004 is back!</title>
      <link>https://old.reddit.com/r/unrealtournament/comments/1pdbe69/breaking_unreal_tournament_2004_is_back/</link>
      <description>OldUnreal just posted this announcement on their [Discord](https://discord.gg/thURucxzs6): "Welcome Back, Unreal Tournament 2004! Hi everyone!...</description>
      <category>apple</category>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <category>linux</category>
      <guid>https://old.reddit.com/r/unrealtournament/comments/1pdbe69/breaking_unreal_tournament_2004_is_back/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 16:02:18 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Linux kernel is just a program</title>
      <link>https://serversfor.dev/linux-inside-out/the-linux-kernel-is-just-a-program/</link>
      <description>Most books and courses introduce Linux through shell commands, leaving the kernel as a mysterious black box doing magic behind the scenes. In this post, we will run some experiments to demystify it: the Linux kernel is just a binary that you can build and run.</description>
      <category>linux</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <guid>https://serversfor.dev/linux-inside-out/the-linux-kernel-is-just-a-program/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 16:02:11 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JavaScript™</title>
      <link>https://javascript.tm/letter</link>
      <description>We need your help to continue our fight over Oracle's claim to the JavaScript trademark. Here's where we are now and what you can do to help.</description>
      <category>cloud</category>
      <category>nodejs</category>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <guid>https://javascript.tm/letter</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 15:02:12 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Polarization by Design: How Elites Could Shape Mass Preferences as AI Reduces Persuasion Costs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.04047</link>
      <description>In democracies, major policy decisions typically require some form of majority or consensus, so elites must secure mass support to govern. Historically, elites could shape support only through limited instruments like schooling and mass media; advances in AI-driven persuasion sharply reduce the cost and increase the precision of shaping public opinion, making the distribution of preferences itself an object of deliberate design. We develop a dynamic model in which elites choose how much to reshape the distribution of policy preferences, subject to persuasion costs and a majority rule constraint. With a single elite, any optimal intervention tends to push society toward more polarized opinion profiles - a ``polarization pull'' - and improvements in persuasion technology accelerate this drift. When two opposed elites alternate in power, the same technology also creates incentives to park society in ``semi-lock'' regions where opinions are more cohesive and harder for a rival to overturn, so advances in persuasion can either heighten or dampen polarization depending on the environment. Taken together, cheaper persuasion technologies recast polarization as a strategic instrument of governance rather than a purely emergent social byproduct, with important implications for democratic stability as AI capabilities advance.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>web</category>
      <guid>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.04047</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 15:02:09 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Validating Blueprints' Content in Unreal | Thomas Poulet</title>
      <link>https://blog.thomaspoulet.fr/posts/validating-blueprints-content-in-unreal/</link>
      <description>Validating Blueprint classes setup in Unreal Engine 5 using Asset Validators.</description>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <guid>https://blog.thomaspoulet.fr/posts/validating-blueprints-content-in-unreal/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 14:01:40 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Credit Union Mortgages: Updated Daily - FinFam</title>
      <link>https://finfam.app/blog/credit-union-mortgages</link>
      <description>Compare daily mortgage rates from over 120 credit unions. See median rates, trends, and calculate your estimated monthly payment.</description>
      <guid>https://finfam.app/blog/credit-union-mortgages</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 10:02:01 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Memory Price Trends - PCPartPicker</title>
      <link>https://pcpartpicker.com/trends/price/memory/</link>
      <description>Memory Price Trends</description>
      <guid>https://pcpartpicker.com/trends/price/memory/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 09:02:03 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitHub - ryanssenn/torchless: High-speed LLM inference in C/C++</title>
      <link>https://github.com/ryanssenn/torchless</link>
      <description>High-speed LLM inference in C/C++. Contribute to ryanssenn/torchless development by creating an account on GitHub.</description>
      <category>cloud</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>python</category>
      <guid>https://github.com/ryanssenn/torchless</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 09:01:58 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inverted Catenaries</title>
      <link>https://xkcd.com/3176/</link>
      <description></description>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <guid>https://xkcd.com/3176/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 02:01:57 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Your Mind Is Not Software</title>
      <link>https://www.razor.blog/2025/11/your-mind-is-not-software.html</link>
      <description>RAZOR.BLOG: SEEING THINGS AS THEY ARE. Where Philosophy meets the road + questions matter more than answers.</description>
      <category>aspnet</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <category>web</category>
      <guid>https://www.razor.blog/2025/11/your-mind-is-not-software.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:03:22 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why WinQuake exists and how it works</title>
      <link>https://fabiensanglard.net/winquake/index.html</link>
      <description>Dec 3, 2025</description>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <guid>https://fabiensanglard.net/winquake/index.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:03:18 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CNPG Recipe 23 - Managing extensions with ImageVolume in CloudNativePG</title>
      <link>https://www.gabrielebartolini.it/articles/2025/12/cnpg-recipe-23-managing-extensions-with-imagevolume-in-cloudnativepg/</link>
      <description>Leveraging the Kubernetes `ImageVolume` feature and PostgreSQL 18's `extension_control_path`, this article demonstrates the CloudNativePG method for declaratively managing extensions like `pgvector` and PostGIS from separate container images, marking the culmination of a multi-year vision to decouple the database core from extension distribution.</description>
      <category>containers</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <category>sql</category>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <guid>https://www.gabrielebartolini.it/articles/2025/12/cnpg-recipe-23-managing-extensions-with-imagevolume-in-cloudnativepg/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:03:15 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I built a timer I can’t fail to set—Daniel De Laney</title>
      <link>https://danieldelaney.net/timer/</link>
      <description>Metacognition needs a prompt</description>
      <guid>https://danieldelaney.net/timer/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:03:12 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding ECDSA - Web3 Security Blog</title>
      <link>https://avidthinker.github.io/2025/11/28/understanding-ecdsa/</link>
      <description>Exploring blockchain, math, and smart contracts through a security lens.</description>
      <category>encryption</category>
      <guid>https://avidthinker.github.io/2025/11/28/understanding-ecdsa/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:03:08 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LLMs are great at box diagrams</title>
      <link>https://joeblu.com/blog/2025_12_llms-are-great-at-box-diagrams/</link>
      <description>I love diagram languages like mermaid.js and PlantUML because the text format that backs the diagram can be tweaked, takes up very little space in storage, and can be re-rendered at various resolutions any time you need. They’re great! I hate writing them. Mermaid has a different syntax for every diagram type, and they’re hard to remember. PlantUML is more consistent, though not totally, and in my experience can be quite verbose.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <guid>https://joeblu.com/blog/2025_12_llms-are-great-at-box-diagrams/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:03:02 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Everything that is wrong in museums starts with wall labels</title>
      <link>https://www.aaronland.info/weblog/2025/11/20/cafeteria/#usf?utm_source=hnblogs.substack.com</link>
      <description>It is difficult to separate the issues and questions that contemporary machine-learning and “artificial intelligence” technologies raise in the context of museum without addressing the long history of past attempts to make collections “digital”  and how those efforts have played out organizationally over the years. So many of those issues end up being made manifest in the challenges surrounding the production of wall labels and this talk will discuss some inconvenient truths (and opportunities) about museums and computing that AI surfaces.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://www.aaronland.info/weblog/2025/11/20/cafeteria/#usf?utm_source=hnblogs.substack.com</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:02:58 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stop talking</title>
      <link>https://gurkan.in/2025/12/stop-talking/</link>
      <description>The years I’ve been working brought a lot of context, more scars, and more pattern recognition. You start seeing inefficiencies, problems. Like a lineman sees a frayed cable: obvious, dangerous, and actually … fixable.</description>
      <guid>https://gurkan.in/2025/12/stop-talking/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:02:53 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How about a unidimensional spaceship? - Page 9</title>
      <link>https://conwaylife.com/forums/viewtopic.php?p=222136#p222136</link>
      <description>I6_I6 wrote: ↑Yesterday, 10:47 am
Wow! This is amazing!
That's 2 macro-spaceships in the span of a week.
I've been watching this thread for a while as it grew, but could never comprehend anything going on.
Will someone bother to explain how it works?
We really need a wiki page.</description>
      <guid>https://conwaylife.com/forums/viewtopic.php?p=222136#p222136</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:02:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why don’t we get more scientific breakthroughs?</title>
      <link>https://lemire.me/blog/2025/12/03/why-dont-we-get-more-scientific-breakthroughs/</link>
      <description>It is absolutely clear to me that large language models represent the most significant scientific breakthrough of the past fifty years. The nature of that breakthrough has far reaching implications for what is happening in science today. And I believe that the entire scientific establishment is refusing to acknowledge it. We often excuse our slow … Continue reading Why don’t we get more scientific breakthroughs?</description>
      <author> (https://lemire.me/blog/author/lemire/)</author>
      <category>python</category>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <guid>https://lemire.me/blog/2025/12/03/why-dont-we-get-more-scientific-breakthroughs/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:02:45 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What I learned building an opinionated and minimal coding agent</title>
      <link>https://mariozechner.at/posts/2025-11-30-pi-coding-agent/</link>
      <description>Lessons I learned while building my own coding agent from scratch.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>nodejs</category>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <category>vscode</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <guid>https://mariozechner.at/posts/2025-11-30-pi-coding-agent/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:02:41 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lessons From a Noisy Monitor — Mergify</title>
      <link>https://mergify.com/blog/lessons-from-a-noisy-monitor</link>
      <description>Your database monitors keep firing even though nothing is wrong? We hit the same problem: noisy IOPS alerts caused by predictable jobs. This post explains how we replaced brittle thresholds with an SLO-based approach that restored signal, eliminated noise, and stopped the monitor from "crying wolf."</description>
      <category>sql</category>
      <guid>https://mergify.com/blog/lessons-from-a-noisy-monitor</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:02:35 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Compliance != Security</title>
      <link>https://introvertmac.wordpress.com/2025/12/03/compliance-security/</link>
      <description>For over a decade, I’ve been doing bug bounty, security audits, and security consulting. And if there’s one thing I’ve seen repeatedly, it’s this:Most startups call a security engineer or hire a se…</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>containers</category>
      <category>sql</category>
      <guid>https://introvertmac.wordpress.com/2025/12/03/compliance-security/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:02:31 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Parcha Dev Blog</title>
      <link>https://blog.parcha.dev/dont-sleep-on-fast-inference</link>
      <description>Engineering insights from the Parcha team. AI agents, fast inference, and building compliance automation.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>web</category>
      <guid>https://blog.parcha.dev/dont-sleep-on-fast-inference</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:02:28 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unpaid Labour in Productive Capacity</title>
      <link>https://danieltan.weblog.lol/2025/12/appendix-b-unpaid-labour-in-productive-capacity</link>
      <description>The Productive Capacity Theory of Money framework begins with a simple observation: when you receive an employment letter, your relationship with the financial system transforms overnight. Banks that wouldn't lend you a dollar suddenly want to give you hundreds of thousands. Credit card companies compete for your business. Mortgage lenders calculate exactly how much house you can afford, typically three to four times your annual salary.</description>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <guid>https://danieltan.weblog.lol/2025/12/appendix-b-unpaid-labour-in-productive-capacity</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:02:23 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Database Was "Correct." It Was Also 296x Too Slow. - Chandler Nguyen</title>
      <link>https://www.chandlernguyen.com/blog/2025/12/02/my-database-was-correct-it-was-also-296x-too-slow/</link>
      <description>October 25th, 2025. My SaaS application was finally feature-complete. Nine major features, multi-tenant architecture, progressive learning—everything worked. But it was slow. Really slow. Dashboard queries</description>
      <author> (https://www.facebook.com/groups/2316660408476702)</author>
      <category>sql</category>
      <guid>https://www.chandlernguyen.com/blog/2025/12/02/my-database-was-correct-it-was-also-296x-too-slow/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:02:18 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why are my headphones buzzing whenever I run my game?</title>
      <link>https://alexene.dev/2025/12/03/Why-do-my-headphones-buzz-when-i-run-my-game.html</link>
      <description>Background</description>
      <category>cloud</category>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <category>rust</category>
      <category>web</category>
      <guid>https://alexene.dev/2025/12/03/Why-do-my-headphones-buzz-when-i-run-my-game.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 22:02:08 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RCE in React Server Components</title>
      <link>https://github.com/vercel/next.js/security/advisories/GHSA-9qr9-h5gf-34mp</link>
      <description>A vulnerability affects certain React packages&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; for versions 19.0.0, 19.1.0, 19.1.1, and 19.2.0 and frameworks that use the affected packages, including Next.js 15.x and 16.x using the A...</description>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <guid>https://github.com/vercel/next.js/security/advisories/GHSA-9qr9-h5gf-34mp</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 22:02:04 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Everyone in Seattle Hates AI — Jonathon Ready</title>
      <link>https://jonready.com/blog/posts/everyone-in-seattle-hates-ai.html</link>
      <description>A post about everyone in Seattle hating AI.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>web</category>
      <guid>https://jonready.com/blog/posts/everyone-in-seattle-hates-ai.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 22:02:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ghostty Is Now Non-Profit</title>
      <link>https://mitchellh.com/writing/ghostty-non-profit</link>
      <description>Ghostty is now fiscally sponsored by Hack Club, a
registered 501(c)(3) non-profit.</description>
      <guid>https://mitchellh.com/writing/ghostty-non-profit</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 21:02:06 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I Reverse Engineered a Billion-Dollar Legal AI Tool and Found 100k+ Confidential Files</title>
      <link>https://alexschapiro.com/security/vulnerability/2025/12/02/filevine-api-100k</link>
      <description>Update: This post received a large amount of attention on Hacker News — see the discussion thread.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <guid>https://alexschapiro.com/security/vulnerability/2025/12/02/filevine-api-100k</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 21:02:02 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>