<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-16"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://linksfor.dev/feed.xml" />
    <title>linksfor.dev(s)</title>
    <link>https://linksfor.dev/feed.xml</link>
    <description>Curated links for devs</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>The RAM Shortage Comes for Us All</title>
      <link>https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2025/ram-shortage-comes-us-all/</link>
      <description>Memory price inflation comes for us all, and if you're not affected yet, just wait.
I was building a new PC last month using some parts I had bought earlier this year. The 64 Gigabyte T-Create DDR5 memory kit I used cost $209 then. Today? The same kit costs $650!
Just in the past week, we found out Raspberry Pi's increasing their single board computer prices. Micron's killing the Crucial brand of RAM and storage devices completely, meaning there's gonna be one fewer consumer memory manufacturer. Samsung can't even buy RAM from themselves to build their own Smartphones, and small vendors like Libre Computer and Mono are seeing RAM prices double, triple, or even worse, and they're not even buying the latest RAM tech!</description>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <guid>https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2025/ram-shortage-comes-us-all/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 20:03:28 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minisforum stuffs an entire Arm Homelab in the MS-R1</title>
      <link>https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2025/minisforum-stuffs-entire-arm-homelab-ms-r1/</link>
      <description>The Minisforum MS-R1 uses the same Cix CD8180 Arm SoC as the Orion O6 I reviewed earlier this year. But everything else about this thing is different.
What this thing should be, is a box that runs Linux and can compete with at least an Apple M1 Mac mini, or a mid-range Mini PC. But what we got... is something different.
Video Hate reading? I also published a video on the MS-R1 on my YouTube channel. Watch it here, or scroll on past.</description>
      <category>apple</category>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <category>linux</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>youtube</category>
      <guid>https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2025/minisforum-stuffs-entire-arm-homelab-ms-r1/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 20:03:25 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JeffGeerling.com has been Migrated to Hugo</title>
      <link>https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2026/migrated-to-hugo/</link>
      <description>Since 2009, this website has run on Drupal. Starting with Drupal 6, and progressing through major site upgrades and migrations to 7, 8, 9, and 10, I used the site as a way to dogfood the same CMS (Content Management System) I used in my day job for over a decade.
But as time progressed—especially after completing a grueling upgrade from Drupal 7 to 8—my enthusiasm for maintaining what's now a more enterprise-focused Digital Experience Platform or 'DXP' for a personal blog has waned.</description>
      <category>ruby</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <category>sql</category>
      <category>youtube</category>
      <guid>https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2026/migrated-to-hugo/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 20:03:21 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1.5 TB of VRAM on Mac Studio - RDMA over Thunderbolt 5</title>
      <link>https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2025/15-tb-vram-on-mac-studio-rdma-over-thunderbolt-5/</link>
      <description>Apple gave me access to this Mac Studio cluster to test RDMA over Thunderbolt, a new feature in macOS 26.2. The easiest way to test it is with Exo 1.0, an open source private AI clustering tool. RDMA lets the Macs all act like they have one giant pool of RAM, which speeds up things like massive AI models.
The stack of Macs I tested, with 1.5 TB of unified memory, costs just shy of $40,000, and if you're wondering, no I cannot justify spending that much money for this. Apple loaned the Mac Studios for testing. I also have to thank DeskPi for sending over the 4-post mini rack containing the cluster.</description>
      <category>apple</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <category>nodejs</category>
      <guid>https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2025/15-tb-vram-on-mac-studio-rdma-over-thunderbolt-5/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 20:03:18 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to silence the fan on a CM5 after shutdown</title>
      <link>https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2025/how-silence-fan-on-cm5-after-shutdown/</link>
      <description>Out of the box, if you buy a Raspberry Pi Compute Module 5, install it on the official CM5 IO Board, and install a fan on it (e.g. my current favorite, the EDAtec CM5 Active Cooler), you'll notice the fan ramps up to 100% speed after you shut down the Pi.
That's not fun, since at least for a couple of my CM5s, they are more often powered down than running, creating a slight cacophany!</description>
      <guid>https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2025/how-silence-fan-on-cm5-after-shutdown/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 20:03:14 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>All Intel GPUs run on Raspberry Pi and RISC-V</title>
      <link>https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2025/all-intel-gpus-run-on-raspberry-pi-and-risc-v/</link>
      <description>We finally have Intel Arc GPUs working on the Pi somewhat stably—it required overcoming many small hurdles, but it looks like support could land in Raspberry Pi OS if we can get a simple patch upstreamed1. If that happens, all you'd need to do to use an Intel card on a Pi is install a firmware package.
The cards I've spent the most time with so far are:</description>
      <category>git</category>
      <category>linux</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2025/all-intel-gpus-run-on-raspberry-pi-and-risc-v/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 20:03:11 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It's not that hard to stop a Trane</title>
      <link>https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2025/its-not-hard-stop-trane/</link>
      <description>Six years ago, I replaced the old HVAC system that came with our house, a central forced air system installed in 19951.
The new system is a Trane XR AC paired with an S9V2 96% efficiency forced-air gas furnace. And it ran great! Better efficiency, quieter, multiple fan speeds so I can circulate air and prevent stale air in some parts of the house... what's not to love?
Well, apparently the engineering:</description>
      <category>rust</category>
      <guid>https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2025/its-not-hard-stop-trane/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 20:03:07 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Testing the Mono Gateway, a custom-built 10 Gbps Router</title>
      <link>https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2026/testing-mono-gateway-custom-built-10-gbps-router/</link>
      <description>Last month, the stars aligned for me to bring the Mono Gateway (a 10 Gbps router that YouTuber Tomaž Zaman and his team at Mono built from scratch) on a trip to Phoenix, and test it with one of the most OP network test boxes I've ever seen, at the ServeTheHome HQ.
In this video, Patrick (from STH) and I put Gateway through a real-world torture test using CyPerf:
Mono Gateway The Gateway is a small (1U/desktop) router with features like a 4-core Arm CPU, 8GB of ECC LPDDR RAM, and decent expansion options for a compact router.</description>
      <category>conference</category>
      <category>apple</category>
      <guid>https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2026/testing-mono-gateway-custom-built-10-gbps-router/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 20:03:04 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Converting hot dog plasma video to sound with OpenCV</title>
      <link>https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2025/converting-hot-dog-plasma-video-sound-opencv/</link>
      <description>When you ground a hot dog to an AM radio tower, it generates plasma.
Your browser does not support the video tag.
While the hot dog's flesh is getting vaporized, a tiny plasma arc moves the air around it back and forth. And because this tower is an AM tower, it uses Amplitude Modulation, where a transmitter changes the amplitude of a carrier wave up and down. Just like a speaker cone moving up and down, the plasma arc from the hot dog turns that modulation into audible sound.</description>
      <category>visualstudio</category>
      <category>apple</category>
      <category>python</category>
      <category>vscode</category>
      <guid>https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2025/converting-hot-dog-plasma-video-sound-opencv/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 20:03:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NIST was 5 μs off UTC after last week's power cut</title>
      <link>https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2025/nist-was-5-%CE%BCs-utc-after-last-weeks-power-cut/</link>
      <description>If you were 5 microseconds late today, blame it on NIST.
Their facility in Boulder Colorado just had its power cut for multiple days. After a backup generator failed, their main ensemble clock lost track of UTC, or Universal Time Coordinated.
But even if you used the NTP timing servers they run, they were never off by more than 5 microseconds.
5 μs might seem insignificant. But it is significant for scientists and universities who rely on NIST's more specialized timing signals.</description>
      <category>apple</category>
      <category>linux</category>
      <guid>https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2025/nist-was-5-%CE%BCs-utc-after-last-weeks-power-cut/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 20:02:56 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CM0 - a new Raspberry Pi you can't buy</title>
      <link>https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2025/cm0-new-raspberry-pi-you-cant-buy/</link>
      <description>This little postage stamp is actually a full Raspberry Pi Zero 2, complete with eMMC storage and WiFi.
But you can't get one. Well, not unless you buy the CM0NANO development board from EDAtec, or you live in China.
This little guy doesn't have an HDMI port, Ethernet, or even USB. It's a special version of the 'Compute Module' line of boards. Little Raspberry Pi 'System on Modules' (SoMs), they're called.</description>
      <category>linux</category>
      <category>apple</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>youtube</category>
      <guid>https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2025/cm0-new-raspberry-pi-you-cant-buy/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 20:02:53 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The DC-ROMA II is the fastest RISC-V laptop and is odd</title>
      <link>https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2025/dc-roma-ii-fastest-risc-v-laptop-and-odd/</link>
      <description>Inside this Framework 13 laptop is a special mainboard developed by DeepComputing in collaboration with Framework. It has an 8-core RISC-V processor, the ESWIN 7702X—not your typical AMD, Intel, or even Arm SoC. The full laptop version I tested costs $1119 and gets you about the performance of a Raspberry Pi.
A Pi 4—the one that came out in 2019.
But unlike the Pi 4, this eats up 25 watts of power at idle, meaning the poor battery only lasts 2-3 hours.</description>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <category>linux</category>
      <category>python</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2025/dc-roma-ii-fastest-risc-v-laptop-and-odd/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 20:02:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Arduino Uno Q is a weird hybrid SBC</title>
      <link>https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2025/arduino-uno-q-weird-hybrid-sbc/</link>
      <description>The Arduino Uno Q is... a weird board. It's the first product born out of Qualcomm's buyout of Arduino.
It's like if you married an Intel CPU, and a Raspberry Pi RP2040 microcontroller—oh wait, Radxa's X4 did that.
Arduino even tried it before with their old Yún board, which had Linux running on a MIPS CPU, married to an ATmega microcontroller.
The Uno Q isn't quite a Raspberry Pi, but it looks like one when you squint at it. And it's not quite an Uno, but it does a pretty good job masquerading as that, too.</description>
      <category>linux</category>
      <category>python</category>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <category>containers</category>
      <guid>https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2025/arduino-uno-q-weird-hybrid-sbc/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 20:02:45 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Air Lab is the Flipper Zero of air quality monitors</title>
      <link>https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2025/air-lab-flipper-zero-air-quality-monitors/</link>
      <description>This air quality monitor costs $250. It's called the Air Lab, and I've been using it to measure the air in my car, home, studio, and a few events over the past few months. And in using it over the course of a road trip I learned to not run recirculate in my car quite as often—more on that later.
Networked Artifacts built in some personality:</description>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <guid>https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2025/air-lab-flipper-zero-air-quality-monitors/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 20:02:42 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why doesn't Apple make a standalone Touch ID?</title>
      <link>https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2025/why-doesnt-apple-make-standalone-touch-id/</link>
      <description>I finally upgraded to a mechanical keyboard. But because Apple's so protective of their Touch ID hardware, there aren't any mechanical keyboards with that feature built in.
But there is a way to hack it. It's incredibly wasteful, and takes a bit more patience than I think most people have, but you basically take an Apple Magic Keyboard with Touch ID, rip out the Touch ID, and install it in a 3D printed box, along with the keyboard's logic board.</description>
      <guid>https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2025/why-doesnt-apple-make-standalone-touch-id/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 20:02:38 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using AMD GPUs on Raspberry Pi without recompiling Linux</title>
      <link>https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2025/using-amd-gpus-on-raspberry-pi-without-recompiling-linux/</link>
      <description>I'm working on a more in-depth test of some newer AMD GPUs on the Raspberry Pi, now that the 15 line kernel patch is (IMO) nearly ready for upstreaming.
But this blog post shows how to quickly get almost any modern AMD GPU running on a Raspberry Pi 5, CM5, or Pi 500+, thanks to this patch on the Pi Linux fork.
Note: This patch actually enables AMD and Intel. I wrote about how to get Intel Arc GPUs running on the Pi yesterday.</description>
      <category>git</category>
      <category>linux</category>
      <category>sql</category>
      <guid>https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2025/using-amd-gpus-on-raspberry-pi-without-recompiling-linux/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 20:02:34 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dell's version of the DGX Spark fixes pain points</title>
      <link>https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2025/dells-version-dgx-spark-fixes-pain-points/</link>
      <description>Dell sent me two of their GB10 mini workstations to test:
In this blog post, I'll cover the base system, just one of the two nodes. Cluster testing is ongoing, and I'll cover things like AI model training and networking more in depth next year, likely with comparisons to the Framework Desktop cluster and Mac Studio cluster I've also been testing.
But many of the same caveats of the DGX Spark (namely, price to performance is not great if you just want to run LLMs on a small desktop) apply to Dell's GB10 box as well.</description>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <category>apple</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>linux</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <guid>https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2025/dells-version-dgx-spark-fixes-pain-points/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 20:02:31 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nvidia Graphics Cards work on Pi 5 and Rockchip</title>
      <link>https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2025/nvidia-graphics-cards-work-on-pi-5-and-rockchip/</link>
      <description>A few months ago, GitHub user @yanghaku dropped a 15 line patch to fix GPU support for practically all AMD GPUs on the Raspberry Pi (and demoed a 3080 running on the Pi with a separate, unreleased patch). This week, GitHub user @mariobalanica dropped this (larger) patch which does the same for Nvidia GPUs!
I have a Raspberry Pi and an Nvidia graphics card—and I'm easily distracted. So I put down my testing of a GB10 system for a bit, and compiled mariobalanica's branch.</description>
      <category>linux</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>sql</category>
      <guid>https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2025/nvidia-graphics-cards-work-on-pi-5-and-rockchip/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 20:02:27 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Big GPUs don't need big PCs</title>
      <link>https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2025/big-gpus-dont-need-big-pcs/</link>
      <description>Ever since I got AMD, Intel, and Nvidia graphics cards to run on a Raspberry Pi, I had a nagging question:
What's the point?
The Raspberry Pi only has 1 lane of PCIe Gen 3 bandwidth available for a connection to an eGPU. That's not much. Especially considering a modern desktop has at least one slot with 16 lanes of PCIe Gen 5 bandwidth. That's 8 GT/s versus 512 GT/s. Not a fair fight.</description>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2025/big-gpus-dont-need-big-pcs/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 20:02:24 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Benchmarking NVENC video transcoding on the Pi</title>
      <link>https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2025/benchmarking-nvenc-video-transcoding-on-pi/</link>
      <description>Now that Nvidia GPUs run on the Raspberry Pi, I've been putting all the ones I own through their paces.
Many people have an older Nvidia card (like a 3060) laying around from an upgrade. So could a Pi be suitable for GPU-accelerated video transcoding, either standalone for conversion, or running something like Jellyfin for video library management and streaming?
That's what I set out to do, and the first step, besides getting the drivers and CUDA going (see blog post linked above), was to find a way to get a repeatable benchmark going.</description>
      <category>cloud</category>
      <category>rust</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <guid>https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2025/benchmarking-nvenc-video-transcoding-on-pi/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 20:02:20 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is "good taste" in software engineering?</title>
      <link>https://www.seangoedecke.com/taste/</link>
      <description>--</description>
      <category>cloud</category>
      <category>ruby</category>
      <category>rust</category>
      <category>python</category>
      <guid>https://www.seangoedecke.com/taste/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 18:06:22 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unification across Microsoft Platforms</title>
      <link>https://davepermen.net/blog/general-development/unification-across-microsoft-platforms</link>
      <description>'Unification across Microsoft Platforms' written by davepermen</description>
      <guid>https://davepermen.net/blog/general-development/unification-across-microsoft-platforms</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 18:06:19 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Autoscaling Web</title>
      <link>https://davepermen.net/blog/web-dev/the-autoscaling-web</link>
      <description>'The Autoscaling Web' written by davepermen</description>
      <category>web</category>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <guid>https://davepermen.net/blog/web-dev/the-autoscaling-web</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 18:06:14 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is it worrying that 95% of AI enterprise projects fail?</title>
      <link>https://www.seangoedecke.com/why-do-ai-enterprise-projects-fail/</link>
      <description>In July of this year, MIT NANDA released a report called The GenAI Divide: State of AI in Business 2025. The report spends most of its time giving advice about…</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>sql</category>
      <guid>https://www.seangoedecke.com/why-do-ai-enterprise-projects-fail/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 18:06:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Run Cleanup Tasks in Windows</title>
      <link>https://davepermen.net/blog/computer-knowledge/run-cleanup-tasks-in-windows</link>
      <description>'Run Cleanup Tasks in Windows' written by davepermen</description>
      <guid>https://davepermen.net/blog/computer-knowledge/run-cleanup-tasks-in-windows</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 18:06:07 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I provide technical clarity to non-technical leaders</title>
      <link>https://www.seangoedecke.com/clarity/</link>
      <description>My mission as a staff engineer is to provide technical clarity to the organization. Of course, I do other stuff too. I run projects, I ship code, I review PRs…</description>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <guid>https://www.seangoedecke.com/clarity/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 18:06:02 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Testing the Mono Gateway, a custom-built 10 Gbps Router</title>
      <link>https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2026/testing-mono-gateway-custom-built-10-gbps-router</link>
      <description></description>
      <category>conference</category>
      <category>apple</category>
      <guid>https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2026/testing-mono-gateway-custom-built-10-gbps-router</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 18:05:58 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We are in the "gentleman scientist" era of AI research</title>
      <link>https://www.seangoedecke.com/ai-and-informal-science/</link>
      <description>Many scientific discoveries used to be made by amateurs. William Herschel, who discovered Uranus, was a composer and an organist. Antoine Lavoisier, who laid…</description>
      <category>cloud</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>python</category>
      <guid>https://www.seangoedecke.com/ai-and-informal-science/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 18:05:55 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Woohoo! Wireless LAN!</title>
      <link>https://davepermen.net/blog/ancient-posts/woohoo-wireless-lan</link>
      <description>'Woohoo! Wireless LAN!' written by davepermen</description>
      <guid>https://davepermen.net/blog/ancient-posts/woohoo-wireless-lan</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 18:05:52 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025 was an excellent year for this blog</title>
      <link>https://www.seangoedecke.com/2025-wrapup/</link>
      <description>--</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://www.seangoedecke.com/2025-wrapup/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 18:05:47 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dell's version of the DGX Spark fixes pain points</title>
      <link>https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2025/dells-version-dgx-spark-fixes-pain-points</link>
      <description>Dell sent me two of their GB10 mini workstations to test:</description>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <category>apple</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>linux</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <guid>https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2025/dells-version-dgx-spark-fixes-pain-points</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 18:05:44 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why it takes months to tell if new AI models are good</title>
      <link>https://www.seangoedecke.com/are-new-models-good/</link>
      <description>--</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <category>python</category>
      <guid>https://www.seangoedecke.com/are-new-models-good/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 18:05:40 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nobody knows how large software products work</title>
      <link>https://www.seangoedecke.com/nobody-knows-how-software-products-work/</link>
      <description>--</description>
      <category>encryption</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <guid>https://www.seangoedecke.com/nobody-knows-how-software-products-work/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 18:05:37 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Endless AI-generated Wikipedia</title>
      <link>https://www.seangoedecke.com/endless-wiki/</link>
      <description>--</description>
      <category>sql</category>
      <category>cloud</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <guid>https://www.seangoedecke.com/endless-wiki/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 18:05:34 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Post from the cellphone</title>
      <link>https://davepermen.net/blog/ancient-posts/post-from-the-cellphone</link>
      <description>'Post from the cellphone' written by davepermen</description>
      <guid>https://davepermen.net/blog/ancient-posts/post-from-the-cellphone</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 18:05:31 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The DC-ROMA II is the fastest RISC-V laptop and is odd</title>
      <link>https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2025/dc-roma-ii-fastest-risc-v-laptop-and-odd</link>
      <description></description>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <category>linux</category>
      <category>python</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2025/dc-roma-ii-fastest-risc-v-laptop-and-odd</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 18:05:26 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI coding agents rely too much on fallbacks</title>
      <link>https://www.seangoedecke.com/agents-and-fallbacks/</link>
      <description>--</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://www.seangoedecke.com/agents-and-fallbacks/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 18:05:23 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Windows 10 UAP Extend Titlebar</title>
      <link>https://davepermen.net/blog/dotnet/windows-10-uap-extend-titlebar</link>
      <description>'Windows 10 UAP Extend Titlebar' written by davepermen</description>
      <category>dotnet</category>
      <guid>https://davepermen.net/blog/dotnet/windows-10-uap-extend-titlebar</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 18:05:19 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Becoming unblockable</title>
      <link>https://www.seangoedecke.com/unblockable/</link>
      <description>With enough careful effort, it’s possible to become unblockable. In other words, you can put yourself in a position where you’re always able to make forward…</description>
      <category>vscode</category>
      <category>conference</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>sql</category>
      <guid>https://www.seangoedecke.com/unblockable/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 18:05:15 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An unofficial FAQ for Stripe's new "Tempo" blockchain</title>
      <link>https://www.seangoedecke.com/tempo-faq/</link>
      <description>Stripe just announced Tempo, a “L1 blockchain” for “stablecoin payments”. What does any of this mean? In 2021, I was interested enough in blockchain to write a…</description>
      <category>nodejs</category>
      <category>sql</category>
      <guid>https://www.seangoedecke.com/tempo-faq/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 18:05:12 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NIST was 5 μs off UTC after last week's power cut</title>
      <link>https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2025/nist-was-5-%CE%BCs-utc-after-last-weeks-power-cut</link>
      <description>If you were 5 microseconds late today, blame it on NIST.</description>
      <category>apple</category>
      <category>linux</category>
      <guid>https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2025/nist-was-5-%CE%BCs-utc-after-last-weeks-power-cut</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 18:05:09 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simple Immutable POCO Types in C#</title>
      <link>https://davepermen.net/blog/dotnet/simple-immutable-poco-types-in-csharp</link>
      <description>'Simple Immutable POCO Types in C#' written by davepermen</description>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <category>dotnet</category>
      <guid>https://davepermen.net/blog/dotnet/simple-immutable-poco-types-in-csharp</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 18:05:05 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MVVM in XAML — Binding of Commands to Root Element</title>
      <link>https://davepermen.net/blog/dotnet/mvvm-in-xaml--binding-of-commands-to-root-element</link>
      <description>'MVVM in XAML — Binding of Commands to Root Element' written by davepermen</description>
      <category>dotnet</category>
      <guid>https://davepermen.net/blog/dotnet/mvvm-in-xaml--binding-of-commands-to-root-element</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 18:05:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What have we learned about building agentic AI tools?</title>
      <link>https://www.seangoedecke.com/ideas-in-agentic-ai-tooling/</link>
      <description>In the middle of 2025, agentic coding finally became a thing: first with the release of Claude Sonnet 4, the first “smart enough to be useful” agentic model…</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <guid>https://www.seangoedecke.com/ideas-in-agentic-ai-tooling/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 18:04:56 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What I learned building an AI-driven spaced repetition app</title>
      <link>https://www.seangoedecke.com/autodeck/</link>
      <description>--</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>encryption</category>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <guid>https://www.seangoedecke.com/autodeck/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 18:04:53 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CM0 - a new Raspberry Pi you can't buy</title>
      <link>https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2025/cm0-new-raspberry-pi-you-cant-buy</link>
      <description></description>
      <category>linux</category>
      <category>apple</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>youtube</category>
      <guid>https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2025/cm0-new-raspberry-pi-you-cant-buy</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 18:04:50 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Software engineers should be a little bit cynical</title>
      <link>https://www.seangoedecke.com/a-little-bit-cynical/</link>
      <description>--</description>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <guid>https://www.seangoedecke.com/a-little-bit-cynical/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 18:04:46 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What I use (12013 HE)</title>
      <link>https://davepermen.net/blog/computer-knowledge/what-i-use-12013-he</link>
      <description>'What I use (12013 HE)' written by davepermen</description>
      <category>visualstudio</category>
      <category>youtube</category>
      <guid>https://davepermen.net/blog/computer-knowledge/what-i-use-12013-he</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 18:04:43 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Should LLMs just treat text content as an image?</title>
      <link>https://www.seangoedecke.com/text-tokens-as-image-tokens/</link>
      <description>Several days ago, DeepSeek released a new OCR paper. OCR, or “optical character recognition”, is the process of converting an image of text - say, a scanned…</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://www.seangoedecke.com/text-tokens-as-image-tokens/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 18:04:38 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What I use (12025 HE)</title>
      <link>https://davepermen.net/blog/computer-knowledge/what-i-use-12025-he</link>
      <description>'What I use (12025 HE)' written by davepermen</description>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <category>visualstudio</category>
      <category>android</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>linux</category>
      <guid>https://davepermen.net/blog/computer-knowledge/what-i-use-12025-he</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 18:04:35 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why doesn't Apple make a standalone Touch ID?</title>
      <link>https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2025/why-doesnt-apple-make-standalone-touch-id</link>
      <description>I finally upgraded to a mechanical keyboard. But because Apple's so protective of their Touch ID hardware, there aren't any mechanical keyboards with that feature built in.</description>
      <guid>https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2025/why-doesnt-apple-make-standalone-touch-id</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 18:04:30 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You can't design software you don't work on</title>
      <link>https://www.seangoedecke.com/you-cant-design-software-you-dont-work-on/</link>
      <description>--</description>
      <category>cloud</category>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://www.seangoedecke.com/you-cant-design-software-you-dont-work-on/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 18:04:26 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI is good news for Australian and European software engineers</title>
      <link>https://www.seangoedecke.com/ai-is-good-news-for-australian-engineers/</link>
      <description>Right now the dominant programing model is something like “centaur chess”, where a skilled human is paired with a computer assistant. Together, they produce…</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://www.seangoedecke.com/ai-is-good-news-for-australian-engineers/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 18:04:19 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mistakes I see engineers making in their code reviews</title>
      <link>https://www.seangoedecke.com/good-code-reviews/</link>
      <description>In the last two years, code review has gotten much more important. Code is now easy to generate using LLMs, but it’s still just as hard to review. Many software…</description>
      <category>sql</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>vscode</category>
      <guid>https://www.seangoedecke.com/good-code-reviews/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 18:04:16 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Only three kinds of AI products actually work</title>
      <link>https://www.seangoedecke.com/ai-products/</link>
      <description>--</description>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://www.seangoedecke.com/ai-products/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 18:04:12 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>'Make invalid states unrepresentable' considered harmful</title>
      <link>https://www.seangoedecke.com/invalid-states/</link>
      <description>One of the most controversial things I believe about good software design is that your code should be more flexible than your domain model. This is in direct…</description>
      <category>sql</category>
      <guid>https://www.seangoedecke.com/invalid-states/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 18:04:09 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Big GPUs don't need big PCs</title>
      <link>https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2025/big-gpus-dont-need-big-pcs</link>
      <description></description>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2025/big-gpus-dont-need-big-pcs</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 18:04:06 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Energy Lie</title>
      <link>https://davepermen.net/blog/energy-transition/the-energy-lie</link>
      <description>'The Energy Lie' written by davepermen</description>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <guid>https://davepermen.net/blog/energy-transition/the-energy-lie</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 18:04:03 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why do AI models use so many em-dashes?</title>
      <link>https://www.seangoedecke.com/em-dashes/</link>
      <description>If you asked most people to name a defining feature of AI-generated writing, they’d probably say the em-dash — like this. Language models use em-dashes so much…</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://www.seangoedecke.com/em-dashes/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 18:03:58 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UWP App for Kiosk Mode</title>
      <link>https://davepermen.net/blog/dotnet/uwp-app-for-kiosk-mode</link>
      <description>'UWP App for Kiosk Mode' written by davepermen</description>
      <category>dotnet</category>
      <guid>https://davepermen.net/blog/dotnet/uwp-app-for-kiosk-mode</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 18:03:55 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Netzwerk Reset auf Windows 8</title>
      <link>https://davepermen.net/blog/computer-knowledge/netzwerk-reset-auf-windows-8</link>
      <description>'Netzwerk Reset auf Windows 8' written by davepermen</description>
      <guid>https://davepermen.net/blog/computer-knowledge/netzwerk-reset-auf-windows-8</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 18:03:50 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI detection tools cannot prove that text is AI-generated</title>
      <link>https://www.seangoedecke.com/ai-detection/</link>
      <description>--</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://www.seangoedecke.com/ai-detection/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 18:03:44 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Writing for AIs is a good way to reach more humans</title>
      <link>https://www.seangoedecke.com/writing-for-ais/</link>
      <description>There’s an idea going around right now about “writing for AIs”: writing as if your primary audience is not human readers, but the language models that will be…</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <guid>https://www.seangoedecke.com/writing-for-ais/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 18:03:41 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>If you are good at code review, you will be good at using AI agents</title>
      <link>https://www.seangoedecke.com/ai-agents-and-code-review/</link>
      <description>Using AI agents correctly is a process of reviewing code. If you’re good at reviewing code, you’ll be good at using tools like Claude Code, Codex, or the…</description>
      <category>git</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>linux</category>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <guid>https://www.seangoedecke.com/ai-agents-and-code-review/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 18:03:38 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The whole point of OpenAI's Responses API is to help them hide reasoning traces</title>
      <link>https://www.seangoedecke.com/responses-api/</link>
      <description>About six months ago, OpenAI released their Responses API, which replaced their previous /chat/completions API for inference. The old API was very simple: you…</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>cloud</category>
      <guid>https://www.seangoedecke.com/responses-api/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 18:03:35 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tiny Game Engine Stuff</title>
      <link>https://davepermen.net/blog/dotnet/tiny-game-engine-stuff</link>
      <description>'Tiny Game Engine Stuff' written by davepermen</description>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <category>dotnet</category>
      <guid>https://davepermen.net/blog/dotnet/tiny-game-engine-stuff</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 18:03:31 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grok is enabling mass sexual harassment on Twitter</title>
      <link>https://www.seangoedecke.com/grok-deepfakes/</link>
      <description>Grok, xAI’s flagship image model, is now being widely used to generate nonconsensual lewd images of women on the internet. When a woman posts an innocuous…</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <guid>https://www.seangoedecke.com/grok-deepfakes/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 18:03:27 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>To get better at technical writing, lower your expectations</title>
      <link>https://www.seangoedecke.com/technical-communication/</link>
      <description>Technical writing is a big part of a software engineer’s job. This is more true the more senior you get. In the limit case, a principal or distinguished…</description>
      <category>encryption</category>
      <category>sql</category>
      <guid>https://www.seangoedecke.com/technical-communication/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 18:03:24 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GPT-5-Codex is a better AI researcher than me</title>
      <link>https://www.seangoedecke.com/ai-research-with-codex/</link>
      <description>--</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://www.seangoedecke.com/ai-research-with-codex/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 18:03:16 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Benchmarking NVENC video transcoding on the Pi</title>
      <link>https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2025/benchmarking-nvenc-video-transcoding-on-pi</link>
      <description></description>
      <category>cloud</category>
      <category>rust</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <guid>https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2025/benchmarking-nvenc-video-transcoding-on-pi</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 18:03:07 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thompson tells how he developed the Go language at Google.</title>
      <link>https://youtube.com/watch?v=NTrAISNdf70</link>
      <description>Kenneth Lane Thompson, winner of the Association for Computing Machinery's A.M. Turing Award, discusses development of the Go programming language at Google in the early 2000s, its relationship the company’s cloud computing platform, and its eventual success as an open source project thanks to its robust standard libraries. This clip is taken from an interview conducted with Thompson by David Brock for the ACM and Computer History Museum on March 6, 2024 which is distributed here by permission of the Computer History Museum. Video of the full interview is available as part of Thompson’s ACM profile at https://amturing.acm.org/interviews/thompson_4588371.cfm.</description>
      <author> (Turing Awardee Clips)</author>
      <category>youtube</category>
      <guid>https://youtube.com/watch?v=NTrAISNdf70</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 11:01:57 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Was Daft Punk Having a Laugh When They Chose the Tempo of Harder, Better, Faster, Stronger?</title>
      <link>https://www.madebywindmill.com/tempi/blog/hbfs-bpm/</link>
      <description>Was Daft Punk Having a Laugh When They Chose the Tempo of Harder, Better, Faster, Stronger?</description>
      <category>youtube</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>sql</category>
      <guid>https://www.madebywindmill.com/tempi/blog/hbfs-bpm/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 03:02:05 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2026 will be my year of the Linux desktop</title>
      <link>https://xeiaso.net/notes/2026/year-linux-desktop/</link>
      <description>The meme will no longer be a dream.</description>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <category>linux</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <guid>https://xeiaso.net/notes/2026/year-linux-desktop/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 03:02:02 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conic Sections</title>
      <link>https://xkcd.com/3189/</link>
      <description></description>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <guid>https://xkcd.com/3189/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 02:02:17 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Clicks Communicator: the ultimate communciation companion</title>
      <link>https://www.clicksphone.com/en/communicator</link>
      <description>Clicks Communicator is phone purpose-built for taking action and communicating in a noisy world with deeper context, versatile input and greater control in a compact design.</description>
      <category>apple</category>
      <category>android</category>
      <guid>https://www.clicksphone.com/en/communicator</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 02:02:13 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Two-Week Experiment – Blue Lemon bits</title>
      <link>https://bluelemonbits.com/2026/01/02/from-macos-to-debian-a-two-week-experiment/</link>
      <description>After many years as a Mac user, the last couple of years I’ve become increasingly frustrated with the macOS software direction and the continuous erosion of the historically vibrant indie developer ecosystem.</description>
      <category>apple</category>
      <category>encryption</category>
      <category>cloud</category>
      <category>linux</category>
      <guid>https://bluelemonbits.com/2026/01/02/from-macos-to-debian-a-two-week-experiment/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 01:03:56 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Giving Your Agent Eyes is not Enough</title>
      <link>https://qckfx.com/blog/giving-your-agent-eyes-is-not-enough</link>
      <description>AI coding agents can build UI. But they can't verify it. Verification requires comparison—your agent doesn't remember anything.</description>
      <author> (Chris Wood)</author>
      <category>apple</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://qckfx.com/blog/giving-your-agent-eyes-is-not-enough</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 01:03:53 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigating and fixing a nasty clone bug</title>
      <link>https://kobzol.github.io/rust/2025/12/30/investigating-and-fixing-a-nasty-clone-bug.html</link>
      <description>Recently I found myself battling with another nasty bug. It took me several hours to understand what is happening, and once I found it, it turned out that the cause of the bug is relevant to the Ergonomic cloning initiative that is currently being discussed a lot. So I thought that it would be a good candidate for a blog post.</description>
      <category>rust</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <guid>https://kobzol.github.io/rust/2025/12/30/investigating-and-fixing-a-nasty-clone-bug.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 01:03:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Year of reading</title>
      <link>https://kg.dev/thoughts/year-of-reading</link>
      <description>2025 was the Year of Discomfort for me. I found myself getting too comfortable with various facets of life. I wasn’t pursuing or sticking with things that made me uncomfortable. I think, and have been told, this comes with age. It’s the same sort of discomfort you feel when you try to take a cold shower on the advice of The Whole Internet. It seems unnecessary. But being uncomfortable is actually good for you. When you venture deeper into the fractals of life, you’re going to feel some discomfort. It’s important to stray from the center.Looking back at the post I made exactly a year ago, I’m proud of the things I stuck with. It wasn’t everything that’s on the list, but a good amount. I even added a few that felt outside my personality. Before I talk about the theme for 2026, I want to share how 2025 went.Split KeyboardsI began the year by learning how to use a split keyboard. Mostly for ergonomics, but also because of the cool factor. This was one I intentionally didn’t stick with. I managed to get pretty quick at typing with a split keyboard, but I realized that the context switching between my laptop keyboard and my split keyboard slowed me down more than I’d like, so I stopped.VimI also learned Vim — one of the best decisions I’ve ever made. Learning Vim is incredibly uncomfortable. But after two to three months of consistency, I couldn’t imagine navigating around text on a computer in any other way. It’s a bit unsettling to think that every time I wanted to move my cursor around my code, I used to pick up my right hand and either move it down to the arrow keys or worse, reach for my mouse. If you’re a programmer, please go learn Vim.Typing AccuracyContinuing with the keyboard theme, I dramatically increased my typing speed and accuracy, yet another thing that was quite uncomfortable. I wasn’t a slow typer, but I wasn’t that fast either. Since the beginning of 2025, I’ve done several typing tests every week. Mostly, the focus has been accuracy, but I will switch gears and focus on speed every once in a while.I can consistently type entire paragraphs at around 110 words per minute with 100% accuracy. A year ago, I couldn’t even reach 100 words per minute, let alone exceed it with 100% accuracy. This progress took around 7,000 typing tests to achieve.--The above three were part of a sub-theme I was pursuing where I wanted to master my tools. I spend most of my day on a computer (perhaps you can relate). The keyboard that sits between my monitor and me is my primary tool. It’s my samurai sword. My chef’s knife. So, it made sense to put in a significant amount of time to master it.KickboxingI’ll start by saying that I failed at sticking with Jiu Jitsu. I took four classes and a bump to the back of the head was enough for me to call it quits. Maybe I’ll pick it back up one day, but I’m terrified of concussions so that will need to wait.Now, as for kickboxing, I think I’m in love. I took my first class in the first week of January and haven’t stopped since. Working your way up the belt ladder is an endless journey, but the path is a joyful one. I’m mostly focused on improving my skills and cardio. The belt will come to me when it’s ready.GymThis was the most consistent year I’ve had in the gym. Despite all the travel and a few bouts with a cold or the flu, I went at least twice a week, every week. I did a proper cut for once — where I went from 195lb to 165lb and achieved the best shape of my life. I’ve hit my protein intake goal pretty much every day of the year.This, I should note, is uncomfortable. I often didn’t want to do it, but that was the whole point of the theme for this year. I didn’t want to, but I did it anyway.AlcoholOn the last day of February, I had a really fun night out with friends. What followed was 3 really not-fun days. Working on a startup is hard enough, but it’s nearly impossible when you can’t even think because of a hangover. I decided to stop for two weeks. Those two weeks turned into a month. Then I talked to my friend who was doing a sobriety challenge for the whole year and decided to join him.Ten months later, and I haven’t been tempted to drink even once. At the one year mark, I will reintroduce alcohol in my life, but it will likely be one or two drinks a month.That was all 2025. For 2026, the theme will be Year of Reading. I’m surprised that I haven’t had this one as a theme before, so I’m excited to dedicate a whole year to reading anything and everything I can. Books, New Yorker articles, poems, essays — all of it.If you’re interested in seeing what I’m reading, follow/befriend me on Goodreads!2026 - Year of reading2025 - Year of discomfort2024 - Year of dedicated focus2023 - Year of leap of faith2022 - Year of travel</description>
      <guid>https://kg.dev/thoughts/year-of-reading</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 01:03:46 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why it matters - Jukka Niiranen blog</title>
      <link>https://jukkaniiranen.com/2026/01/why-it-matters/</link>
      <description>We don’t write just to deliver a payload of importance. We write to think. The sudden flood of "why it matters" formula in written content is not a positive sign for this.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://jukkaniiranen.com/2026/01/why-it-matters/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 01:03:42 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The CEO cost function</title>
      <link>https://carette.xyz/posts/automated_ceo/</link>
      <description>Looking for an Algorithmic Executive</description>
      <category>cloud</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>encryption</category>
      <guid>https://carette.xyz/posts/automated_ceo/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 01:03:35 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting Real With LLMs - Gilad Peleg</title>
      <link>https://www.giladpeleg.com/blog/getting-real-with-llms</link>
      <description>It's hard to tell from the internet what can one do with LLMs at their workplace. This blog tries to cover the current options and challenges</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>containers</category>
      <category>python</category>
      <guid>https://www.giladpeleg.com/blog/getting-real-with-llms</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 01:03:30 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Representing Hierarchies</title>
      <link>https://gpfault.net/posts/first-child-next-sibling.html</link>
      <description>published on Jan 01 2026</description>
      <category>nodejs</category>
      <category>web</category>
      <guid>https://gpfault.net/posts/first-child-next-sibling.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 01:03:27 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solving Agent Context Loss: A Beads + Claude Code Workflow for Large Features - JXØ</title>
      <link>https://jx0.ca/solving-agent-context-loss/</link>
      <description>How external task state with beads transformed my AI coding workflow from constant babysitting to autonomous execution of 17-task epics. Includes the complete skill set to replicate this workflow.</description>
      <author> (Jarred Kenny)</author>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <category>nodejs</category>
      <category>sql</category>
      <category>typescript</category>
      <guid>https://jx0.ca/solving-agent-context-loss/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 01:03:23 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rent a Mac M4 Mini and Access It via SSH from Linux</title>
      <link>https://www.vincentschmalbach.com/rent-a-mac-m4-mini-and-access-it-via-ssh-from-linux/</link>
      <description>I needed a Mac to run a Laravel test suite. On my ThinkPad T15g with Docker, the tests took so long I gave up after 2 hours. My client said it takes 5 minutes on their M4 Mac. I decided to rent one…</description>
      <category>apple</category>
      <category>sql</category>
      <category>linux</category>
      <category>containers</category>
      <guid>https://www.vincentschmalbach.com/rent-a-mac-m4-mini-and-access-it-via-ssh-from-linux/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 01:03:20 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I switched away from Zig to C3</title>
      <link>https://lowbytefox.dev/blog/from-zig-to-c3/</link>
      <description>LowByteFox's Personal Website</description>
      <category>rust</category>
      <guid>https://lowbytefox.dev/blog/from-zig-to-c3/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 01:03:15 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Next Thing Will Not Be Big</title>
      <link>https://blog.glyph.im/2026/01/the-next-thing-will-not-be-big.html</link>
      <description>Disruption, too, will be disrupted.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <category>linux</category>
      <category>containers</category>
      <category>apple</category>
      <guid>https://blog.glyph.im/2026/01/the-next-thing-will-not-be-big.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 01:03:11 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vibe coding killed Cursor</title>
      <link>https://ischemist.com/writings/long-form/how-vibe-coding-killed-cursor</link>
      <description>Cursor is dying because cost-optimization forces models into tunnel vision. RAG agents fail because they only see what they search for. The superior workflow for 2026 is massive context windows (gemini 2.5 pro) and manual control. Stop letting agents hide code from the model.</description>
      <author> (Anton Morgunov)</author>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>python</category>
      <guid>https://ischemist.com/writings/long-form/how-vibe-coding-killed-cursor</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 01:03:08 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Common prefix skipping, adaptive sort</title>
      <link>http://smalldatum.blogspot.com/2026/01/common-prefix-skipping-adaptive-sort.html</link>
      <description>The patent expired for US7680791B2 . I invented this while at Oracle and it landed in 10gR2  with claims of ~5X better performance vs the pr...</description>
      <category>sql</category>
      <category>apple</category>
      <category>vscode</category>
      <category>linux</category>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <guid>http://smalldatum.blogspot.com/2026/01/common-prefix-skipping-adaptive-sort.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 01:03:04 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An experiment in vibe coding</title>
      <link>https://nolanlawson.com/2025/12/28/an-experiment-in-vibe-coding/</link>
      <description>For the holidays, I gave myself a little experiment: build a small web app for my wife to manage her travel itineraries. I challenged myself to avoid editing the code myself and just do it “v…</description>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <category>web</category>
      <category>sql</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://nolanlawson.com/2025/12/28/an-experiment-in-vibe-coding/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 01:03:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Try to Take My Position: The Best Promotion Advice I Ever Got</title>
      <link>https://andrew.grahamyooll.com/blog/Try-to-Take-My-Position/</link>
      <description>Published on 2026-01-02 by Andrew Graham-Yooll</description>
      <guid>https://andrew.grahamyooll.com/blog/Try-to-Take-My-Position/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 01:02:56 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Web to Native: Building Apps with SvelteKit &amp; Capacitor</title>
      <link>https://bryanhogan.com/blog/web-to-app-sveltekit-capacitor</link>
      <description>A step-by-step tutorial on integrating CapacitorJS with SvelteKit. Convert your website into an Android/iOS app.</description>
      <category>android</category>
      <category>visualstudio</category>
      <category>apple</category>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <category>nodejs</category>
      <guid>https://bryanhogan.com/blog/web-to-app-sveltekit-capacitor</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 01:02:53 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dimensions: A Terminal Tab Manager</title>
      <link>https://karlvmuller.com/posts/dimensions/</link>
      <description>An interactive terminal tool that keeps tmux tabs organized into focused workspaces.</description>
      <category>rust</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://karlvmuller.com/posts/dimensions/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 01:02:50 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why are weather forecasting sites so bad?</title>
      <link>https://blog.engora.com/2025/12/why-is-weather-forecasting-so-bad.html</link>
      <description>How AI and generative AI is disruptive for consumer weather forecasting services. </description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <guid>https://blog.engora.com/2025/12/why-is-weather-forecasting-so-bad.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 01:02:46 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What I Actually Want To Say in Tech Interviews</title>
      <link>https://nelson.cloud/what-i-actually-want-to-say-in-tech-interviews/</link>
      <description>Honest answers to common interview questions in the tech field.</description>
      <guid>https://nelson.cloud/what-i-actually-want-to-say-in-tech-interviews/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 01:02:43 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Socialist Now Runs New York: What History Predicts</title>
      <link>https://zcashexplained.com/blog/new-york-voted-socialist/</link>
      <description>NYC elected socialist Zohran Mamdani as mayor in 2025. Now sworn in, historical patterns show why societies turn to socialism and what the real solution is.</description>
      <author> (Anonymous)</author>
      <category>encryption</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://zcashexplained.com/blog/new-york-voted-socialist/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 01:02:39 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Developer Is Dead, Long Live the Designer</title>
      <link>https://deadend.dev/posts/the-developer-is-dead-long-live-the-designer/</link>
      <description>With the advent of coding agents and their improvement, developing software as we have been doing it is, at least in many fields, already going the way of the Dodo. But bear with me for a second while I try to explain why I think this is great for developers and I am not actually trying to doom-bait.
It was never about just typing the code This is now cliché, but also the crux of the matter. A year into working on a side project like it’s my job, and having made wide use of AI coding agents, I can say I was surprised by the perspective shift this allowed for me.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <guid>https://deadend.dev/posts/the-developer-is-dead-long-live-the-designer/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 01:02:35 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My setup, and why tmux workflow is better than ever | Raine Virta</title>
      <link>https://raine.dev/blog/my-tmux-setup/</link>
      <description>Keybindings, popup tools, and workflows for a terminal-centric setup</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <guid>https://raine.dev/blog/my-tmux-setup/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 01:02:32 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Was it really a Billion Dollar Mistake?</title>
      <link>https://www.gingerbill.org/article/2026/01/02/was-it-really-a-billion-dollar-mistake/</link>
      <description>TL;DR null pointer dereferences are empirically the easiest class of invalid memory addresses to catch at runtime, and are the least common kind of invalid memory addresses that happen in memory unsafe languages. The trivial solutions to remove the “problem” null pointers have numerous trade-offs which are not obvious, and the cause of why people think it is a “problem” comes from a specific kind of individual-element mindset.
Most people have probably heard of the Billion Dollar Mistake before, which was coined/invented by Tony Hoare: the inventor of null references/pointers.</description>
      <category>rust</category>
      <guid>https://www.gingerbill.org/article/2026/01/02/was-it-really-a-billion-dollar-mistake/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 01:02:28 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MCP works great — until you actually ship.</title>
      <link>https://www.kernl.sh/blog/dont-use-mcp</link>
      <description>Why MCP isn't ready for production agents, and what to do instead.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>python</category>
      <category>typescript</category>
      <guid>https://www.kernl.sh/blog/dont-use-mcp</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 01:02:24 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>POSSE</title>
      <link>https://indieweb.org/POSSE</link>
      <description>POSSE is an abbreviation for Publish (on your) Own Site, Syndicate Elsewhere, the practice of posting content on your own site first, then publishing copies or sharing links to third parties (like social media silos) with original post links to provide viewers a path to directly interacting with your content.</description>
      <category>conference</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <category>python</category>
      <guid>https://indieweb.org/POSSE</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 00:02:17 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We Should Call Them Macroservices</title>
      <link>https://idiallo.com/blog/whe-should-call-them-macroservices?src=feed</link>
      <description>I love the idea of microservices. When there's a problem on your website, you don't need to fix and redeploy your entire codebase. If the issue only affects your authentication service, you can deploy</description>
      <category>sql</category>
      <guid>https://idiallo.com/blog/whe-should-call-them-macroservices?src=feed</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 23:02:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Let users zoom in on mobile devices</title>
      <link>https://idiallo.com/blog/let-user-zoom-in-on-mobile?src=feed</link>
      <description>This is a bit of a rant. Maybe my eyes are not as good as they used to be. When I read an article that has pictures on them, I like to zoom in to see the details. You might think this makes no sense, </description>
      <category>web</category>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <guid>https://idiallo.com/blog/let-user-zoom-in-on-mobile?src=feed</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 23:02:56 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why my redirect rules from 2013 still work and yours don't</title>
      <link>https://idiallo.com/blog/my-redirect-rules-from-2013-still-work?src=feed</link>
      <description>Here is something that makes me proud of my blog. The redirect rule I wrote for my very first article 12 years ago still works! This blog was an experiment. When I designed it, my intention was to try</description>
      <category>sql</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <category>web</category>
      <guid>https://idiallo.com/blog/my-redirect-rules-from-2013-still-work?src=feed</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 23:02:52 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Natural Path to Gamblification</title>
      <link>https://idiallo.com/blog/a-natural-path-to-gamblification?src=feed</link>
      <description>I had a 383-day streak on Duolingo. Three hundred and eighty-three days of that green owl peeking through my notifications, reminding me that my streak was in danger. I wrote about how I never actuall</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>encryption</category>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <guid>https://idiallo.com/blog/a-natural-path-to-gamblification?src=feed</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 23:02:48 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>All AI Videos Are Harmful</title>
      <link>https://idiallo.com/blog/all-ai-videos-are-harmful?src=feed</link>
      <description>When OpenAI released the first version of Sora, I was excited. For years, I'd had this short story sitting on my hard drive, something I'd written long ago and always dreamed of bringing to life as a </description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>youtube</category>
      <guid>https://idiallo.com/blog/all-ai-videos-are-harmful?src=feed</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 23:02:43 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We have all we need to make mass surveillance a reality</title>
      <link>https://idiallo.com/blog/we-have-all-we-need-for-mass-surveillance?src=feed</link>
      <description>I was watching a movie when I got a random notification from Google Maps on my phone. I never get notifications from this app unless I'm doing turn-by-turn navigation. This one was titled "Timeline," </description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>nodejs</category>
      <guid>https://idiallo.com/blog/we-have-all-we-need-for-mass-surveillance?src=feed</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 23:02:39 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poor Man's Productivity Trick</title>
      <link>https://idiallo.com/blog/poormans-productivity-trick?src=feed</link>
      <description>Have you ever joined a large organization? One with a quarter million employees? Their process is fascinating. You receive hundreds of emails to set up different software. You get a machine mailed to </description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://idiallo.com/blog/poormans-productivity-trick?src=feed</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 23:02:35 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do I Leave the Laptop at the Office?</title>
      <link>https://idiallo.com/blog/do-i-leave-the-laptop-in-the-office?src=feed</link>
      <description>A few years back, I worked at an AI startup as the first hired engineer. All of us could fit in a four-space cubicle, sharing an office with multiple startups. As you can imagine, when you're trying t</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://idiallo.com/blog/do-i-leave-the-laptop-in-the-office?src=feed</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 23:02:31 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paying for the rides I took 8 years ago</title>
      <link>https://idiallo.com/blog/paying-for-my-8-years-old-ride?src=feed</link>
      <description>What does it mean when we say that investors are subsidizing the price of a service? We often hear that ChatGPT is not profitable, despite some users paying $20 a month, or others up to $200 a month. </description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://idiallo.com/blog/paying-for-my-8-years-old-ride?src=feed</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 23:02:27 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Blogging Dead?</title>
      <link>https://idiallo.com/blog/what-its-like-blogging-in-2025?src=feed</link>
      <description>When I started 2025, I set myself a simple challenge: write consistently and see if I could reclaim some of the audience this blog once had. In 2024, I had published just 4 posts and had only a handfu</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>android</category>
      <guid>https://idiallo.com/blog/what-its-like-blogging-in-2025?src=feed</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 23:02:23 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>