<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-16"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://linksfor.dev/feed.xml" />
    <title>linksfor.dev(s)</title>
    <link>https://linksfor.dev/feed.xml</link>
    <description>Curated links for devs</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>comma.ai — make driving chill</title>
      <link>https://comma.ai/</link>
      <description>An AI upgrade for your car</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://comma.ai/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 08:02:02 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unrolling the Codex agent loop</title>
      <link>https://openai.com/index/unrolling-the-codex-agent-loop/</link>
      <description>By Michael Bolin, Member of the Technical Staff</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <guid>https://openai.com/index/unrolling-the-codex-agent-loop/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 05:02:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gas Town’s Agent Patterns, Design Bottlenecks, and Vibecoding at Scale</title>
      <link>https://maggieappleton.com/gastown</link>
      <description>On agent orchestration patterns, why design and critical thinking are the new bottlenecks, and whether we should let go of looking at code</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <category>cloud</category>
      <guid>https://maggieappleton.com/gastown</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 02:01:56 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Double-Pronged Extension Cord</title>
      <link>https://xkcd.com/3198/</link>
      <description></description>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <guid>https://xkcd.com/3198/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 02:01:53 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Forecasting the death of StackOverflow</title>
      <link>https://blog.qwertyforce.dev/posts/forecast_stackoverflow_death</link>
      <description>You've probably seen the news: StackOverflow is almost dead

If nothing extraordinary happens, the site's run is basically over and it may end up as one of the first high-profile casualties of the LLM era.
The only real question is when.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://blog.qwertyforce.dev/posts/forecast_stackoverflow_death</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 01:05:37 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interacting with Developers on Reddit</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2026/01/23/interacting-with-developers-on-reddit/</link>
      <description></description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2026/01/23/interacting-with-developers-on-reddit/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 01:05:31 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How dedication can change the magic of music</title>
      <link>https://www.samueland.dev/blog/2026-01-23-how-dedication-changes</link>
      <description>Crafted with care</description>
      <guid>https://www.samueland.dev/blog/2026-01-23-how-dedication-changes</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 01:05:26 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You might not need a sync server for real-time collaboration</title>
      <link>https://www.kevinmake.com/writings/p2p-realtime-collaboration</link>
      <description>Lessons from building multiplayer games.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <guid>https://www.kevinmake.com/writings/p2p-realtime-collaboration</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 01:05:23 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Build a Social Network as an Adult - Thomas Unise</title>
      <link>https://thomasunise.com/how-to-build-a-social-network-as-an-adult/</link>
      <description>Making friends as an adult is a problem nobody prepares you for. So here is a strategy no one seems to talk about. When you’re young, friendships happen automatically due...</description>
      <guid>https://thomasunise.com/how-to-build-a-social-network-as-an-adult/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 01:05:17 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We have to re-learn to walk alone</title>
      <link>https://blog.julik.nl/2026/01/go-fast-and-go-alone</link>
      <description>Reading the article about Nexus that Obie has posted I got absolutely struck. Yes, it can be said without a shade of doubt that the modern way of building software, the late-2025-way with Opus 4.5 in the picture, is markedly different from the one we operated in for the last decade (or more). I haven’t been sitting on my hands either. One of my smaller pursuits, now that I am a proud self-employed raconteur, has been moneymaker - a piece of kit I wanted for all the business aspects of the said raconteurship. Think: basic accounting bank statements and balances invoicing time tracking …all of that - across several projects, clients and managing entities And, out of principle, I’ve decided to take my chances and release the reins - let the models “drive” the application much more than I did in the past 6 months or so. Because it is important to learn, first and foremost - how to care less about code. And my experience has not been dissimilar from what Obie describes, with a few important differences. But what struck me much stronger is how other humans fit into this. Let me explain. If you squint, you will notice one element missing from Obie’s story: other team members.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>nodejs</category>
      <category>cloud</category>
      <category>typescript</category>
      <guid>https://blog.julik.nl/2026/01/go-fast-and-go-alone</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 01:05:12 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Uncomfortable Math of Working for Yourself - Thomas Unise</title>
      <link>https://thomasunise.com/the-uncomfortable-math-of-working-for-yourself/</link>
      <description>Nobody Tells You Freedom Has a Billing Rate This year in 2026, I turn 40. I’ve been self-employed since I was 25. That’s fifteen years of answering to no one,...</description>
      <guid>https://thomasunise.com/the-uncomfortable-math-of-working-for-yourself/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 01:05:08 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Backseat Software – Mike Swanson's Blog</title>
      <link>https://blog.mikeswanson.com/backseat-software/</link>
      <description>What if your car worked like so many apps? You’re driving somewhere important…maybe running a little bit late. A few minutes into the drive, your car pulls over to the side of the road and asks:</description>
      <category>android</category>
      <category>apple</category>
      <guid>https://blog.mikeswanson.com/backseat-software/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 01:05:04 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Better Practices Guide to Using Claude Code</title>
      <link>https://kylestratis.com/posts/a-better-practices-guide-to-using-claude-code/</link>
      <description>A comprehensive guide to getting the most out of Claude Code</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>nodejs</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <category>typescript</category>
      <guid>https://kylestratis.com/posts/a-better-practices-guide-to-using-claude-code/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 01:04:33 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>make an ideal man | enombic</title>
      <link>https://enombic.com/make-an-ideal-man</link>
      <description>observe the ideal, then do the practical things.</description>
      <guid>https://enombic.com/make-an-ideal-man</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 01:04:29 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Futureproofing Tines: Partitioning a 17TB table in PostgreSQL | Tines</title>
      <link>https://www.tines.com/blog/futureproofing-tines-partitioning-a-17tb-table-in-postgresql/</link>
      <description></description>
      <category>sql</category>
      <category>ruby</category>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <category>vscode</category>
      <category>cloud</category>
      <guid>https://www.tines.com/blog/futureproofing-tines-partitioning-a-17tb-table-in-postgresql/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 01:04:25 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Think About Self-Attention Intuitively</title>
      <link>https://www.henrydashwood.com/posts/attention-intuition</link>
      <description>An example of how to think about self-attention in an intuitive way</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://www.henrydashwood.com/posts/attention-intuition</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 01:04:17 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AGENTS.md as a dark signal</title>
      <link>https://joshmock.com/post/2026-agents-md-as-a-dark-signal/</link>
      <description>Is an AGENTS.md or CLAUDE.md file in a repo a sign of possibly poor code quality?</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://joshmock.com/post/2026-agents-md-as-a-dark-signal/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 01:04:14 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Claude Code is a Footgun — Jonathon Ready</title>
      <link>https://jonready.com/blog/posts/claude-code-is-a-footgun.html</link>
      <description>How agentic coding tools can build impressive features while making your codebase incomprehensible.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>web</category>
      <guid>https://jonready.com/blog/posts/claude-code-is-a-footgun.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 01:04:06 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I found the perfect yearly calendar (for me)</title>
      <link>https://blog.notmyhostna.me/posts/i-found-the-perfect-yearly-calendar-for-me</link>
      <description>The new year has started and I was once again looking for a simple calendar to do some yearly planning. I've tried to find something for this use …</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>apple</category>
      <guid>https://blog.notmyhostna.me/posts/i-found-the-perfect-yearly-calendar-for-me</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 01:04:03 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Long View of History</title>
      <link>https://brianschrader.com/archive/the-long-view-of-history/</link>
      <description>History as a subject is often viewed by students and the public at large as a domain without a use, a pedantic study of dates and names with some vague mission to remember the past—a memorial to ages past but neither a forward-looking or useful endeavor. The study of history produces teachers of history and nothing more. And while the study of history does not produce new widgets or novel computer advances, and nor does it deepen our understanding of materials science or physics.</description>
      <guid>https://brianschrader.com/archive/the-long-view-of-history/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 01:03:54 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Third Conversational Pattern in BDD</title>
      <link>https://lizkeogh.com/2026/01/23/a-third-conversational-pattern-in-bdd/</link>
      <description>It’s been a moment! COVID disrupted a lot of things, not least my writing. More recently I’ve been busy with my new employment with the amazing Assent, focusing on sustainability in man…</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://lizkeogh.com/2026/01/23/a-third-conversational-pattern-in-bdd/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 01:03:50 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Future of Software Teams in a Claude Code World</title>
      <link>https://chbigelow.com/blog/the-future-of-software-product-engineering/</link>
      <description>How AI is changing software team structures: from specialists to product engineers, full stack builders, and small teams that ship faster. What's happening now and predictions for the future.</description>
      <author> (Chris Bigelow)</author>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://chbigelow.com/blog/the-future-of-software-product-engineering/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 01:03:46 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Spent 3 Years Chasing Backlinks the Wrong Way. Heres What Actually Works in 2026. | serpsherpa</title>
      <link>https://webmatrices.com/post/i-spent-3-years-chasing-backlinks-the-wrong-way-heres-what-actually-works-in-2026</link>
      <description>I'll be honest with you.For the first two years of running my sites, I thought backlinks were this magical thing that would fix all my ranking problems. I bought courses. I sent hundreds of outreach emails. I even paid for a few link packages that promised "high DA" placements.Most of it was a complete waste of money.It wasn't until I started talking to actual SEO practitioners, people running real businesses and agencies, that I realized how backwards my approach was. The advice floating around online is either outdated, oversimplified, or designed to sell you something.So I spent the last few months collecting insights from link builders, agency owners, and solo SEOs who actually do this work every day. Combined with the latest industry research, heres what I wish someone had told me three years ago.The stat that changes everythingBefore we get into tactics, you need to understand the landscape youre operating in.94% of all online content receives zero external backlinks.Thats not my number. Thats from a Backlinko study analyzing millions of web pages. Only 2.2% of content gets links from more than one website.When I first saw this, I felt two things. First, relief, because maybe I wasn't as bad at this as I thought. Second, frustration, because it means the game is fundamentally harder than most people admit.The SEO industry talks about link building like its just another checkbox. "Create great content and the links will come." Thats technically true... for 6% of content. The other 94% needs a different strategy.The "3 Bs" framework that actually makes senseOne experienced link builder I talked to put it simply:"You either buy them, beg for them, or build them yourself. Every link strategy falls into one of those three buckets."Buying is exactly what it sounds like. Theres an entire marketplace ecosystem, some legitimate, some not. The average cost of a paid backlink is $361 according to Search Endurance data. High-quality contextual links? $700 to $2,000 per link. Some agencies report spending $1,500 average per earned link from outreach campaigns.Begging is outreach. Guest post pitches. HARO responses. "Would you consider linking to my resource?" emails. Its slow and the success rate is brutal. Only 8.5% of cold outreach emails generate backlinks. But personalized outreach increases success by 50%, so theres room to improve.Building means creating assets so valuable that people link naturally. Or building your own network of sites. Or turning customers into link sources through reviews and testimonials.The practitioners I respect most lean heavily toward begging and building. The ones trying to sell you something push buying.The metric everyone obsesses over (that experts ignore)DA. DR. Domain Authority. Domain Rating.If youre new to SEO, these third-party metrics probably dominate your thinking. Higher number = better link, right?Heres what surprised me: only 28.99% of experienced link builders rely on DA/DR metrics. Compare that to 51.39% of beginners who use them as their primary quality indicator.The experts I talked to said the same thing different ways:"Forget about DA and DR. Focus on whether the site has actual traffic.""Pages that dont rank dont pass authority. A DR 70 site with zero organic traffic is worthless.""The only metric that matters is: would real humans click this link?"This tracks with what Google has said publicly. John Mueller has confirmed that Google ignores links from pages that dont get traffic. That "high DA" Medium article? Zero authority. LinkedIn posts? Nofollow and ignored. Guest posts on sites that exist purely to sell guest posts? Spam.The test is simple: would this link exist if Google didnt?If the answer is no, its probably not worth pursuing.What the data says actually worksAfter cross-referencing practitioner insights with multiple industry studies, these strategies showed up consistently:Digital PR (48.6% of experts call it most effective)A 2025 survey of 518 SEO professionals found that Digital PR is now considered the most effective link building tactic, beating guest posting by 3x.What this looks like in practice:Create original research or data studiesPitch journalists through platforms like HARO, Qwoted, Featured, or Source of SourcesRespond to reporter queries with genuine expertiseOne caveat multiple practitioners mentioned: "If you use AI to write your responses, they can tell and you wont get selected."Guest posting (still works, but differently)Guest posting came in second at 16% effectiveness rating. But theres a catch.The practitioners who succeed with guest posting arent targeting "write for us" pages. Theyre building relationships with editors at real publications in their niche. They pitch specific, valuable angles, not generic "I can write about anything" emails.The average success rate for guest post pitches is 5-10%, compared to 2-3% for general outreach.Linkable assets (the long game)Creating content people actually want to reference. Calculators. Original data. Industry tools. Comprehensive guides.Content over 3,000 words gets 3.5x more backlinks than shorter articles. Posts with more than three videos attract 55% more backlinks. "Why" and "What" posts get 25.8% more links than "how to" posts.One agency owner told me they couldnt get links for their automotive clients no matter what they tried. So they started their own automotive blog to link from. Thats the level of commitment this takes.Competitor backlink auditsRun your competitors through Ahrefs or SEMrush. See who links to them. Reach out with something better.74.3% of marketers use Ahrefs as their primary link building tool. But multiple practitioners warned me: dont just copy competitor backlinks blindly. Check if those linking sites have actual traffic first.Unlinked brand mentionsIf someone mentions your brand but doesnt link, ask them to add the link. Multiple practitioners said this works surprisingly well with minimal effort.The uncomfortable truth about buying linksI need to address this directly because 74.3% of link builders pay for links in some form.The warnings I heard repeatedly:"Links from freelancers get removed in 2-4 months.""Most providers are just reselling the same private blog lists.""Avoid anyone who leads with DA scores. Thats a red flag."91.89% of SEO professionals believe their competitors buy links. So its clearly happening at scale. But the practitioners who do it successfully follow specific rules:Test small before committing to packagesUse marketplaces with monitoring and replacement guaranteesVerify the site has actual organic traffic, not just high metricsCheck outbound link density (too many = spam)The cost is going up too. 41% of SEOs expect link acquisition costs to increase further as competition intensifies.Link exchanges: dead or alive?I got conflicting answers on this one.Some practitioners called link exchanges "a tactic from 20 years ago, before the Penguin update." Others swore by them for building their businesses.The difference comes down to context.Dead: Random A-links-to-B, B-links-to-A exchanges that Google can easily detect.Alive: A jewelry site linking to a wedding planning site because their audiences genuinely overlap. A spa putting brochures at a hotel front desk, as one person described it.One practitioner put it perfectly:"Exchanging backlinks is about relationship building. I exchanged links with people in similar niches and similar locations. It doesnt matter what their DA is. What matters is whether people looking for engagement rings are also looking for wedding information."The test again: would this link make sense even if search engines didnt exist?The timeline nobody talks aboutHeres something that wouldve saved me a lot of frustration early on.It takes an average of 3.1 months for links to show their impact on rankings.46.6% of link builders see results within 1-3 months. But that means over half wait longer. Some practitioners told me they budget 6+ months before expecting significant movement.This is why the "quick wins" link building services sell rarely deliver. By the time you realize the links didnt work, theyre already onto the next client.What Im doing differently nowAfter everything Ive learned, heres how my approach has changed:I stopped looking at DA. I check if sites have actual organic traffic instead. Takes an extra step but filters out garbage.I stopped expecting quick results. The people building real sites think in timelines of months and years, not weeks.I started thinking about relationships instead of transactions. Every link should make sense even if Google disappeared tomorrow.I accepted this is slow. As one practitioner told me: "You get a lot of nos. You just keep grinding."I invest in content worth linking to. Original research. Data studies. Tools. Things that provide genuine value.I use outreach strategically, not desperately. Personalized emails to relevant contacts, not mass blasts to anyone with a website.The bottom lineLink building in 2026 isnt dead. But its harder, slower, and more expensive than most people admit.The practitioners who succeed share common traits: patience, relationship focus, quality over quantity, and a willingness to create genuinely useful content.The ones who fail are usually chasing shortcuts, whether thats cheap link packages, AI-generated outreach, or gaming metrics that Google has learned to ignore.94% of content gets zero links. If you want to be in the other 6%, you need a strategy thats built for the long game.Slow and boring beats fast and spammy. Every time.#CaseStudy #SEO #BackLink</description>
      <author> (serpsherpa)</author>
      <category>rust</category>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://webmatrices.com/post/i-spent-3-years-chasing-backlinks-the-wrong-way-heres-what-actually-works-in-2026</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 01:03:42 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Downloading a podcast to create an audiobook</title>
      <link>https://kevinboone.me/clh_podcast_to_audiobook.html</link>
      <description>If a podcast has an RSS feed, we can download it, parse it, and then   download all the content into a single folder, which can then   be played by any audio player.</description>
      <category>linux</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <guid>https://kevinboone.me/clh_podcast_to_audiobook.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 01:03:38 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Avoiding Duplicate Objects in Django Querysets</title>
      <link>https://johnnymetz.com/posts/avoiding-duplicate-objects-in-django-querysets/</link>
      <description>When filtering Django querysets across relationships, you can easily end up with duplicate objects in your results. This is a common gotcha that happens with both one-to-many (1:N) and many-to-many (N:N) relationships. Let’s explore why this happens and the best way to avoid it.
The Problem When you filter a queryset by traversing a relationship, Django performs a SQL JOIN. If a parent object has multiple related objects that match your filter, the parent object appears multiple times in the result set.</description>
      <category>python</category>
      <category>sql</category>
      <guid>https://johnnymetz.com/posts/avoiding-duplicate-objects-in-django-querysets/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 01:03:35 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Time Management for Anarchists</title>
      <link>https://jimmunroe.net/comics/pamphlets/time_management_for_anarchists/time_management_for_anarchists.html</link>
      <description>I did a seminar at Canzine, a zine fair in Toronto. It focused on the paradoxical notion that if you want to live without bosses, you have to be self-disciplined. I attribute my productivity to bei…</description>
      <guid>https://jimmunroe.net/comics/pamphlets/time_management_for_anarchists/time_management_for_anarchists.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 01:03:32 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I estimate work as a staff software engineer</title>
      <link>https://www.seangoedecke.com/how-i-estimate-work/</link>
      <description>There’s a kind of polite fiction at the heart of the software industry. It goes something like this:</description>
      <guid>https://www.seangoedecke.com/how-i-estimate-work/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 00:02:04 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tesla kills Autopilot, locks lane-keeping behind $99/month fee</title>
      <link>https://arstechnica.com/cars/2026/01/tesla-wants-recurring-revenue-discontinues-autopilot-in-favor-of-fsd/</link>
      <description>With falling sales and shrinking profits, the recurring revenue will be most welcome.</description>
      <category>android</category>
      <guid>https://arstechnica.com/cars/2026/01/tesla-wants-recurring-revenue-discontinues-autopilot-in-favor-of-fsd/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 00:02:01 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can AI grow corn?</title>
      <link>https://proofofcorn.com/</link>
      <description>@fredwilson challenged @seth: AI can write code, but it can't affect the physical world. This is our response.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://proofofcorn.com/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 22:02:14 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Overrun with AI slop, cURL scraps bug bounties to ensure "intact mental health"</title>
      <link>https://arstechnica.com/security/2026/01/overrun-with-ai-slop-curl-scraps-bug-bounties-to-ensure-intact-mental-health/</link>
      <description>The onslaught includes LLMs finding bogus vulnerabilities and code that won't compile.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>linux</category>
      <guid>https://arstechnica.com/security/2026/01/overrun-with-ai-slop-curl-scraps-bug-bounties-to-ensure-intact-mental-health/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 22:02:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Announcing winapp, the Windows App Development CLI</title>
      <link>https://blogs.windows.com/windowsdeveloper/2026/01/22/announcing-winapp-the-windows-app-development-cli/</link>
      <description>We are excited to announce the public preview of the Windows App Development CLI (winapp), a new open-source c</description>
      <category>nodejs</category>
      <category>rust</category>
      <category>visualstudio</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <guid>https://blogs.windows.com/windowsdeveloper/2026/01/22/announcing-winapp-the-windows-app-development-cli/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 17:02:20 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Connect to ANY Computer from ANYwhere!  The Comet Pro Remote KVM</title>
      <link>https://youtube.com/watch?v=Y1WJv6Udcms</link>
      <description>Dave reviews and explains the GL.iNet Comet Pro Remote KVM which allows you to remotely connect to any PC or device that has HDMI and USB.

Comet Pro: 
https://link.gl-inet.com/rm10-davesgarage-260123

This episode is sponsored in part by GL.iNet, but as always, episode sponsors do not get editorial input, control, or advance showing.</description>
      <author> (Dave's Garage)</author>
      <category>youtube</category>
      <guid>https://youtube.com/watch?v=Y1WJv6Udcms</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 16:02:07 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Proton Spam and the AI Consent Problem</title>
      <link>https://dbushell.com/2026/01/22/proton-spam/</link>
      <description>The one where I get very annoyed with my email provider</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <guid>https://dbushell.com/2026/01/22/proton-spam/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 14:02:19 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I built a light that can see radio waves</title>
      <link>https://youtube.com/watch?v=moBCOEiqiPs</link>
      <description>Spectrum Slit, rootkid (2026)

About: https://rootkid.me/works/spectrum-slit

Music: Uranium - Radioactive Man</description>
      <author> (Rootkid)</author>
      <category>youtube</category>
      <guid>https://youtube.com/watch?v=moBCOEiqiPs</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 14:02:14 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ghostty/AI_POLICY.md at main · ghostty-org/ghostty</title>
      <link>https://github.com/ghostty-org/ghostty/blob/main/AI_POLICY.md</link>
      <description>👻 Ghostty is a fast, feature-rich, and cross-platform terminal emulator that uses platform-native UI and GPU acceleration. - ghostty-org/ghostty</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://github.com/ghostty-org/ghostty/blob/main/AI_POLICY.md</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 14:02:13 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>