<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-16"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://linksfor.dev/feed.xml" />
    <title>linksfor.dev(s)</title>
    <link>https://linksfor.dev/feed.xml</link>
    <description>Curated links for devs</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>Langjam Gamejam</title>
      <link>https://langjamgamejam.com/</link>
      <description>A 7-day challenge to create a programming language and then use it to build a game.</description>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <guid>https://langjamgamejam.com/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 19:02:02 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>System 7 natively boots on the Mac mini G4!</title>
      <link>https://macos9lives.com/smforum/index.php?topic=7711.0</link>
      <description>System 7 natively boots on the Mac mini G4!</description>
      <category>apple</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <category>python</category>
      <guid>https://macos9lives.com/smforum/index.php?topic=7711.0</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 16:02:32 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leak confirms OpenAI is preparing ads on ChatGPT for public roll out</title>
      <link>https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/artificial-intelligence/leak-confirms-openai-is-preparing-ads-on-chatgpt-for-public-roll-out/</link>
      <description>OpenAI is now internally testing 'ads' inside ChatGPT that could redefine the web economy.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>android</category>
      <guid>https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/artificial-intelligence/leak-confirms-openai-is-preparing-ads-on-chatgpt-for-public-roll-out/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 15:02:01 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Confessions of a Software Developer: No More Self-Censorship - Kerrick Long (blog)</title>
      <link>https://kerrick.blog/articles/2025/confessions-of-a-software-developer-no-more-self-censorship/</link>
      <description>I haven't published since April because I've been afraid. What was I afraid of? In this post I detail every single thing I've avoided admitting on this blog.</description>
      <category>ruby</category>
      <category>dotnet</category>
      <category>sql</category>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <guid>https://kerrick.blog/articles/2025/confessions-of-a-software-developer-no-more-self-censorship/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 13:02:03 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Airbus update on A320 Family precautionary fleet action</title>
      <link>https://www.airbus.com/en/newsroom/press-releases/2025-11-airbus-update-on-a320-family-precautionary-fleet-action</link>
      <description>Analysis of a recent event involving an A320 Family aircraft has revealed that intense solar radiation may corrupt data critical. Read more.</description>
      <author> (https://www.facebook.com/airbus)</author>
      <guid>https://www.airbus.com/en/newsroom/press-releases/2025-11-airbus-update-on-a320-family-precautionary-fleet-action</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 08:01:58 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>So you wanna build a local RAG?</title>
      <link>https://blog.yakkomajuri.com/blog/local-rag</link>
      <description>November 26, 2025</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>sql</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <guid>https://blog.yakkomajuri.com/blog/local-rag</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 07:01:58 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How good engineers write bad code at big companies</title>
      <link>https://www.seangoedecke.com/bad-code-at-big-companies/</link>
      <description>--</description>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <category>sql</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://www.seangoedecke.com/bad-code-at-big-companies/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 04:02:12 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molly</title>
      <link>https://molly.im/</link>
      <description>Molly is an improved Signal app for Android</description>
      <category>encryption</category>
      <category>sql</category>
      <guid>https://molly.im/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 04:02:09 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Dutch universities do without Microsoft?</title>
      <link>https://dub.uu.nl/en/news/can-dutch-universities-do-without-microsoft</link>
      <description>Can Dutch higher education part ways with Microsoft? The sector is trying to break free, and alternatives are being explored here and there. At the same time, more and more tasks are being completed by Microsoft tools.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://dub.uu.nl/en/news/can-dutch-universities-do-without-microsoft</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 02:02:05 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Imgur Geo-Blocked the UK, So I Geo-Unblocked My Entire Network</title>
      <link>https://blog.tymscar.com/posts/imgurukproxy/</link>
      <description>Imgur started blocking UK users. Rather than installing a VPN on every device, I set up a network-wide proxy that tunnels Imgur traffic through a VPN automatically.</description>
      <category>containers</category>
      <category>conference</category>
      <guid>https://blog.tymscar.com/posts/imgurukproxy/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 01:02:03 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to work with Product: Taste and Adjust</title>
      <link>https://blog.nilenso.com/blog/2025/11/26/how-to-work-with-product-taste-and-adjust/</link>
      <description>Srihari Sriraman
        
      
      
    
    
      
      
         ...</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://blog.nilenso.com/blog/2025/11/26/how-to-work-with-product-taste-and-adjust/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 23:03:26 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decimal is sometimes wrong</title>
      <link>https://jt-hill.com/dropping-decimal/</link>
      <description>Credkit is dropping its usage of the Python Decimal class. I thought it was the solution to all my problems, but it was not.</description>
      <author> (JT Hill)</author>
      <category>python</category>
      <category>rust</category>
      <guid>https://jt-hill.com/dropping-decimal/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 23:03:21 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A first look at Django's new background tasks</title>
      <link>https://roam.be/notes/2025/a-first-look-at-djangos-new-background-tasks/</link>
      <description>Django 6.0 introduces a built-in background tasks framework in `django.tasks`. But don't expect to phase out Celery, Huey or other preferred solutions just yet.</description>
      <category>python</category>
      <category>sql</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <guid>https://roam.be/notes/2025/a-first-look-at-djangos-new-background-tasks/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 23:03:18 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dealgorithmed – Manu</title>
      <link>https://manuelmoreale.com/thoughts/dealgorithmed</link>
      <description>TL;DR: I hate having spare time, and I decided to launch another newsletter called Dealgorithmed. Will start on January 1st, delivered every 1st and …</description>
      <category>android</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>apple</category>
      <category>conference</category>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <guid>https://manuelmoreale.com/thoughts/dealgorithmed</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 23:03:13 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I want to give a lot of fucks! - Prashant Anand</title>
      <link>https://anandprashant.com/posts/i-want-to-give-a-lot-of-fucks</link>
      <description>Stop caring. Stop giving a fuck.</description>
      <guid>https://anandprashant.com/posts/i-want-to-give-a-lot-of-fucks</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 23:03:07 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agentic Coding Is Anything But · Mat</title>
      <link>https://matcohle.me/agentic-coding-is-anything-but/</link>
      <description>For the joy of making</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://matcohle.me/agentic-coding-is-anything-but/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 23:03:03 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Seriousness</title>
      <link>https://www.punkrockbio.com/p/on-seriousness</link>
      <description>We need to be serious in our culture to achieve the future of our dreams.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <guid>https://www.punkrockbio.com/p/on-seriousness</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 23:03:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Talk "From Bias to Bots"</title>
      <link>https://www.munich-datageeks.de/talk-from-bias-to-bots/</link>
      <description>Karim built a bot testing housing applications in Munich. Western names got 4x more responses. Nationwide tests confirmed systemic bias. A decade later, he warns modern AI has made algorithmic discrimination far more sophisticated and opaque.</description>
      <category>encryption</category>
      <category>rust</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>apple</category>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <guid>https://www.munich-datageeks.de/talk-from-bias-to-bots/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 23:02:55 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Psychology of Bad Code - SheHacksPurple</title>
      <link>https://shehackspurple.ca/2025/11/27/the-psychology-of-bad-code/</link>
      <description>In this blog series I will explore several known bad developer behaviors that lead to insecure software, as well as how we can combat them by applying behavioral economic interventions. This series is an expansion upon my thoughts from my conference talk ‘Threat Modeling Developer Behavior: The Psychology of Bad Code’.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://shehackspurple.ca/2025/11/27/the-psychology-of-bad-code/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 23:02:51 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Unexpected Effectiveness of One-Shot Decompilation with Claude</title>
      <link>https://blog.chrislewis.au/the-unexpected-effectiveness-of-one-shot-decompilation-with-claude/</link>
      <description>A deep dive into how a 'one-shot' Claude headless loop (paired with scoring, defensive tooling, and a simple bash driver) massively accelerates matching decompilation of Snowboard Kids 2 on the Nintendo 64.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <category>vscode</category>
      <guid>https://blog.chrislewis.au/the-unexpected-effectiveness-of-one-shot-decompilation-with-claude/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 23:02:47 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tips for effective prototyping with Rails 8 and Claude Code</title>
      <link>https://www.wyeworks.com/blog/2025/11/26/tips-for-effective-prototyping-rails-claude-code/</link>
      <description>As developers, we’re living in a time where building applications from scratch is easier than ever, thanks to AI tools like Claude Code. Our…</description>
      <category>ruby</category>
      <category>sql</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <guid>https://www.wyeworks.com/blog/2025/11/26/tips-for-effective-prototyping-rails-claude-code/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 23:02:43 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The One = Digital planetary system we simply all agree on</title>
      <link>https://blog.hermesloom.org/p/the-one-digital-planetary-system</link>
      <description>Fragmentation of digital systems disrupts workflows and harms overall productivity.</description>
      <guid>https://blog.hermesloom.org/p/the-one-digital-planetary-system</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 23:02:39 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Be useful in emergencies</title>
      <link>https://kg.dev/thoughts/emergencies</link>
      <description>Before the years of compounding technical experience, before accumulating an intricate understanding of corporate bureaucracy, before I started my own company — I was an intern. An intern who thought he knew more than any other intern on the planet. I miss the confidence I had before I learned more about the world. I really thought that I could do no wrong.As with most forms of arrogance, it didn’t take long to catch up to me. This time, in the form of a P0, company-wide alarm. When you’re 19, few things prepare you for a situation like this. The closest I had come to dealing with an emergency was a mandatory CPR class I took while working the front desk at a YMCA as a teenager. This, though, was different.The team that I worked on was in charge of datacenter failovers. This is the process of migrating traffic from one datacenter to another in case of an emergency. One day, there was some sort of cooling issue in one of our datacenters on the East Coast. Servers were getting overheated and we had to act fast to redirect traffic to the West Coast. It was my team’s time to shine.Code that is only executed during emergencies tends to collect cobwebs. In these cobwebs, there lived a bug. A bug that I had put there. The same one that rendered this emergency lever of ours completely useless. The only way around it was to do the failover by hand — a long, painful process involving dozens of people across the company.The embarrassment I felt when it was discovered that I had caused the issue was… something else. Thankfully, I had a great manager who made sure the attention was kept off of me until he had a chance to talk to me privately after this whole thing was resolved.At the end of the day, when all affected customers were migrated to the healthy datacenter and everyone was happy, my manager told me something I have never forgotten. The best piece of advice I’ve been given in my career:Things like this will happen again in your career. Things break all the time. Sometimes, it will be your doing and other times someone else’s. Regardless, you need to learn how to deal with situations like these. Learn to be useful during emergencies.Since then, I’ve tried to put myself in positions where I’d play a role in resolving major issues. Some caused by me; most (thankfully) not. Emergencies are scary and most people will try to weasel their way out of playing a major role in them, so this opens up space for those of us willing to take on the challenge. Take full advantage.The way that you deal with an emergency is a whole separate, complex topic. You should read Sources of Power by Gary Klein if you’re interested in learning about how professionals make decisions in high-stakes situations. For now, I’ll leave you with this one tip: Present as the calmest person in the room. Slow down your heart rate. Write things down so you don’t forget about all the moving pieces as they come in. Keep track of who is supposed to be doing what. Speak more slowly. Breathe.</description>
      <guid>https://kg.dev/thoughts/emergencies</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 23:02:35 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Securing File Imports: Fixing SSRF and XXE Vulnerabilities</title>
      <link>https://hugo.writizzy.com/p/securing-file-imports-fixing-ssrf-and-xxe-vulnerabilities</link>
      <description>How to fix SSRF and XXE vulnerabilities in file imports? Real-world case with exploitation, code examples, and security solutions in Kotlin.</description>
      <category>apple</category>
      <category>web</category>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <guid>https://hugo.writizzy.com/p/securing-file-imports-fixing-ssrf-and-xxe-vulnerabilities</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 23:02:31 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interfaces should make understanding opt-out, not opt-in</title>
      <link>https://www.amantulsyan.com/interfaces-should-make-understanding-opt-out-not-opt-in/</link>
      <description>Current AI tools make understanding optional, creating passive builders who plateau at mediocrity. A case for interfaces that keep comprehension at the center while letting us choose when to abstract it away.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>nodejs</category>
      <category>python</category>
      <guid>https://www.amantulsyan.com/interfaces-should-make-understanding-opt-out-not-opt-in/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 23:02:22 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bringing Sexy Back</title>
      <link>https://lux-magazine.com/article/privacy-eroticism/</link>
      <description>Internet surveillance has killed eroticism. We need privacy to reclaim it.</description>
      <category>apple</category>
      <guid>https://lux-magazine.com/article/privacy-eroticism/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 23:02:19 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Twelve Thought Experiments on the Computational Theory of Consciousness – Joe Antognini</title>
      <link>https://joe-antognini.github.io/ml/thought-experiments-on-consciousness</link>
      <description>A few years ago I outlined the so-called “triviality argument” thatconsciousness cannot be reduced to the process of ...</description>
      <guid>https://joe-antognini.github.io/ml/thought-experiments-on-consciousness</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 23:02:13 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bridge Clearance</title>
      <link>https://xkcd.com/3174/</link>
      <description></description>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <guid>https://xkcd.com/3174/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 22:02:04 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>