<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-16"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://linksfor.dev/feed.xml" />
    <title>linksfor.dev(s)</title>
    <link>https://linksfor.dev/feed.xml</link>
    <description>Curated links for devs</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Sonnet 4.6</title>
      <link>https://www.anthropic.com/news/claude-sonnet-4-6</link>
      <description>Claude Sonnet 4.6 is a full upgrade of the model’s skills across coding, computer use, long-reasoning, agent planning, knowledge work, and design. </description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>apple</category>
      <category>vscode</category>
      <guid>https://www.anthropic.com/news/claude-sonnet-4-6</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 20:02:32 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GrapheneOS - break free from Google and Apple [ENG 🇬🇧]</title>
      <link>https://blog.tomaszdunia.pl/grapheneos-eng/</link>
      <description>🇬🇧-&gt;🇵🇱 Przejdź do polskiej wersji tego wpisu / Go to polish version of this post</description>
      <category>android</category>
      <category>cloud</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <category>apple</category>
      <guid>https://blog.tomaszdunia.pl/grapheneos-eng/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 13:02:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rise of the Triforce</title>
      <link>https://dolphin-emu.org/blog/2026/02/16/rise-of-the-triforce/</link>
      <description>During the rapid technological advancements of the early 1990s, the video game industry was on the cusp of a massive addition - another dimension. With console shenanigans like the Super FX chip giving players a taste of 3D, hype was at an all-time high. But the games released for home consoles were nothing compared to what arcade developers were capable of doing. By employing gigantic budgets and cutting-edge hardware, the arcade gave players a chance to see the future, today.
But the future eventually arrived with the launch of the 5th generation of consoles. All of a sudden, the revolutionary 3D hardware features that were once exclusive to arcades were now available in home consoles. Without next-generation hype pushing players into the arcade, powerful but expensive arcade machines were no longer sustainable to develop. The industry adjusted by moving toward more cost effective solutions, with many turning to the inexpensive, already proven 3D-capable hardware available in 5th gen home consoles.
Rather than turning around the decline of the arcade, the cheaper hardware may have helped accelerate it. There were fewer unique experiences to pull players into the arcade, and previous hit exclusives were now seeing high quality home console ports that allowed them to be enjoyed without munching quarters. When the 6th generation arrived with the Dreamcast and the PlayStation 2, many arcade stalwarts waved the white flag and started to shift their arcade divisions to home console projects, with mixed success.
Sega was among those hit hardest by this era. They produced some of the greatest arcade thrills of the 1990s and enjoyed massive success in the home console market with the Sega Genesis/Mega Drive. But a string of mistakes and miscalculations combined with the slumping arcade industry sent them to the brink of bankruptcy. By 2002, the Dreamcast had been soundly defeated by the launch of the PlayStation 2, and Sega began porting some of their hits to their former rivals' hardware just to stay afloat.
The home market was lost, but the languishing arcade scene presented Sega with an opportunity. They still had legendary arcade development teams, and if Sega could leverage them to produce a wave of arcade hits, they would be in a position to dominate a new era of arcades when most others were changing gears. There was just one problem: Sega didn't have the resources that they once did. If they were going to do this, they needed some help.
And so they did something that would have been considered unthinkable just five years prior. Sega teamed up with Nintendo to develop a GameCube-based arcade platform. Bolstering their ranks was Namco, another coin-op stalwart with tons of arcade veterans.
Three companies, one mission: Triforce.</description>
      <category>encryption</category>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://dolphin-emu.org/blog/2026/02/16/rise-of-the-triforce/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 09:02:06 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LLM-generated skills work, if you generate them afterwards</title>
      <link>https://www.seangoedecke.com/generate-skills-afterwards/</link>
      <description>LLM “skills” are a short explanatory prompt for a particular task, typically bundled with helper scripts. A recent paper showed that while skills are useful to LLMs, LLM-authored skills are not. From the abstract:</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://www.seangoedecke.com/generate-skills-afterwards/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 03:02:17 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SkillsBench: Benchmarking How Well Agent Skills Work Across Diverse Tasks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.12670</link>
      <description>Agent Skills are structured packages of procedural knowledge that augment LLM agents at inference time. Despite rapid adoption, there is no standard way to measure whether they actually help. We present SkillsBench, a benchmark of 86 tasks across 11 domains paired with curated Skills and deterministic verifiers. Each task is evaluated under three conditions: no Skills, curated Skills, and self-generated Skills. We test 7 agent-model configurations over 7,308 trajectories. Curated Skills raise average pass rate by 16.2 percentage points(pp), but effects vary widely by domain (+4.5pp for Software Engineering to +51.9pp for Healthcare) and 16 of 84 tasks show negative deltas. Self-generated Skills provide no benefit on average, showing that models cannot reliably author the procedural knowledge they benefit from consuming. Focused Skills with 2--3 modules outperform comprehensive documentation, and smaller models with Skills can match larger models without them.</description>
      <category>web</category>
      <guid>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.12670</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 02:01:58 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A/B Testing Your RAG Pipeline: Chunking, Retrieval, and Reranking Strategies You Can Build With One Prompt Each | Rasha Hantash</title>
      <link>https://www.rasha.me/blog/rag-pipeline-claude-code-agent-teams</link>
      <description>How to quickly build and compare RAG pipeline variants — cosine vs. hybrid search, fixed vs. semantic chunking, Cohere vs. cross-encoder reranking — using Claude Code, Graphite stacks, and your own offline evals.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>vscode</category>
      <category>sql</category>
      <category>containers</category>
      <category>conference</category>
      <guid>https://www.rasha.me/blog/rag-pipeline-claude-code-agent-teams</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:04:24 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Break Stasis</title>
      <link>https://oldmanrahul.com/2026/02/15/break-stasis/</link>
      <description>Personal Musings and Transcripts</description>
      <category>sql</category>
      <guid>https://oldmanrahul.com/2026/02/15/break-stasis/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:04:22 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plan it, Work it, Review it, Reflect it</title>
      <link>https://ai.unicrons.cloud/en/2026/02/15/plan-it-work-it-review-it-reflect-it/</link>
      <description>Our workflow for working with AI agents: create, plan, implement, review and reflect.</description>
      <category>git</category>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>sql</category>
      <guid>https://ai.unicrons.cloud/en/2026/02/15/plan-it-work-it-review-it-reflect-it/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:04:19 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rob Panico - You Never See the Whole Shape at Once</title>
      <link>https://www.robpanico.com/articles/display/?entry_short=you-never-see-the-whole-shape-at-once</link>
      <description>A tesseract can never be seen all at once—only through partial, time-bound projections—and that limitation turns out to be the point. What looks contradictory from a single frame often reveals coherence when allowed to rotate over time. This essay uses the geometry of higher dimensions to explore why certainty fractures complex things, and why humility toward incomplete views is not weakness but structural necessity.</description>
      <guid>https://www.robpanico.com/articles/display/?entry_short=you-never-see-the-whole-shape-at-once</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:04:15 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experiments with CodeMirror - Blog - aziis98</title>
      <link>https://aziis98.com/blog/codemirror-review-tool/</link>
      <description>This is a tutorial on writing a simple code review interface with CodeMirror 6 and the unified merge extension.</description>
      <category>vscode</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>web</category>
      <guid>https://aziis98.com/blog/codemirror-review-tool/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:04:11 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluate Your Own RAG: Why Best Practices Failed Us - Charles AZAM</title>
      <link>https://charlesazam.com/blog/rag/</link>
      <description>We benchmarked our production RAG system across embedding models, chunk sizes, chunking strategies, and retrieval modes. The results contradicted common wisdom.</description>
      <category>cloud</category>
      <category>sql</category>
      <category>vscode</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>containers</category>
      <guid>https://charlesazam.com/blog/rag/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:04:07 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Dyslexia, Programming and Lisp. — Relections on Software Engineering</title>
      <link>https://www.iwillig.me/blog/on-dyslexia-and-lisp/</link>
      <description>Dyslexia is a difference in the way the brain processes language. It is often defined as the difference between intelligence (vaguely defined via the fake IQ test) and a person's ability to read. That is, a dyslexic with normal intelligence will underperform compared to their peers in learning how to read. There are many different theories on what the cause is, but most people believe that there are fundamental differences between the brains of people who have dyslexia and those that do not. In Maryanne Wolf's book, Dyslexia, Fluency, and the Brain, several essays point to a physical difference in the density of specialized brain cells that the brain uses to process letter shapes. It has become clear recently from fMRIs that dyslexics actually develop unique neural pathways for reading that are located in the right side of the brain compared to the normal left-side-dominated reading pathways. However, a root cause has not been identified, and the jury is still out. Dyslexia varies considerably, with up to 15% of the population experiencing some form of it.</description>
      <category>ruby</category>
      <category>python</category>
      <guid>https://www.iwillig.me/blog/on-dyslexia-and-lisp/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:04:03 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Type-based alias analysis in the Toy Optimizer</title>
      <link>https://bernsteinbear.com/blog/toy-tbaa/</link>
      <description>Another entry in the Toy Optimizer series.</description>
      <category>python</category>
      <category>ruby</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <category>nodejs</category>
      <guid>https://bernsteinbear.com/blog/toy-tbaa/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:04:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inside Claude Cowork: How Anthropic Runs Claude Code in a Local VM on Your Mac</title>
      <link>https://pvieito.com/2026/01/inside-claude-cowork</link>
      <description></description>
      <category>nodejs</category>
      <category>containers</category>
      <category>cloud</category>
      <category>python</category>
      <category>linux</category>
      <guid>https://pvieito.com/2026/01/inside-claude-cowork</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:03:56 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Things I Check Before Opening a PR</title>
      <link>https://www.jakeworth.com/posts/things-i-check-before-opening-a-pr/</link>
      <description>What is a programmer but a series of PRs (pull requests)? I optimize PRs to introduce the best code I can, be easy to review, and document my work so I can make sense of it in the future. Here are some things I always check before opening a PR.</description>
      <category>typescript</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <category>ruby</category>
      <category>nodejs</category>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <guid>https://www.jakeworth.com/posts/things-i-check-before-opening-a-pr/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:03:53 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dario Amodei — The Adolescence of Technology</title>
      <link>https://darioamodei.com/essay/the-adolescence-of-technology</link>
      <description>Confronting and Overcoming the Risks of Powerful AI</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <guid>https://darioamodei.com/essay/the-adolescence-of-technology</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:03:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trying New Things</title>
      <link>https://daoudclarke.net/2026/02/16/trying-new-things</link>
      <description>16 February 2026</description>
      <guid>https://daoudclarke.net/2026/02/16/trying-new-things</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:03:46 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Menelaos Vergis</title>
      <link>https://menelaos.vergis.net/posts/Why-I-Finally-Stopped-Designing-My-CV-and-Started-Coding-It</link>
      <description>Things I work on</description>
      <category>nodejs</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <category>web</category>
      <guid>https://menelaos.vergis.net/posts/Why-I-Finally-Stopped-Designing-My-CV-and-Started-Coding-It</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:03:43 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Personal Software | Matt Spear</title>
      <link>https://mattspear.co/blog/personal-software</link>
      <description>I built a habit tracker, a tab manager, a task board, and an AI assistant. None are products. They're personal software – and soon everyone will have their own.</description>
      <category>apple</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <category>sql</category>
      <guid>https://mattspear.co/blog/personal-software</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:03:39 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deploying Your Own IndieWeb Site with Indiekit + Eleventy (Docker Compose based)</title>
      <link>https://rmendes.net/content/articles/2026-02-14-deploying-your-own-indieweb-site/</link>
      <description>Deploying Your Own IndieWeb Site with Indiekit + Eleventy (Docker Compose based) 14 February 2026 indiekit indieweb deploy eleventy A complete guide to deploying [Indiekit](https://getindiekit.com) on...</description>
      <category>containers</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <category>apple</category>
      <category>youtube</category>
      <category>linux</category>
      <guid>https://rmendes.net/content/articles/2026-02-14-deploying-your-own-indieweb-site/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:03:36 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Long Tail of LLM-Assisted Decompilation</title>
      <link>https://blog.chrislewis.au/the-long-tail-of-llm-assisted-decompilation/</link>
      <description>After rapid advances thanks to one-shot decompilation, progress on the Snowboard Kids 2 decompilation began to falter. This post explores the workflow evolution, tooling improvements, and fundamental LLM limits that emerged when tackling the long tail of increasingly difficult functions.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <guid>https://blog.chrislewis.au/the-long-tail-of-llm-assisted-decompilation/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:03:31 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Move Faster Manifesto</title>
      <link>https://brianguthrie.com/p/the-move-faster-manifesto/</link>
      <description>Lessons for shipping software quickly by skipping the grind</description>
      <guid>https://brianguthrie.com/p/the-move-faster-manifesto/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:03:28 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Brent Benson - A custom app creation renaissance</title>
      <link>https://brentwbenson.org/posts/custom-app-enablement/</link>
      <description>There is a change in the calculus of what is achievable with a sketch and a 10 minute conversation</description>
      <category>apple</category>
      <category>python</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <guid>https://brentwbenson.org/posts/custom-app-enablement/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:03:25 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You're Probably Pronouncing "Ubuntu" Wrong</title>
      <link>https://www.rly0nheart.com/posts/youre-probably-pronouncing-ubuntu-wrong/</link>
      <description>Ritchie Mwewa</description>
      <category>linux</category>
      <guid>https://www.rly0nheart.com/posts/youre-probably-pronouncing-ubuntu-wrong/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:03:21 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Love Letter to Self-Hosting</title>
      <link>https://lukaswerner.com/post/2026-02-13@self-hosting-letter</link>
      <description>I’ve tried to put to paper why I love self-hosting; yet I’ve never been fully able to accurately describe what I love about it. Perhaps it is the digital sovereignty, or the rejection of living on the internet and renting my space, or perhaps it is a way of feeling closer to the software I use. Either way it is something that matters a great deal to me.</description>
      <category>containers</category>
      <category>youtube</category>
      <guid>https://lukaswerner.com/post/2026-02-13@self-hosting-letter</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:03:18 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>R.I.P. Rest In Prompt – Hugo Daniel</title>
      <link>https://hugodaniel.com/posts/rip-rest-in-prompt/</link>
      <description>Architecture designed for machine collaboration</description>
      <author> (Hugo Daniel)</author>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <category>nodejs</category>
      <category>web</category>
      <category>vscode</category>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <guid>https://hugodaniel.com/posts/rip-rest-in-prompt/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:03:15 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The speed of building has outpaced the thinking: why we need a new moral standard for AI development</title>
      <link>https://www.eliostruyf.com/killing-indie-development-with-ai/</link>
      <description>Explore the impact of AI on indie development and the need for a moral compass in coding. Are we sacrificing quality for speed?</description>
      <author> (https://www.eliostruyf.com/about)</author>
      <category>visualstudio</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>encryption</category>
      <guid>https://www.eliostruyf.com/killing-indie-development-with-ai/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:03:07 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Harnessing Postgres race conditions</title>
      <link>https://www.lirbank.com/harnessing-postgres-race-conditions</link>
      <description>Synchronization barriers let you test for race conditions with confidence.</description>
      <author> (Mikael Lirbank)</author>
      <category>sql</category>
      <guid>https://www.lirbank.com/harnessing-postgres-race-conditions</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:03:03 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>xavxav - Software Archeology in 2026</title>
      <link>https://xav.io/blog/software-archeology/</link>
      <description>February 16, 2026</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://xav.io/blog/software-archeology/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:03:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mark Nguyen</title>
      <link>https://mark-n.co/blog/living-a-life-less-lonely/</link>
      <description>Mark Nguyen. Full stack software developer and designer</description>
      <guid>https://mark-n.co/blog/living-a-life-less-lonely/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:02:56 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do LLMs hallucinate more in Czech than in English? – Miloš Švaňa</title>
      <link>https://svana.name/2026/02/do-llms-hallucinate-more-in-czech-than-in-english/</link>
      <description>Having explored hallucination benchmarks for LLMs, I’ve decided to use the TruthfulQA dataset to see if LLMs hallucinate more when I talk to them in Czech instead of English.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://svana.name/2026/02/do-llms-hallucinate-more-in-czech-than-in-english/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:02:53 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I built a coding agent two months before ChatGPT existed</title>
      <link>https://solmaz.io/log/2026/02/13/coding-agent-before-chatgpt/</link>
      <description>I built a coding agent back in 2022, 2 months before ChatGPT launched:</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>nodejs</category>
      <category>python</category>
      <guid>https://solmaz.io/log/2026/02/13/coding-agent-before-chatgpt/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:02:46 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why do I feel bad following recommendation algorithms?</title>
      <link>https://edwardbx.com/articles/recommendation-algorithms/</link>
      <description>How can I still find interesting things without them?</description>
      <category>youtube</category>
      <guid>https://edwardbx.com/articles/recommendation-algorithms/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:02:43 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Peer-reviewers in the coal mine? About AI &amp; employment</title>
      <link>https://www.ericburel.tech/blog/ai-impact-employment-and-peer-review</link>
      <description>Maybe Section 174 killed Brynjolfsson canaries. Maybe it's indeed AI. This article is about how you should treat working papers as working papers and give more love to the process of peer-reviewing.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://www.ericburel.tech/blog/ai-impact-employment-and-peer-review</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:02:40 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Words are a Leaky Abstraction</title>
      <link>https://brianschrader.com/archive/words-are-a-leaky-abstraction/</link>
      <description>Something about hearing the phrase "Claude's Soul Document" got me thinking again about a problem I've long pondered. Software folks, like myself, have a long and proud history of taking words that exist and coopting them, manipulating the meaning of those words into feeble shadows of their former selfs. Tech people and tech companies do this on accident and on purpose, both because it can be useful to reduce a human concept to something simpler to quantify and because its easier to market and sell. Machine Learning, an academic term, becomes Artificial Intelligence and the word "Intelligence" is defined down in order to be achievable.</description>
      <category>encryption</category>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://brianschrader.com/archive/words-are-a-leaky-abstraction/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:02:36 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Get a portable monitor, they’re great</title>
      <link>https://davidgerard.co.uk/blockchain/2025/02/11/get-a-portable-monitor-theyre-great/</link>
      <description>An exciting new form of gadget — portable monitors! Light, 10” to 21”, USB-C power, signal via USB-C or mini-HDMI. And portable.</description>
      <guid>https://davidgerard.co.uk/blockchain/2025/02/11/get-a-portable-monitor-theyre-great/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:02:33 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Use Protocols, Not Services</title>
      <link>https://notnotp.com/notes/use-protocols-not-services/</link>
      <description>The Internet is almost anonymous and privacy-preserving by design. I mean, unless some administrator actively tries to track you, there is no built-in...</description>
      <guid>https://notnotp.com/notes/use-protocols-not-services/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 00:02:05 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Khronos Announces glTF Gaussian Splatting Extension</title>
      <link>https://www.khronos.org/news/press/gltf-gaussian-splatting-press-release</link>
      <description>Today, The Khronos Group, announces a release candidate for the…</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://www.khronos.org/news/press/gltf-gaussian-splatting-press-release</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 23:02:17 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI is destroying Open Source, and it's not even good yet</title>
      <link>https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2026/ai-is-destroying-open-source/</link>
      <description>Over the weekend Ars Technica retracted an article because the AI a writer used hallucinated quotes from an open source library maintainer.
The irony here is the maintainer in question, Scott Shambaugh, was harassed by someone's AI agent over not merging it's AI slop code.
It's likely the bot was running through someone's local 'agentic AI' instance (likely using OpenClaw). The guy who built OpenClaw was just hired by OpenAI to "work on bringing agents to everyone." You'll have to forgive me if I'm not enthusastic about that.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>youtube</category>
      <guid>https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2026/ai-is-destroying-open-source/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 22:02:11 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SNEWS</title>
      <link>https://xkcd.com/3208/</link>
      <description></description>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <guid>https://xkcd.com/3208/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 22:02:05 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>