<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-16"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://linksfor.dev/feed.xml" />
    <title>linksfor.dev(s)</title>
    <link>https://linksfor.dev/feed.xml</link>
    <description>Curated links for devs</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>Was Daft Punk Having a Laugh When They Chose the Tempo of Harder, Better, Faster, Stronger?</title>
      <link>https://www.madebywindmill.com/tempi/blog/hbfs-bpm/</link>
      <description>Was Daft Punk Having a Laugh When They Chose the Tempo of Harder, Better, Faster, Stronger?</description>
      <category>youtube</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>sql</category>
      <guid>https://www.madebywindmill.com/tempi/blog/hbfs-bpm/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 03:02:05 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2026 will be my year of the Linux desktop</title>
      <link>https://xeiaso.net/notes/2026/year-linux-desktop/</link>
      <description>The meme will no longer be a dream.</description>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <category>linux</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <guid>https://xeiaso.net/notes/2026/year-linux-desktop/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 03:02:02 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conic Sections</title>
      <link>https://xkcd.com/3189/</link>
      <description></description>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <guid>https://xkcd.com/3189/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 02:02:17 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Clicks Communicator: the ultimate communciation companion</title>
      <link>https://www.clicksphone.com/en/communicator</link>
      <description>Clicks Communicator is phone purpose-built for taking action and communicating in a noisy world with deeper context, versatile input and greater control in a compact design.</description>
      <category>apple</category>
      <category>android</category>
      <guid>https://www.clicksphone.com/en/communicator</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 02:02:13 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Two-Week Experiment – Blue Lemon bits</title>
      <link>https://bluelemonbits.com/2026/01/02/from-macos-to-debian-a-two-week-experiment/</link>
      <description>After many years as a Mac user, the last couple of years I’ve become increasingly frustrated with the macOS software direction and the continuous erosion of the historically vibrant indie developer ecosystem.</description>
      <category>apple</category>
      <category>encryption</category>
      <category>cloud</category>
      <category>linux</category>
      <guid>https://bluelemonbits.com/2026/01/02/from-macos-to-debian-a-two-week-experiment/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 01:03:56 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Giving Your Agent Eyes is not Enough</title>
      <link>https://qckfx.com/blog/giving-your-agent-eyes-is-not-enough</link>
      <description>AI coding agents can build UI. But they can't verify it. Verification requires comparison—your agent doesn't remember anything.</description>
      <author> (Chris Wood)</author>
      <category>apple</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://qckfx.com/blog/giving-your-agent-eyes-is-not-enough</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 01:03:53 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigating and fixing a nasty clone bug</title>
      <link>https://kobzol.github.io/rust/2025/12/30/investigating-and-fixing-a-nasty-clone-bug.html</link>
      <description>Recently I found myself battling with another nasty bug. It took me several hours to understand what is happening, and once I found it, it turned out that the cause of the bug is relevant to the Ergonomic cloning initiative that is currently being discussed a lot. So I thought that it would be a good candidate for a blog post.</description>
      <category>rust</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <guid>https://kobzol.github.io/rust/2025/12/30/investigating-and-fixing-a-nasty-clone-bug.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 01:03:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Year of reading</title>
      <link>https://kg.dev/thoughts/year-of-reading</link>
      <description>2025 was the Year of Discomfort for me. I found myself getting too comfortable with various facets of life. I wasn’t pursuing or sticking with things that made me uncomfortable. I think, and have been told, this comes with age. It’s the same sort of discomfort you feel when you try to take a cold shower on the advice of The Whole Internet. It seems unnecessary. But being uncomfortable is actually good for you. When you venture deeper into the fractals of life, you’re going to feel some discomfort. It’s important to stray from the center.Looking back at the post I made exactly a year ago, I’m proud of the things I stuck with. It wasn’t everything that’s on the list, but a good amount. I even added a few that felt outside my personality. Before I talk about the theme for 2026, I want to share how 2025 went.Split KeyboardsI began the year by learning how to use a split keyboard. Mostly for ergonomics, but also because of the cool factor. This was one I intentionally didn’t stick with. I managed to get pretty quick at typing with a split keyboard, but I realized that the context switching between my laptop keyboard and my split keyboard slowed me down more than I’d like, so I stopped.VimI also learned Vim — one of the best decisions I’ve ever made. Learning Vim is incredibly uncomfortable. But after two to three months of consistency, I couldn’t imagine navigating around text on a computer in any other way. It’s a bit unsettling to think that every time I wanted to move my cursor around my code, I used to pick up my right hand and either move it down to the arrow keys or worse, reach for my mouse. If you’re a programmer, please go learn Vim.Typing AccuracyContinuing with the keyboard theme, I dramatically increased my typing speed and accuracy, yet another thing that was quite uncomfortable. I wasn’t a slow typer, but I wasn’t that fast either. Since the beginning of 2025, I’ve done several typing tests every week. Mostly, the focus has been accuracy, but I will switch gears and focus on speed every once in a while.I can consistently type entire paragraphs at around 110 words per minute with 100% accuracy. A year ago, I couldn’t even reach 100 words per minute, let alone exceed it with 100% accuracy. This progress took around 7,000 typing tests to achieve.--The above three were part of a sub-theme I was pursuing where I wanted to master my tools. I spend most of my day on a computer (perhaps you can relate). The keyboard that sits between my monitor and me is my primary tool. It’s my samurai sword. My chef’s knife. So, it made sense to put in a significant amount of time to master it.KickboxingI’ll start by saying that I failed at sticking with Jiu Jitsu. I took four classes and a bump to the back of the head was enough for me to call it quits. Maybe I’ll pick it back up one day, but I’m terrified of concussions so that will need to wait.Now, as for kickboxing, I think I’m in love. I took my first class in the first week of January and haven’t stopped since. Working your way up the belt ladder is an endless journey, but the path is a joyful one. I’m mostly focused on improving my skills and cardio. The belt will come to me when it’s ready.GymThis was the most consistent year I’ve had in the gym. Despite all the travel and a few bouts with a cold or the flu, I went at least twice a week, every week. I did a proper cut for once — where I went from 195lb to 165lb and achieved the best shape of my life. I’ve hit my protein intake goal pretty much every day of the year.This, I should note, is uncomfortable. I often didn’t want to do it, but that was the whole point of the theme for this year. I didn’t want to, but I did it anyway.AlcoholOn the last day of February, I had a really fun night out with friends. What followed was 3 really not-fun days. Working on a startup is hard enough, but it’s nearly impossible when you can’t even think because of a hangover. I decided to stop for two weeks. Those two weeks turned into a month. Then I talked to my friend who was doing a sobriety challenge for the whole year and decided to join him.Ten months later, and I haven’t been tempted to drink even once. At the one year mark, I will reintroduce alcohol in my life, but it will likely be one or two drinks a month.That was all 2025. For 2026, the theme will be Year of Reading. I’m surprised that I haven’t had this one as a theme before, so I’m excited to dedicate a whole year to reading anything and everything I can. Books, New Yorker articles, poems, essays — all of it.If you’re interested in seeing what I’m reading, follow/befriend me on Goodreads!2026 - Year of reading2025 - Year of discomfort2024 - Year of dedicated focus2023 - Year of leap of faith2022 - Year of travel</description>
      <guid>https://kg.dev/thoughts/year-of-reading</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 01:03:46 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why it matters - Jukka Niiranen blog</title>
      <link>https://jukkaniiranen.com/2026/01/why-it-matters/</link>
      <description>We don’t write just to deliver a payload of importance. We write to think. The sudden flood of "why it matters" formula in written content is not a positive sign for this.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://jukkaniiranen.com/2026/01/why-it-matters/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 01:03:42 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The CEO cost function</title>
      <link>https://carette.xyz/posts/automated_ceo/</link>
      <description>Looking for an Algorithmic Executive</description>
      <category>cloud</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>encryption</category>
      <guid>https://carette.xyz/posts/automated_ceo/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 01:03:35 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting Real With LLMs - Gilad Peleg</title>
      <link>https://www.giladpeleg.com/blog/getting-real-with-llms</link>
      <description>It's hard to tell from the internet what can one do with LLMs at their workplace. This blog tries to cover the current options and challenges</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>containers</category>
      <category>python</category>
      <guid>https://www.giladpeleg.com/blog/getting-real-with-llms</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 01:03:30 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Representing Hierarchies</title>
      <link>https://gpfault.net/posts/first-child-next-sibling.html</link>
      <description>published on Jan 01 2026</description>
      <category>nodejs</category>
      <category>web</category>
      <guid>https://gpfault.net/posts/first-child-next-sibling.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 01:03:27 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solving Agent Context Loss: A Beads + Claude Code Workflow for Large Features - JXØ</title>
      <link>https://jx0.ca/solving-agent-context-loss/</link>
      <description>How external task state with beads transformed my AI coding workflow from constant babysitting to autonomous execution of 17-task epics. Includes the complete skill set to replicate this workflow.</description>
      <author> (Jarred Kenny)</author>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <category>nodejs</category>
      <category>sql</category>
      <category>typescript</category>
      <guid>https://jx0.ca/solving-agent-context-loss/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 01:03:23 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rent a Mac M4 Mini and Access It via SSH from Linux</title>
      <link>https://www.vincentschmalbach.com/rent-a-mac-m4-mini-and-access-it-via-ssh-from-linux/</link>
      <description>I needed a Mac to run a Laravel test suite. On my ThinkPad T15g with Docker, the tests took so long I gave up after 2 hours. My client said it takes 5 minutes on their M4 Mac. I decided to rent one…</description>
      <category>apple</category>
      <category>sql</category>
      <category>linux</category>
      <category>containers</category>
      <guid>https://www.vincentschmalbach.com/rent-a-mac-m4-mini-and-access-it-via-ssh-from-linux/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 01:03:20 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I switched away from Zig to C3</title>
      <link>https://lowbytefox.dev/blog/from-zig-to-c3/</link>
      <description>LowByteFox's Personal Website</description>
      <category>rust</category>
      <guid>https://lowbytefox.dev/blog/from-zig-to-c3/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 01:03:15 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Next Thing Will Not Be Big</title>
      <link>https://blog.glyph.im/2026/01/the-next-thing-will-not-be-big.html</link>
      <description>Disruption, too, will be disrupted.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <category>linux</category>
      <category>containers</category>
      <category>apple</category>
      <guid>https://blog.glyph.im/2026/01/the-next-thing-will-not-be-big.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 01:03:11 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vibe coding killed Cursor</title>
      <link>https://ischemist.com/writings/long-form/how-vibe-coding-killed-cursor</link>
      <description>Cursor is dying because cost-optimization forces models into tunnel vision. RAG agents fail because they only see what they search for. The superior workflow for 2026 is massive context windows (gemini 2.5 pro) and manual control. Stop letting agents hide code from the model.</description>
      <author> (Anton Morgunov)</author>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>python</category>
      <guid>https://ischemist.com/writings/long-form/how-vibe-coding-killed-cursor</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 01:03:08 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Common prefix skipping, adaptive sort</title>
      <link>http://smalldatum.blogspot.com/2026/01/common-prefix-skipping-adaptive-sort.html</link>
      <description>The patent expired for US7680791B2 . I invented this while at Oracle and it landed in 10gR2  with claims of ~5X better performance vs the pr...</description>
      <category>sql</category>
      <category>apple</category>
      <category>vscode</category>
      <category>linux</category>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <guid>http://smalldatum.blogspot.com/2026/01/common-prefix-skipping-adaptive-sort.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 01:03:04 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An experiment in vibe coding</title>
      <link>https://nolanlawson.com/2025/12/28/an-experiment-in-vibe-coding/</link>
      <description>For the holidays, I gave myself a little experiment: build a small web app for my wife to manage her travel itineraries. I challenged myself to avoid editing the code myself and just do it “v…</description>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <category>web</category>
      <category>sql</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://nolanlawson.com/2025/12/28/an-experiment-in-vibe-coding/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 01:03:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Try to Take My Position: The Best Promotion Advice I Ever Got</title>
      <link>https://andrew.grahamyooll.com/blog/Try-to-Take-My-Position/</link>
      <description>Published on 2026-01-02 by Andrew Graham-Yooll</description>
      <guid>https://andrew.grahamyooll.com/blog/Try-to-Take-My-Position/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 01:02:56 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Web to Native: Building Apps with SvelteKit &amp; Capacitor</title>
      <link>https://bryanhogan.com/blog/web-to-app-sveltekit-capacitor</link>
      <description>A step-by-step tutorial on integrating CapacitorJS with SvelteKit. Convert your website into an Android/iOS app.</description>
      <category>android</category>
      <category>visualstudio</category>
      <category>apple</category>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <category>nodejs</category>
      <guid>https://bryanhogan.com/blog/web-to-app-sveltekit-capacitor</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 01:02:53 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dimensions: A Terminal Tab Manager</title>
      <link>https://karlvmuller.com/posts/dimensions/</link>
      <description>An interactive terminal tool that keeps tmux tabs organized into focused workspaces.</description>
      <category>rust</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://karlvmuller.com/posts/dimensions/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 01:02:50 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why are weather forecasting sites so bad?</title>
      <link>https://blog.engora.com/2025/12/why-is-weather-forecasting-so-bad.html</link>
      <description>How AI and generative AI is disruptive for consumer weather forecasting services. </description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <guid>https://blog.engora.com/2025/12/why-is-weather-forecasting-so-bad.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 01:02:46 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What I Actually Want To Say in Tech Interviews</title>
      <link>https://nelson.cloud/what-i-actually-want-to-say-in-tech-interviews/</link>
      <description>Honest answers to common interview questions in the tech field.</description>
      <guid>https://nelson.cloud/what-i-actually-want-to-say-in-tech-interviews/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 01:02:43 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Socialist Now Runs New York: What History Predicts</title>
      <link>https://zcashexplained.com/blog/new-york-voted-socialist/</link>
      <description>NYC elected socialist Zohran Mamdani as mayor in 2025. Now sworn in, historical patterns show why societies turn to socialism and what the real solution is.</description>
      <author> (Anonymous)</author>
      <category>encryption</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://zcashexplained.com/blog/new-york-voted-socialist/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 01:02:39 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Developer Is Dead, Long Live the Designer</title>
      <link>https://deadend.dev/posts/the-developer-is-dead-long-live-the-designer/</link>
      <description>With the advent of coding agents and their improvement, developing software as we have been doing it is, at least in many fields, already going the way of the Dodo. But bear with me for a second while I try to explain why I think this is great for developers and I am not actually trying to doom-bait.
It was never about just typing the code This is now cliché, but also the crux of the matter. A year into working on a side project like it’s my job, and having made wide use of AI coding agents, I can say I was surprised by the perspective shift this allowed for me.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <guid>https://deadend.dev/posts/the-developer-is-dead-long-live-the-designer/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 01:02:35 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My setup, and why tmux workflow is better than ever | Raine Virta</title>
      <link>https://raine.dev/blog/my-tmux-setup/</link>
      <description>Keybindings, popup tools, and workflows for a terminal-centric setup</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <guid>https://raine.dev/blog/my-tmux-setup/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 01:02:32 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Was it really a Billion Dollar Mistake?</title>
      <link>https://www.gingerbill.org/article/2026/01/02/was-it-really-a-billion-dollar-mistake/</link>
      <description>TL;DR null pointer dereferences are empirically the easiest class of invalid memory addresses to catch at runtime, and are the least common kind of invalid memory addresses that happen in memory unsafe languages. The trivial solutions to remove the “problem” null pointers have numerous trade-offs which are not obvious, and the cause of why people think it is a “problem” comes from a specific kind of individual-element mindset.
Most people have probably heard of the Billion Dollar Mistake before, which was coined/invented by Tony Hoare: the inventor of null references/pointers.</description>
      <category>rust</category>
      <guid>https://www.gingerbill.org/article/2026/01/02/was-it-really-a-billion-dollar-mistake/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 01:02:28 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MCP works great — until you actually ship.</title>
      <link>https://www.kernl.sh/blog/dont-use-mcp</link>
      <description>Why MCP isn't ready for production agents, and what to do instead.</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>python</category>
      <category>typescript</category>
      <guid>https://www.kernl.sh/blog/dont-use-mcp</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 01:02:24 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>POSSE</title>
      <link>https://indieweb.org/POSSE</link>
      <description>POSSE is an abbreviation for Publish (on your) Own Site, Syndicate Elsewhere, the practice of posting content on your own site first, then publishing copies or sharing links to third parties (like social media silos) with original post links to provide viewers a path to directly interacting with your content.</description>
      <category>conference</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <category>python</category>
      <guid>https://indieweb.org/POSSE</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 00:02:17 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We Should Call Them Macroservices</title>
      <link>https://idiallo.com/blog/whe-should-call-them-macroservices?src=feed</link>
      <description>I love the idea of microservices. When there's a problem on your website, you don't need to fix and redeploy your entire codebase. If the issue only affects your authentication service, you can deploy</description>
      <category>sql</category>
      <guid>https://idiallo.com/blog/whe-should-call-them-macroservices?src=feed</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 23:02:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Let users zoom in on mobile devices</title>
      <link>https://idiallo.com/blog/let-user-zoom-in-on-mobile?src=feed</link>
      <description>This is a bit of a rant. Maybe my eyes are not as good as they used to be. When I read an article that has pictures on them, I like to zoom in to see the details. You might think this makes no sense, </description>
      <category>web</category>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <guid>https://idiallo.com/blog/let-user-zoom-in-on-mobile?src=feed</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 23:02:56 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why my redirect rules from 2013 still work and yours don't</title>
      <link>https://idiallo.com/blog/my-redirect-rules-from-2013-still-work?src=feed</link>
      <description>Here is something that makes me proud of my blog. The redirect rule I wrote for my very first article 12 years ago still works! This blog was an experiment. When I designed it, my intention was to try</description>
      <category>sql</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <category>web</category>
      <guid>https://idiallo.com/blog/my-redirect-rules-from-2013-still-work?src=feed</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 23:02:52 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Natural Path to Gamblification</title>
      <link>https://idiallo.com/blog/a-natural-path-to-gamblification?src=feed</link>
      <description>I had a 383-day streak on Duolingo. Three hundred and eighty-three days of that green owl peeking through my notifications, reminding me that my streak was in danger. I wrote about how I never actuall</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>encryption</category>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <guid>https://idiallo.com/blog/a-natural-path-to-gamblification?src=feed</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 23:02:48 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>All AI Videos Are Harmful</title>
      <link>https://idiallo.com/blog/all-ai-videos-are-harmful?src=feed</link>
      <description>When OpenAI released the first version of Sora, I was excited. For years, I'd had this short story sitting on my hard drive, something I'd written long ago and always dreamed of bringing to life as a </description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>youtube</category>
      <guid>https://idiallo.com/blog/all-ai-videos-are-harmful?src=feed</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 23:02:43 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We have all we need to make mass surveillance a reality</title>
      <link>https://idiallo.com/blog/we-have-all-we-need-for-mass-surveillance?src=feed</link>
      <description>I was watching a movie when I got a random notification from Google Maps on my phone. I never get notifications from this app unless I'm doing turn-by-turn navigation. This one was titled "Timeline," </description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>nodejs</category>
      <guid>https://idiallo.com/blog/we-have-all-we-need-for-mass-surveillance?src=feed</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 23:02:39 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poor Man's Productivity Trick</title>
      <link>https://idiallo.com/blog/poormans-productivity-trick?src=feed</link>
      <description>Have you ever joined a large organization? One with a quarter million employees? Their process is fascinating. You receive hundreds of emails to set up different software. You get a machine mailed to </description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://idiallo.com/blog/poormans-productivity-trick?src=feed</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 23:02:35 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do I Leave the Laptop at the Office?</title>
      <link>https://idiallo.com/blog/do-i-leave-the-laptop-in-the-office?src=feed</link>
      <description>A few years back, I worked at an AI startup as the first hired engineer. All of us could fit in a four-space cubicle, sharing an office with multiple startups. As you can imagine, when you're trying t</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://idiallo.com/blog/do-i-leave-the-laptop-in-the-office?src=feed</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 23:02:31 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paying for the rides I took 8 years ago</title>
      <link>https://idiallo.com/blog/paying-for-my-8-years-old-ride?src=feed</link>
      <description>What does it mean when we say that investors are subsidizing the price of a service? We often hear that ChatGPT is not profitable, despite some users paying $20 a month, or others up to $200 a month. </description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <guid>https://idiallo.com/blog/paying-for-my-8-years-old-ride?src=feed</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 23:02:27 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Blogging Dead?</title>
      <link>https://idiallo.com/blog/what-its-like-blogging-in-2025?src=feed</link>
      <description>When I started 2025, I set myself a simple challenge: write consistently and see if I could reclaim some of the audience this blog once had. In 2024, I had published just 4 posts and had only a handfu</description>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>android</category>
      <guid>https://idiallo.com/blog/what-its-like-blogging-in-2025?src=feed</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 23:02:23 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TIL: Parental controls aren't for parents</title>
      <link>https://beasthacker.com/til/parental-controls-arent-for-parents.html</link>
      <description>I found a stranger texting my 12-year-old on a 'kid-safe' Gabb phone. Parental controls are broken.</description>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <guid>https://beasthacker.com/til/parental-controls-arent-for-parents.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 21:02:20 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>39C3: Power Cycles - media.ccc.de</title>
      <link>https://media.ccc.de/b/congress/2025</link>
      <description>Video Streaming Portal des Chaos Computer Clubs</description>
      <guid>https://media.ccc.de/b/congress/2025</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 19:02:20 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Public Domain Day 2026 in Literature - Blog</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/blog/public-domain-day-2026</link>
      <description>Read about the new ebooks Standard Ebooks is releasing for Public Domain Day 2026!</description>
      <guid>https://standardebooks.org/blog/public-domain-day-2026</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 18:02:08 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 years of personal finances in plain text files</title>
      <link>https://sgoel.dev/posts/10-years-of-personal-finances-in-plain-text-files/</link>
      <description>I've been tracking my finances using Beancount in plain text files for 10 years. Here are the numbers, the workflow, and why I believe plaintext accounting will outlive any app.</description>
      <category>encryption</category>
      <category>git</category>
      <category>python</category>
      <guid>https://sgoel.dev/posts/10-years-of-personal-finances-in-plain-text-files/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 17:02:07 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Home</title>
      <link>https://github.com/j-brooke/FracturedJson/wiki</link>
      <description>JSON formatter that produces highly readable but fairly compact output.  - j-brooke/FracturedJson</description>
      <category>visualstudio</category>
      <category>typescript</category>
      <category>python</category>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <guid>https://github.com/j-brooke/FracturedJson/wiki</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 17:02:04 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Human papillomavirus prevalence in first, second and third cervical cell samples from women HPV-vaccinated as girls, Denmark, 2017 to 2024: data from the Trial23 cohort study</title>
      <link>https://www.eurosurveillance.org/content/10.2807/1560-7917.ES.2025.30.27.2400820</link>
      <description>BACKGROUND
Danish women vaccinated with the 4-valent human papillomavirus (HPV) vaccine (HPV types: 6/11/16/18) at age 14 in 2008 reached screening age in 2017, allowing assessment of long-term effects on prevalence, persistence and incidence of HPV infections.
AIM
To examine the HPV status of cervical samples over time among women vaccinated as girls.
METHODS
Between February 2017 and February 2024, residual material from cytology-analysed samples collected through the ‘Trial23’ study, part of the national screening programme, was tested for HPV16/18 and non-vaccine high-risk (HR) HPV types. Prevalence in first, second and third samples, and persistence and incidence between samples were calculated.
RESULTS
Over 7 years, 8,659 women provided at least one sample, 5,835 at least two and 2,461 at least three. In 7,800 vaccinated women, HPV16/18 prevalence was 0.4% (95% confidence interval (CI): 0.2–0.5), 0.3% (95% CI: 0.1–0.4) and 0.2% (95% CI: 0.0–0.4) in three consecutive samples. Prevalence of non-vaccine HR HPV was 32% (95% CI: 31–33), 28% (95% CI: 27–29) and 31% (95% CI: 29–33). Persistence of HPV16/18 and non-vaccine HPV among vaccinated women was 40% and 53%. In adjusted analyses comparing vaccinated vs unvaccinated women, incidence was significantly lower for HPV16/18 (adjusted relative risk (aRR) &amp;lt; 0.10) while incidence of non-vaccine HR HPV types was higher (aRR: 1.66; 95% CI: 1.12–2.45). No significant difference was observed for persistence.
CONCLUSION
Our study provides real-world evidence of stable protection against HPV16/18 infections in women vaccinated as girls. Less intensive screening seems reasonable until women vaccinated with the 9-valent vaccine reach screening age, when screening should be reconsidered.</description>
      <category>vscode</category>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <guid>https://www.eurosurveillance.org/content/10.2807/1560-7917.ES.2025.30.27.2400820</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 16:02:08 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>